<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Agilebase docs – Security Features</title>
    <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Security Features on Agilebase docs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Users</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/users/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/users/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2 id=&#34;adding-a-user&#34;&gt;Adding a user&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can add a new user from scratch, or clone an existing one. To add:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to the homepage and &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/introduction/development-mode/&#34;&gt;toggle development mode on&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click the &amp;lsquo;+ USER&amp;rsquo; button under Lists at the top of the screen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To clone:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to the homepage and &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/introduction/development-mode/&#34;&gt;toggle development mode on&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click the Users box at the top right to load a list of existing users&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click a user to clone to open up their editing panel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At the bottom, press the Clone button&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a cost is to be applied, this will be shown to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should now see an editing screen with the details of the user you just created.
![Add user][/add-user.png]
&lt;img src=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/new-user-details.png&#34; alt=&#34;User editing&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can enter the user&amp;rsquo;s name and username. If the username isn&amp;rsquo;t their email address, enter their email address in the field provided too. This is useful&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to allow them to reset their own password by receiving a link by email&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to allow them to receive notifications when another user adds a comment against a record&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;as various features allow a user to be assigned to a record. Workflows can be set up to email those users. E.g. if an account manager is assigned to a customer, you may want to email them when a complaint is received from that customer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;passwords&#34;&gt;Passwords&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The recommended way to set passwords is for the user to choose their own, which they can do once they have a username and email address filled in. They will need to visit the login page, click the &amp;lsquo;reset password&amp;rsquo; link and type in their username. They will be emailed a link which will let them set a password.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an administrator, you can also manually reset someone&amp;rsquo;s password by clicking &amp;lsquo;change password&amp;rsquo; in their user details screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We recommend the adoption of a password wallet service like &lt;a href=&#34;https://1password.com/&#34;&gt;1Password&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://lastpass.com&#34;&gt;LastPass&lt;/a&gt; or built-in browser features to generate and store passwords. That lets passwords become much more secure and harder to guess whilst not requiring users to remember them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;notes-about-password-security&#34;&gt;Notes about password security&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Passwords must be a minimum of 8 characters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When someone sets or changes their password, it&amp;rsquo;s checked against &lt;a href=&#34;https://haveibeenpwned.com/Passwords&#34;&gt;https://haveibeenpwned.com/Passwords&lt;/a&gt; to ensure it&amp;rsquo;s not a common one and is suitable for ongoing use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Passwords are stored in our system &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.okta.com/blog/2019/03/what-are-salted-passwords-and-password-hashing/&#34;&gt;salted and hashed&lt;/a&gt; using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bcrypt&#34;&gt;bcrypt&lt;/a&gt; scheme, with 13 rounds. This means that we do not know what your passwords are and in the unfortunate event of our passwords database being hacked, the original passwords would still not be able to be retrieved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;two-factor-authentication&#34;&gt;Two factor authentication&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users are strongly encouraged to set up two factor authentication (2FA) using an app. Unfortunately this is one step an administrator can&amp;rsquo;t do for them, but luckily it is quick and easy to do: &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/users/2fa-setup/&#34;&gt;here&amp;rsquo;s how&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users without 2FA will be prompted to do so in the user interface and by email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2FA is mandatory for &lt;a href=&#34;#roles&#34;&gt;administrators&lt;/a&gt; and necessary for a user to have before &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/privileges/&#34;&gt;develop&lt;/a&gt; privileges can be assigned to them. Users also need to have 2FA enabled in order to perform certain functions such as exporting to spreadsheet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When enabled, a user will be prompted for the 2FA code as well as their password when they log in from a device or location they haven&amp;rsquo;t used in the past 30 days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a user encounters any problems with 2FA, e.g. they lose the device for generating their codes, you can temporarily disable 2FA on their account by going to their user details screen and un-ticking &amp;lsquo;use 2FA&amp;rsquo;. Of course, you need to be aware of the risks, for example double checking that a user who contacts you is really who they say they are. Once they can log in, they&amp;rsquo;ll be able to enable 2FA themselves again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;mandating-2fa-for-everyone&#34;&gt;Mandating 2FA for everyone&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This can be done in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/advanced-usage/company-settings/#mandate-2fa&#34;&gt;company settings&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;other-options&#34;&gt;Other options&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;learner-progression-level&#34;&gt;Learner Progression Level&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When created, the level defaults to being a &amp;lsquo;core user&amp;rsquo;, i.e. a standard user who has no special development privileges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A software architect can change this to move any user up (or down) in learner development progress. Please see &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/introduction/learner-progression/&#34;&gt;learner progression&lt;/a&gt; for more information on what abilities each level confers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;use-the-custom-agilechilli-ui-rather-than-agilebases&#34;&gt;Use the custom AgileChilli UI rather than Agilebase&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s possible for companies to apply their logo and custom login screen to the system. Please contact us if you&amp;rsquo;d like to set this up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;logout-after&#34;&gt;Logout after&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Automatically end the user&amp;rsquo;s session after this many minutes of inactivity. The user themselves can also change this setting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;restrict-data-access&#34;&gt;Restrict data access&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, you can specify a field name, either an equals or a contains filter and a value. The button &lt;em&gt;set to user ID&lt;/em&gt; will set the value to the user&amp;rsquo;s ID.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this is to limit the data rows a particular user sees in a view. If a field with the name you specify appears in a view, a filter will be automatically applied so the user only sees rows which match the filter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, if you set &lt;code&gt;created by [auto] = Oliver Kohll (oliver@agilechilli.com)&lt;/code&gt;, then (assuming &lt;code&gt;Oliver Kohll (oliver@agilechilli.com)&lt;/code&gt; is their username), the user will only see records they created, as long as the &amp;lsquo;created by [auto]&amp;rsquo; field appears in the view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A similar feature exists to add filters to roles - useful when you may want to apply the same filter to multiple users. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/roles/#multi-tenanting&#34;&gt;roles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;roles&#34;&gt;Roles&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tick a role to assign the user to it. The primary purpose of roles is to apply privileges to groups of users, see &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/roles/&#34;&gt;roles&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s one special role which can be assigned. It will be marked &lt;strong&gt;grants administrative privileges&lt;/strong&gt;. Assigning that role will make a user an administrator, with full permissions over the complete system. They can create/remove users, roles, tables etc., as well as assign themselves privileges on any table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next to each role listed is a list of tiles that will be added to their screen if that role is assigned to them. This is a convenience feature to speed up setting up their home screen. The tiles shown for a role are those which more than half of the members of that role have. Tiles can be manually added and removed by an [administrator] or the user themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If any role is a &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/roles/#multi-tenanting&#34;&gt;filtering role&lt;/a&gt;, the filter applied is also displayed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;privileges&#34;&gt;Privileges&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assign individual table &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/privileges/&#34;&gt;privileges&lt;/a&gt; to a user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When dealing with larger numbers of users it&amp;rsquo;s usually more manageable if you use roles to assign privileges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a user has a privilege due to being a member of a role, that privilege is shown with a shaded blue background. Any additional privileges individually assigned to them are shown in green.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;tiles&#34;&gt;Tiles&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Allows an admin to add/remove &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tiles/&#34;&gt;tiles&lt;/a&gt; for a user. By default users can add/remove tiles themselves too, although this can be disabled through the use of a &lt;a href=&#34;#other-options&#34;&gt;custom UI&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;viewing-users&#34;&gt;Viewing users&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the homepage, &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/introduction/development-mode/&#34;&gt;toggle development mode on&lt;/a&gt; and click the &amp;lsquo;users&amp;rsquo; box at the top right. You&amp;rsquo;ll see a list of existing user accounts. Their details are listed including 2FA status (whether they&amp;rsquo;re using app-based 2FA or not) and when they last logged in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each user&amp;rsquo;s roles are shown. Any &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/roles/#multi-tenanting&#34;&gt;multi-tenanting&lt;/a&gt; roles are also included.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The list of users can be exported to spreadsheet by clicking again on the &amp;lsquo;users&amp;rsquo; box at the top right of the screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that if you want to see a full audit trail of what each user has done (editing, searching, exporting etc.), then you can use the optional &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/usage-monitoring/usage-reporting/#enhanced-audit-trail&#34;&gt;enhanced audit trail&lt;/a&gt; feature (only available on certain plans).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;removing-users&#34;&gt;Removing users&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To remove a user, click one in the list (see above) to open the user editing panel. At the bottom, click the Remove button.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A user removal will have no effect on any data stored in the system. The user&amp;rsquo;s previous comments will still be visible for example and their username will still be logged against any records they&amp;rsquo;re marked as owner of. Their changes will still be in the audit trail and they will be marked as the creator/last editor of records where relevant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may want to take some other actions after deletion e.g. to re-assign records they are assigned to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A deleted user&amp;rsquo;s profile image will be replaced with a standard icon representing a deleted user, when displayed in comment streams etc.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Roles</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/roles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/roles/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The primary purpose of roles is to apply privileges to groups of users, rather than applying them individually. That makes managing large numbers of users easier and also more secure as it&amp;rsquo;s easy to see which privileges each type of user has and which they don&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roles have some other important uses, such as multi-tenanting, described below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;creating-a-role&#34;&gt;Creating a role&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to the homepage and toggle development mode on
42 Click the &amp;lsquo;+ ROLE&amp;rsquo; button at the top right of the screen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/add-role.png&#34; alt=&#34;Add Role&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should now see an editing screen with the details of the role you just created. You can give it a name and there are a few options:
&lt;img src=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/new-role-details.png&#34; alt=&#34;Role details&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Allow Export&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Referrs to exporting to spreadsheet - see &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/integrations/exporting-to-spreadsheet/&#34;&gt;spreadsheet exports&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Allow global editing&lt;/strong&gt;
Users with &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/privileges/&#34;&gt;edit privileges&lt;/a&gt; on a particular table, when added to this role, will be able to perform global edits on the data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To perform a global edit, the user should&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;filter the view (by typing into the filter boxes at the top of each column) to narrow down the rows to those which should be edited&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;double click on a column header in a view, to edit the data in that field. The field must be from the view&amp;rsquo;s parent table.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;click the &amp;rsquo;edit filtered&amp;rsquo; button which appears&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;type in the value you want to apply and follow through the prompts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;User Visibility&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Allow only multi-tenanting views to be seen&lt;/strong&gt;
Used to configure &lt;a href=&#34;#multi-tenanting&#34;&gt;multi-tenanting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;members&#34;&gt;Members&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tick each user to add them to the role. Users will gain all the privileges defined by the role.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;privileges&#34;&gt;Privileges&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Select the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/privileges/&#34;&gt;table privileges&lt;/a&gt; which will apply to members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Privileges are additive - if a user is a member of multiple roles, they gain all the privileges from each of those roles added together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;multi-tenanting&#34;&gt;Multi-tenanting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Multi-tenanting is the ability to separate users into groups who can’t see each other’s data. This can be used for example to allow different sets of companies, clubs, or membership groups (or whatever the organisational group is) to use the same system features whilst remaining separate from each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Multi-tenanting is a powerful feature that can be used not just for customers to segragate data amongst their users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Partners can also use this facility if building software to widely market. In that case, each customer they sign up can very quickly be set up with their own private dataset, whilst the partner retains the ability to add features which will automatically apply to everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To set up multi-tenanting:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;first &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/&#34;&gt;add a text field&lt;/a&gt; to all tables in the system for which you want data to be segragated. The field must be named the same in every table, for example&amp;rsquo;s sake here let&amp;rsquo;s assume it&amp;rsquo;s called &amp;lsquo;account name&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Then create one role for each set of users who you want to segregate. We&amp;rsquo;ll assume there&amp;rsquo;s one called &amp;lsquo;Customer A&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the role details screen for the Customer A role, tick &lt;em&gt;user visibility&lt;/em&gt;. That means that users in this role won&amp;rsquo;t see users in other roles with the same option ticked. In other words, users from Customer A won&amp;rsquo;t be able to select Customer B or Customer C users when doing things like adding comments or assigning users to records.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Under &lt;em&gt;restrict data access&lt;/em&gt; in the role details, enter &lt;code&gt;account name = Customer A&lt;/code&gt;, i.e. &lt;em&gt;Filter Field Name&lt;/em&gt; = &amp;lsquo;account name&amp;rsquo;, &lt;em&gt;Filter Value&lt;/em&gt; = &amp;lsquo;Customer A&amp;rsquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, ensure the account name field is present in all views based on the table. When creating a view, any fields used for multi-tenanting will automatically be added but you may need to retro-fit any existing views.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has two effects -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When a user assigned to the Customer A role creates a new record in one of the multi-tenanting tables, the account name field will automatically be populated with the value Customer A (as entered under &lt;em&gt;restrict data access&lt;/em&gt;). The field will be invisible to them - they won&amp;rsquo;t be able to see or edit the value.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When looking at records in a view, a filter will be automatically applied so the user only sees records where account name = Customer A.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users who &lt;strong&gt;aren&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/strong&gt; a member of the role will see the account name field in the data editing form and in views. This can be useful for allowing e.g. group managers to see all data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If any multi-tenanting roles are set up, then views which &lt;strong&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/strong&gt; contain a multi-tenanting field will be marked in red in the administration interface, as a warning. If a multi-tenanting user loads one of these views, they will see all records. Typically, practically all views will need the multi-tenanting field to be present.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;allow-only-multi-tenanting-views-to-be-seen&#34;&gt;Allow only multi-tenanting views to be seen&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Optionally, this can be ticked. If ticked, user&amp;rsquo;s will only be shown views which contain the multi-tenanting field, &amp;lsquo;Account Name&amp;rsquo; in the example above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an added protection - if the multi-tenanting field is removed from a view, the user won&amp;rsquo;t see it any more. Otherwise they&amp;rsquo;d be able to see all data in the view, even that which they shouldn&amp;rsquo;t. This can also be useful to set when there is partial multi-tenanting set up, i.e. some views are multi-tenanted but others aren&amp;rsquo;t and you only want certain groups (e.g. people outside the organisation) to see the multi-tenanted parts, not everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;complex-multi-tenanting&#34;&gt;Complex multi-tenanting&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;multi-level&#34;&gt;Multi-level&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users may be a member of more than one multi-tenanting role. For example you may use two multi-tenanting fields/roles, one for a company and another for a division. Members of a company role will be able to see data from all divisions in their company and members of both a company and a division role will only be able to see data for a single division.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;multi-account-via-multiple-roles&#34;&gt;Multi-account (via multiple roles)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s also possible for a user to be a member of multiple roles, all of which are set to multi-tenant on the same field, with different values. E.g. if a user is a member of Company A and Company B roles as in our example above, they will see data from those two companies when viewing records, but not Company C.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This works best when the user has read-only privileges on the data, e.g. for a manager reporting on those two companies. They can view records but not add new records, as the system is unable to determine the value of the account name field to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;multi-account-via-_contains_-filtering&#34;&gt;Multi-account (via &lt;em&gt;contains&lt;/em&gt; filtering)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s also possible to define a role filter under &lt;em&gt;restrict data access&lt;/em&gt; with a &amp;lsquo;contains&amp;rsquo; rather than an &amp;lsquo;=&amp;rsquo; filter. You can then use a naming convension for your account name values to allow members of this role to see multiple accounts. As above, users of this role will need to be read-only on the data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;api-setup&#34;&gt;API setup&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a multi-tenanting account, it&amp;rsquo;s possible to create new tenants, with users, by API, as opposed to the manual actions of an administrator. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/integrations/creating-user-accounts/&#34;&gt;Creating user accounts with the API&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;role-properties&#34;&gt;Role properties&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;brand-name-and-domain&#34;&gt;Brand name and domain&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These two options allow system emails (password reset notification etc.) to come from a domain name of your choice and be branded with a particular &amp;lsquo;app&amp;rsquo; name. This can be useful if you&amp;rsquo;re creating a public-facing app using Agilebase, rather than applications for your own staff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To allow the domain name to work, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to contact us to set it up - our server will need to be authorised to send email from your domain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;custom-menus&#34;&gt;Custom menus&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s possible to add custom menu items into the user menu (the one at the top right that appears if you click your user icon). That means if your company has specific help pages or process documentation relevant to your organisation or application, you can make them available from within Agilebase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each custom menu has a title, description and URL, which will be opened in a new tab when the menu item’s chosen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply add these into the &lt;strong&gt;menu title&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;menu description&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;menu URL&lt;/strong&gt; properties of a role. Assigning that role to a user will add the menu item to their profile menu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To add multiple menu items to a user or users, assign multiple roles, each with one menu item defined.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Privileges</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/privileges/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/privileges/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;In Agilebase, there are three privilege levels, as well as a special &amp;lsquo;develop&amp;rsquo; privilege.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The three privileges take effect per table, i.e. a user/role can have certain privileges on one table and different ones on another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Privileges are additive - if a user is a member of multiple roles, they gain all the privileges from each of those roles added together, plus any they may have individually assigned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;privilege-levels&#34;&gt;Privilege levels&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;View&lt;/strong&gt;: ability to see data in a table&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edit&lt;/strong&gt;: ability to create, edit and delete data in a table (create and delete subject to various table options)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Develop&lt;/strong&gt;: the privilege that allows you to use the &amp;lsquo;application building&amp;rsquo; features of Agilebase, relating to a table. Namely the ability to
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;modify the structure, i.e. create/delete fields, tabs, change options etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;create, edit and delete views from the table, including creating charts, maps and word clouds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;upload or create printout templates for views&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;view usage statistics about a table&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Develop also allows some extended user features
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;delete any user&amp;rsquo;s comments from a table&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;unlock locked records to allow editing (one at a time)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;override table options which would normally disallow adding/removing records from a table&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;override options which would normally disallow exporting data to a spreadsheet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;import data from spreadsheet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;override options which would normally disallow global editing of data in the table&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Privilege levels work in conjunction with &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/introduction/learner-progression/&#34;&gt;Learner Progression levels&lt;/a&gt;, for example, only someone at level Citizen Developer level 3 can have Develop privileges assigned to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two Factor Authentication is required for any user with any Citizen Developer or Software Architect role.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;assigning-table-privileges&#34;&gt;Assigning table privileges&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Table privileges can be assigned to one or more users or roles from that table&amp;rsquo;s editing screen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From a user or role editing screen, privileges on one or more tables can be assigned&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two methods are equivalent, whichever is the most convenient for a given purpose can be used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Managing privileges by role rather than by individual user is recommended. That makes managing large numbers of users easier and also more secure as it&amp;rsquo;s easy to see which privileges each type of user has and which they don&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To assign one or more role or user privileges to a table:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/adding-and-removing/#editing-a-table&#34;&gt;Edit a table&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open the &lt;em&gt;roles and privileges&lt;/em&gt; panel, then select or un-select any privileges required&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To assign one or more table privileges to a particular role or user:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On the homepage, toggle on development mode&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click &lt;em&gt;roles&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;users&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select the role or user to assign privileges to, then select or un-select any privileges required&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;related-to-privileges&#34;&gt;Related to privileges&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Database systems often have the concept of row level privileges. The equivalent in Agilebase is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/roles/#multi-tenanting&#34;&gt;multi-tenanting&lt;/a&gt; system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Individual fields in a table can be locked or hidden, see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-options/common-options/#show-if-record-in-view&#34;&gt;field options&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Exporting</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/exporting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/exporting/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Exporting to spreadsheet is only one way of getting data out of Agilebase, but it is the most commonly used amongst everyday users. For less ad-hoc data transfers, such as integrations with third party systems involving incoming and/or outgoing data, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/integrations/&#34;&gt;API&lt;/a&gt; can be used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;allowing-exports&#34;&gt;Allowing exports&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order for a user to be allowed to export to spreadsheet, a number of critieria have to be matched, to suitably protect your organisation&amp;rsquo;s data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The user must have &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/users/#two-factor-authentication&#34;&gt;Two Factor Authentication&lt;/a&gt; enabled&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The view to export from must have exporting enabled (it&amp;rsquo;s enabled by default). To do this
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/introduction/development-mode/&#34;&gt;edit the view&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;under &lt;em&gt;properties and options&lt;/em&gt;, tick &lt;em&gt;allow exports&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The user must also be a member of a &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/roles/&#34;&gt;role&lt;/a&gt; that allows exporting (disabled by default). To allow exporting for a role,
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;on the homepage, toggle &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/introduction/development-mode/&#34;&gt;development mode&lt;/a&gt; on&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;click &lt;em&gt;roles&lt;/em&gt; and select the role you want&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tick &lt;em&gt;allow exports&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A user with &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/privileges/&#34;&gt;develop privileges&lt;/a&gt; on the view&amp;rsquo;s parent table can bypass criteria 2 and 3. This privilege is not commonly applied to normal users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;exporting&#34;&gt;Exporting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A user with the ability to export can do so by opening the view, clicking the export icon near the top right and selecting &lt;em&gt;export&lt;/em&gt; from the options in the menu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/export.png&#34; alt=&#34;exporting&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the user &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/views/filters/&#34;&gt;filters&lt;/a&gt; the data on screen before doing this, only the filtered data will be exported.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The resulting spreadsheet will be in Microsoft Excel format. The first sheet will be some metadata about the export, such as a timestamp, the name of the exporter and any filters applied. The second sheet will be the actual data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Column A in the data sheet holds the internal row ID of each record. This is useful for matching purposes if you&amp;rsquo;re going to be modifying then re-importing the data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;charts&#34;&gt;Charts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the view has &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/charting/&#34;&gt;charts&lt;/a&gt; attached, one sheet per chart will also be included in the spreadsheet. The contents will be the chart data, not the chart visualisation itself, but the visualisation can easily be re-created in the spreadsheet from the data if necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;limits-and-notifications&#34;&gt;Limits and notifications&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An administrator can log whether each table contains commercially sensitive data (ticked by default) and/or personal data (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://gdpr-info.eu/art-4-gdpr/)&#34;&gt;https://gdpr-info.eu/art-4-gdpr/)&lt;/a&gt;. If either of these options is ticked for a view&amp;rsquo;s parent table, you’ll have additional options for&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;notifying all administrators if an export of more than a certain number of rows is done&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;setting a hard limit to completely disallow exports of more than a certain number of rows&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To configure these options, see &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/options/&#34;&gt;tables&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may also want to set an export prompt message to show people when they request an export, to remind people of their data protection obligations under the GDPR for example. This can be done in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/advanced-usage/company-settings/#export-message&#34;&gt;company settings&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Usage Monitoring</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/usage-monitoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/usage-monitoring/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Agilebase comprehensively logs changes to data in the system as well as changes to the structure of the system. Powerful &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/usage-monitoring/usage-reporting/&#34;&gt;reporting facilities&lt;/a&gt; allow the generation of audit trails, trend monitoring, customer success monitoring etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-logged&#34;&gt;What is logged&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;user-actions&#34;&gt;User actions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following actions are recorded&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;logins, including connection details&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;record edits (create, update and delete)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;global edits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;comment additions and removals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;data imports and exports&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;viewing and searching/filtering data in views&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;password resets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When logging a record deletion, the data values deleted are logged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further, for every record in a table, the following metadata is stored and can be included in views:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The creation time and time of last update&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The user who created the record and who last updated it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The view count: how many times the record has been opened&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A visual activity histogram showing the number of edits per week over the past six months&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-types/special-field-types/automatically-present-fields/&#34;&gt;automatically present fields&lt;/a&gt; for full details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;api-and-workflow-actions&#34;&gt;API and workflow actions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data changes or outflows arising from &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/integrations/&#34;&gt;API calls&lt;/a&gt;are logged to the same log store as user actions. Instead of logging the user taking the action, it&amp;rsquo;s logged as an API call with the IP address of the source of the request.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Automated &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/workflows/&#34;&gt;workflow&lt;/a&gt; actions are also logged. Each is marked as a workflow actions with the name of the action (i.e. the view name) to identify it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;administration-and-management-actions&#34;&gt;Administration and management actions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All significant actions are recorded, in summary&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;adding, updating or removing users, roles and privileges&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;table additions and removals, field additions and removals, data constraint additions and removals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;view additions, updates and removals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;chart edits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;viewing-logs&#34;&gt;Viewing logs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Changes to schemas (e.g. tables and views) can be seen in the editing panels for those objects. On the development homepage, a history of recent changes can be seen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Changes to an individual record can be seen from the &amp;lsquo;history&amp;rsquo; link at the bottom left of any editing screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the account has the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/usage-monitoring/usage-reporting/#enhanced-audit-trail&#34;&gt;enhanced audit trail&lt;/a&gt; then all data can be queried using Agilebase views.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;retention-periods&#34;&gt;Retention periods&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data is retained for 12 months as standard. The enhanced audit trail allows customers to define their own retention period, the maximum being unlimited.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Logging in from an app</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/app_login/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2021 09:20:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/app_login/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s possible for a developer to create a third party application, for example a phone or tablet app, that communicates with Agilebase via the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/integrations&#34;&gt;API&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now to use the API, you don&amp;rsquo;t need to authenticate as a user, as long as the app has the correct Authorization key(s), it can read and write data to Agilebase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, in some cases the app may need to confirm that someone has a valid Agilebase account before allowing them to use the app. This may or may not be necessary depending on the use case, for example depending on whether the app is free to use for anyone, or must be limited to paying customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To validate a user, the app must redirect them to the Agilebase login page, let them log in and confirm that was successful. Therefore, a HTTP client is necessary - this can be a &amp;lsquo;web view component&amp;rsquo; or a programmatic client such as the &lt;a href=&#34;https://hc.apache.org/&#34;&gt;Apache HTTP Client&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Java_%28programming_language%29&#34;&gt;Java&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this example, we&amp;rsquo;ll use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://reactjs.org/&#34;&gt;React&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.npmjs.com/package/react-native-webview&#34;&gt;Native Web View&lt;/a&gt; but the principle is the same for any programming language or library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;general-principle&#34;&gt;General Principle&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The application must reproduce the same login process as a human would, using a HTTP client. Importantly, the HTTP client must support cookies, as the login process depends on them, in particular setting a &lt;code&gt;JSESSIONID&lt;/code&gt; cookie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make a request to load the page &lt;a href=&#34;https://appserver.gtportalbase.com/Agilebase/AppController.servlet?return=user_details&#34;&gt;https://appserver.gtportalbase.com/Agilebase/AppController.servlet?return=user_details&lt;/a&gt;. This will return the login page and set the cookie value.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Submit the login form using the user&amp;rsquo;s username and password. If using a programattic process i.e. making the calls from code rather than using a web view, this means making a form POST to &lt;code&gt;/Agilebase/j_security_check&lt;/code&gt; with the parameters &lt;code&gt;j_username&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;j_password&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Detect whether the login&amp;rsquo;s successful. If not, the standard Agilebase login failure page will be returned&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If successful, a HTML page will be returned containing three hidden input fields, &lt;code&gt;username&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;forename&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;surname&lt;/code&gt; containing relevant details for the logged in user. If being called from a React Native Web View, the page will also post back messages to React using this JavaScript:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;if (window.ReactNativeWebView) {
    window.ReactNativeWebView.postMessage(&amp;#34;username:&amp;#34; + username);
    window.ReactNativeWebView.postMessage(&amp;#34;forename:&amp;#34; + forename);
    window.ReactNativeWebView.postMessage(&amp;#34;surname:&amp;#34; + surname);
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;example&#34;&gt;Example&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a full example of a login.js page using the React Native Web View. NB this is an example taken from a full application, so you will need to modify it / strip it back to suit your needs, before it can be run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;//Node imports
import React, {useEffect, useRef, useState} from &amp;#39;react&amp;#39;;
import {View, StatusBar, Image, ImageBackground, ScrollView} from &amp;#39;react-native&amp;#39;;

//Local imports
import {styles} from &amp;#39;../../../styles/loginStyles&amp;#39;;
import {Images, Colors, Constants, Language} from &amp;#39;../../../common&amp;#39;;
import {useNetInfo} from &amp;#34;@react-native-community/netinfo&amp;#34;;
import { WebView } from &amp;#39;react-native-webview&amp;#39;;
import {useDispatch, useSelector} from &amp;#39;react-redux&amp;#39;;
import {updateUserData} from &amp;#39;../../../redux/actions/commonAction&amp;#39;;
import commonFunctions from &amp;#39;../../../common/commonFunctions&amp;#39;;
import SplashScreen from &amp;#39;react-native-splash-screen&amp;#39;
const {fontSize, fontFamily, Window} = Constants;

const LoginScreen = (props) =&amp;gt; {
    const dispatch = useDispatch();
    const {user_data} = useSelector(state =&amp;gt; state);
    const netInfo = useNetInfo();

    useEffect(function () {
        SplashScreen.hide();
        console.log(&amp;#39;netInfo==============&amp;#39;, netInfo)
        if(netInfo?.isInternetReachable || netInfo?.details != null){
            checkUser();
        }
    }, [netInfo, user_data]);

    const checkUser = () =&amp;gt; {
        if(user_data &amp;amp;&amp;amp; user_data?.forename &amp;amp;&amp;amp; user_data?.surname &amp;amp;&amp;amp; user_data?.username){
            goToNextPage();
        }
        console.log(&amp;#39;user_data&amp;#39;, user_data)
    }

    const goToNextPage = async () =&amp;gt; {
        await commonFunctions.removeTimeStamp();
        navigateToNextPage();
    }

    const onResponseFromWebView = (event) =&amp;gt; {
        const eventData = event.nativeEvent.data;
        console.log(&amp;#39;eventData&amp;#39;, eventData);
        if (eventData.includes(&amp;#39;username&amp;#39;)) {
            dispatch(updateUserData({username: eventData.split(&amp;#39;username:&amp;#39;)[1]}));
        } else if (eventData.includes(&amp;#39;forename&amp;#39;)) {
            dispatch(updateUserData({forename: eventData.split(&amp;#39;forename:&amp;#39;)[1]}));
        } else if (eventData.includes(&amp;#39;surname&amp;#39;)) {
            dispatch(updateUserData({surname: eventData.split(&amp;#39;surname:&amp;#39;)[1]}));
        }
    }

    const navigateToNextPage = () =&amp;gt; {
        if (netInfo?.isInternetReachable) {
            return props.navigation.navigate(&amp;#39;Loading&amp;#39;);
        }
        return props.navigation.navigate(&amp;#39;MyApplicationPage&amp;#39;);
    }

    return (
        &amp;lt;View style={styles.container}&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;StatusBar backgroundColor={Colors.black} barStyle={&amp;#39;dark-content&amp;#39;}/&amp;gt;
            {(netInfo?.isInternetReachable &amp;amp;&amp;amp; !user_data?.surname) ?
                &amp;lt;WebView
                    source={{uri: &amp;#39;https://appserver.gtportalbase.com/Agilebase/AppController.servlet?return=user_details&amp;#39;}}
                    onMessage={onResponseFromWebView}
                    textZoom={100}
                    sharedCookiesEnabled={true}
                /&amp;gt; :
                &amp;lt;View style={styles.loadingImage}&amp;gt;
                    &amp;lt;Image source={Images.logo}/&amp;gt;
                &amp;lt;/View&amp;gt;
            }
        &amp;lt;/View&amp;gt;
    );
};

export default LoginScreen;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
