<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>agileBase docs – Charting</title>
    <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/charting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Charting on agileBase docs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 11:40:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/charting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Built In Charting</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/charting/built-in-charting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/charting/built-in-charting/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Charting is not strictly an administrator function, as any user can create charts and other data visualisations, such as maps and word clouds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, it&amp;rsquo;s useful for administrators to know how the system works in outline, so they can support users and also because creating charts may be a key part of building an application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In agileBase, charts &amp;lsquo;belong to&amp;rsquo; a view. Each view can have a collection of charts. Users can toggle between viewing data rows and looking at charts based on those rows. When a user filters data using the quick filter boxes at the top of the screen, the data or charts (whichever is shown) will update to match the filtered results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;creating-a-chart&#34;&gt;Creating a chart&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the tiles interface, open the tile and view to use as a source of chart data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click the charts button to the left of the data rows displayed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click the &lt;em&gt;add/edit chart or map&lt;/em&gt; button&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Follow each of the steps (1 - 3) on screen to build the chart&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the last step, give a name to the chart and press &lt;em&gt;save&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When choosing a type of chart in step 3, small previews will be displayed based on some of the chart data. However some chart types may display a message rather than a preview. In this case, the chart data selected in step 1 is not applicable for this chart type.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, if in step 1 we have a count of items per year:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/chart-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Chart - step 1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;then the scatter diagram will work but the bubble chart won&amp;rsquo;t. For the bubble chart, &lt;strong&gt;two&lt;/strong&gt; y-axis measurements are required, one to specify the position of the bubble on the y-axis, plus another to determine the relative size of the bubble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/chart-bubble.png&#34; alt=&#34;Chart - step 3&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;embedding-charts-in-forms&#34;&gt;Embedding charts in forms&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Charts can be embedded into tables. When the user opens a record, the chart will automatically filter to show data pertaining to that record only.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So for example if you have a chart of sales per month per customer, which you embed into a customer table, it will show as sales per month, only for the customer on screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is accomplished by using a view with chart(s) as a &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-types/special-field-types/referenced-data/&#34;&gt;cross-referenced panel&lt;/a&gt; - see that page for setup information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;embedding-charts-in-tabs&#34;&gt;Embedding charts in tabs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a tab contains many &amp;lsquo;child&amp;rsquo; records, e.g. an organisation may have a tab which contains financial data for the past 10 years, then charts can display above the rows of data when the tab&amp;rsquo;s opened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To accomplish this, simply add a chart to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/hierarchy-navigation/tabs/#tab-view&#34;&gt;view used by the tab&lt;/a&gt;. When the tab is opened, the chart will automatically be filtered to only show data pertaining to the parent table, in a similar fashion to how charts embedded using cross-referenced panels are filtered, as above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/endole-example.png&#34; alt=&#34;Endole example&#34; title=&#34;Example of a chart in a tab&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;subscribing-users-or-roles-to-charts&#34;&gt;Subscribing users or roles to charts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users can be subscribed to charts (or subscribe themselves) to receive them by email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In a view with some charts, open the charts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next to &amp;lsquo;Send these charts to me&amp;rsquo;, select a frequency, e.g. monthly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Under &amp;lsquo;Include data too&amp;rsquo;, select tabular data to include in the email too - various options will be displayed e.g. all new rows since the last email&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next to &amp;lsquo;roles&amp;rsquo;, select a role to send the charts and data to. All users in the role will be subscribed. Multiple roles can be added&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the view has no charts, this function can be used to send tabular data only&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;going-further&#34;&gt;Going further&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;agileBase can also integrate with third party business intelligence and reporting tools, using the API Creator. A worked example is &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/integrations/pull-example-power-bi/&#34;&gt;here for Power BI&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Business Intelligence</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/charting/business-intelligence/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/charting/business-intelligence/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before setting up a BI connection, please be aware of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/charting#privacy-and-data-security&#34;&gt;data privacy and security&lt;/a&gt; considerations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At agileBase we host an instance of &lt;a href=&#34;https://superset.apache.org&#34;&gt;Apache Superset&lt;/a&gt; which can be used by customers to create reporting dashboards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However the setup processes below also applies to third party tools such as Power BI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;initial-setup&#34;&gt;Initial Setup&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first step is to &lt;a href=&#34;https://agilechilli.com/contact-us/&#34;&gt;contact us&lt;/a&gt; to request we set up an Apache Superset account (this will also allow connections from other BI tools). We will then set up as many Superset users you require - there is no ongoing cost for these login accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that Superset logins are separate from agileBase ones - the usernames and passwords can be different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sending-data-to-superset&#34;&gt;Sending data to Superset&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A developer with MANAGE privileges on a view&amp;rsquo;s parent table can set this up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In agileBase, open the view you wish to report on. Ensure it has all the necessary fields and calculations in it which you want to report on. If not, add them before continuing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click the charting icon to view the chart setup interface&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At the bottom of the screen, tick &amp;lsquo;send data to a shareable dashboard&amp;rsquo;. As this makes data available &lt;a href=&#34;charting#privacy-and-data-security&#34;&gt;outside of agileBase&lt;/a&gt;, you will be asked to confirm you will treat the data in a way which maintains privacy and security before enabling the feature.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within a few seconds, the data will then be available in Superset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;changes&#34;&gt;Changes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s easy for developers to make changes to views in agileBase, for example adding / removing fields, changing calculations or just renaming a view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, when the BI connection is active, bear in mind that certain changes will disable the connection. The reason is that once data is set up to transfer to a separate system, the other system typically expects it to remain in the same format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That means that if you rename the view or move it, or rename/delete fields and calculations, you may afterwards need to re-connect BI by repeating step 3 above. Additionally, check your charts in Superset, to see if they need re-creating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;creating-dashboards-in-superset&#34;&gt;Creating dashboards in Superset&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that you&amp;rsquo;ve set up agileBase to make data available to Superset, you can create charts and dashboards there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a &amp;lsquo;dataset&amp;rsquo; in Superset, corresponding to the view you set up above
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From the &lt;em&gt;Data&lt;/em&gt; menu at the top, select &lt;em&gt;datasets&lt;/em&gt;, then click the &lt;em&gt;+ dataset&lt;/em&gt; button&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Under &lt;em&gt;Schema&lt;/em&gt;, select your company name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Under &lt;em&gt;Table&lt;/em&gt;, select the name of the view that you set up above&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click &lt;em&gt;ADD&lt;/em&gt; at the bottom of the dialog (you may need to scroll down)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create the chart
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click &lt;em&gt;Charts&lt;/em&gt; at the top, then &lt;em&gt;+ Chart&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select the dataset created above&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choose a chart type, then &lt;em&gt;Create New Chart&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drag metrics (e.g. &amp;lsquo;COUNT&amp;rsquo;) and fields from the left into the appropriate areas in the middle column&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click &lt;em&gt;Save&lt;/em&gt; and Superset will prompt you to add the chart to a new or existing dashboard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Access the dashboard from the &lt;em&gt;Dashboards&lt;/em&gt; menu at the top&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more details on creating charts and editing dashboards, including video walkthroughs, see &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.preset.io/docs/create-a-chart&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first view sent to Superset is free, further views can be purchased in bundles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
