<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>agileBase docs – Special Field Types</title>
    <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-types/special-field-types/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Special Field Types on agileBase docs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-types/special-field-types/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Separators</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-types/special-field-types/separators/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-types/special-field-types/separators/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;A separator field doesn&amp;rsquo;t actually store any data, but is used as a marker of the start of a block of fields. Create a separator  and move it to just before the field which should be the first in a block.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/table-layouts/&#34;&gt;table layout&lt;/a&gt;, these blocks will be displayed in different ways, but in all cases will form a distinct group of fields.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inline help can be added for separators in the same way as for normal fields, by adding a field description. This help text will apply to the whole block of fields created by a separator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a system with several&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/blocks-one-expanded.png&#34; alt=&#34;blocks&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Comment Feeds</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-types/special-field-types/comment-feeds/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-types/special-field-types/comment-feeds/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Adding a comment feed to a table adds a discussion area to a form, transforming its usefulness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comment feeds in agileBase are quite a large topic, as one of the most often used features central to the platform. It&amp;rsquo;s common for at least one comment feed to be added to every table in the system, allowing users to collaborate and discuss data wherever they are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ability to discuss and comment on data can be one of the most important mechanisms used to break down silo thinking and help organisations that wish to adopt a more systematic or process orientated view of things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;comment-feeds-in-action&#34;&gt;Comment feeds in action&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s an example of a comment feed in a table, being used to add a new comment. Previous comments can be seen underneath, with the user and date/time of each.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/add-comment.png&#34; alt=&#34;add comment&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The available recipients are those people who have privileges to view data in the table (it&amp;rsquo;s no use sending a comment to someone who can&amp;rsquo;t see the data being discussed).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The user interface intelligently selects an initial list of recipients from those available, but they can be added or removed by the user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this example, Cliff, Gemma and Mark have been set to receive email notifications as well. The email they receive will contain a link to take them directly to the record the comment was added to. They can reply to the email to log an additional comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People who aren&amp;rsquo;t recipients of a comment will still see the comment when they visit the record it&amp;rsquo;s been added to, they just won&amp;rsquo;t get a notification in their comments stream or elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People who are mentioned by name in a comment (Mark in this example) will get an in-app alert as well as the comment appearing in their comment stream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A user&amp;rsquo;s notification options affect whether they receive comments from a particular table or person by default, and how they receive those comments. The table option &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/options/#accept-emails-to-this-address&#34;&gt;email notifications&lt;/a&gt; also affects this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;comments-to-other-fields&#34;&gt;Comments to other fields&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although adding a comments feed field is the easiest way of allowing people to comment on data, users can at any time add a comment to &lt;strong&gt;any&lt;/strong&gt; field on the screen, by hovering over the field until an &amp;lsquo;add comment&amp;rsquo; icon appears. This opens a smaller, basic comment adding interface, without the options for choosing recipients above, rather the default set of recipients is always used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-comments-stream-tile&#34;&gt;The comments stream tile&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When someone&amp;rsquo;s the receipient of a comment, they&amp;rsquo;ll be able to see it in the comments stream tile on their homepage. Clicking on it will navigate to the related record. We won&amp;rsquo;t go into every detail of the user interface in this administrator documentation, but comments can be searched and the comments tile can be expanded to full screen like any other tile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;email-integration&#34;&gt;Email integration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As above, anyone who receives a comment notification can reply to the email to add another comment (their email address must be their username or recorded in their user defailt), or they can click on a link to view the related record including previous comments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, comments are also the mechanism by which emails from external parties can be logged - see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/options/#accept-emails-to-this-address&#34;&gt;accept emails to this address&lt;/a&gt; table option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/workflows/send-email/&#34;&gt;workflow&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/workflows/send-chaser/&#34;&gt;chaser&lt;/a&gt; sends an outgoing email, that is logged as a comment (including any attachments) too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;slack-integration&#34;&gt;Slack integration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.slack.com&#34;&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt; is integrated via &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/advanced-usage/company-settings/&#34;&gt;company options&lt;/a&gt;, every comment added will also be sent to your Slack workspace.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Referenced data</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-types/special-field-types/referenced-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-types/special-field-types/referenced-data/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Most fields in a table allow data entry into that table, but referenced data fields allow data from &lt;strong&gt;other&lt;/strong&gt; places to be embedded, specifically &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/views/&#34;&gt;views&lt;/a&gt;, created from any table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Optionally, the embedded data can be editable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This can be used for many purposes, such as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;showing calculations, e.g. when editing a recipe, you may want to show the total cost/kg of all ingredients and packaging in that recipe&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;embedding charts, e.g. in the record for a customer, you may want to show the last 12 months of sales data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;allowing quick editing of related data, e.g. after selecting a customer contact for a sales opportunity, allow quick editing of their contact details without having to navigate away from the opportunity record&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some more esoteric uses are also possible&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;referenced data can be used as a source of data to populate standard fields in the form, i.e. to provide default values for fields - see &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-options/common-options/#set-from-previous-referenced-field&#34;&gt;relation field options&lt;/a&gt; for more information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a referenced data field can be displayed as a button to &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/workflows/advanced/workflow-buttons/&#34;&gt;manually run a workflow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;adding-a-referenced-field&#34;&gt;Adding a referenced field&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Referenced fields are based on views. The contents of a view will be displayed in the form where a field referencing data from that view is added.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The way it works is that the chosen view must contain the ID field of the table the referenced field is added to. When displaying data, the view is filtered to only show records where the ID matches that of the record being edited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s take an example - you wish to include details of any ingredients supplied by a company in a supplier details screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, create a view of ingredients linked to each supplier. It may have data in it such as the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/referenced-source-view.png&#34; alt=&#34;referenced source view&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is some repetition in this view because each ingredient can be supplied by more than one supplier. Each line represents an ingredient/supplier combination. The supplier names aren&amp;rsquo;t included in this particular view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a field referencing this view is added to the suppliers table, the output may display like this, when editing a particular supplier:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/referenced-panels.png&#34; alt=&#34;referenced panels&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So to summarise, the steps are&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/views/creating-a-view/&#34;&gt;Create&lt;/a&gt; or find a view containing the data you wish to embed. It must contain the ID field of the table the data is embedded in (in this case &amp;lsquo;opportunities&amp;rsquo;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/#adding-a-field&#34;&gt;Add a field&lt;/a&gt; of type &lt;em&gt;referenced data&lt;/em&gt;. Select the table your target view was created from, then the target view itself, before pressing &lt;em&gt;create field&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually, there is one case in which the rule that the view must contain the ID of the table the referenced data is being added to. That&amp;rsquo;s when you want to show &lt;strong&gt;all&lt;/strong&gt; rows from the view, without filtering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is typically used in a minority of cases, but can be useful when you want to embed data that isn&amp;rsquo;t related to the target table. For example, showing some global settings that may affect the functionality of a system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;showing-one-or-more-rows&#34;&gt;Showing one or more rows&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If more than one row in the view has an ID matching the ID of the table being added to, all will be shown. There is limited space in a form, so if there are lots, then a &amp;lsquo;see more&amp;rsquo; option will appear after the first few rows. For a more compact view, &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-options/referenced-field-options/#tabular-display&#34;&gt;tabular display&lt;/a&gt; can be chosen in the referenced field options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;showing-charts&#34;&gt;Showing charts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the view used has one or more &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/charting/&#34;&gt;charts&lt;/a&gt;, they will be shown instead of the data rows. The filtering acts exactly the same way, only data matching the containing table&amp;rsquo;s ID is used as the source of the chart data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/embedded-chart.png&#34; alt=&#34;embedded chart&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;showing-images-and-documents&#34;&gt;Showing images and documents&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Images and documents can be included in referenced panels too. Just include a &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-types/special-field-types/file/&#34;&gt;file field&lt;/a&gt; in the view used for the panel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;making-referenced-data-editable&#34;&gt;Making referenced data editable&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Optionally, referenced data can be made editable by clicking on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A view containing the containing table&amp;rsquo;s ID can be created one of two ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a view from the containing table, &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/views/joins/&#34;&gt;joining&lt;/a&gt; to other tables&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a view from another table, joining it to the containing table&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a view is built the second way and embedded into the table via a referenced field, the data will be editable: clicking on an element of referenced data will turn it into a data entry form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it&amp;rsquo;s built the first way, data will not be editable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an editable referenced field, only fields directly from the table made to create the view will be editable. Other fields will be read-only.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Automatically present fields</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-types/special-field-types/automatically-present-fields/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-types/special-field-types/automatically-present-fields/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;When every &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/&#34;&gt;table&lt;/a&gt; is created, a series of fields are automatically added. These aren&amp;rsquo;t displayed in the data entry form of a table, but are available to be added into views.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;id-field&#34;&gt;ID field&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In database parlance, the table&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Primary_key&#34;&gt;primary key&lt;/a&gt; - providing a unique ID to identify each record. Values are generated in sequence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;agileBase creates and manages primary keys, using them to link related tables together automatically, however it&amp;rsquo;s useful for administrators to understand the concept and implementation. Many platform features depending on including the ID field for a particular table in a view, such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-types/special-field-types/referenced-data/&#34;&gt;referenced fields&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;creation-time-auto&#34;&gt;Creation Time [Auto]&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The record&amp;rsquo;s creation time, accurate to the ms and displayed to the second by default.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;created-by-auto&#34;&gt;Created By [Auto]&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The user ID of the person who created the record, in the form &lt;code&gt;Forename Surname (username)&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This format is used to identify a user everywhere in agileBase, for example when assigning a record to a user. When a user ID identifies a person in a &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/workflows/send-chaser/&#34;&gt;chaser&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/workflows/send-email/&#34;&gt;email workflow&lt;/a&gt;, agileBase will look up and use their email address, from their account details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a record is created by a workflow, the Created By will be &lt;code&gt;System User (system)&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When created by an API call, it will be &lt;code&gt;Public API (IP Address) (public api&lt;/code&gt;, where the IP address of the calling system is recorded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;last-modified-auto&#34;&gt;Last Modified [Auto]&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The record&amp;rsquo;s last modification time. Behaviour is similar to Creation Time [Auto], above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;modified-by-auto&#34;&gt;Modified By [Auto]&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The user ID of the person who last updated the record. Behaviour is the same as Created By [Auto].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;locked-auto&#34;&gt;Locked [Auto]&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A boolean value which is true if the record has been &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/options/#records-lockable&#34;&gt;locked&lt;/a&gt; by a workflow, to disallow further editing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;view-count-auto&#34;&gt;View Count [Auto]&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How many times a particular record has been opened or viewed by a user. A measure of popularity if you like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;activity-histogram-auto&#34;&gt;Activity Histogram [Auto]&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The activity histogram of a record shows the relative activity of each record, i.e. the number of record edits that have occurred, over a period of time. It&amp;rsquo;s displayed as a small &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sparkline&#34;&gt;sparkline&lt;/a&gt; chart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The activity over the past six months is shown, one point, or &amp;lsquo;spike&amp;rsquo; per week. The more edits in a week there are, the higher the spike. Edits to &amp;lsquo;child&amp;rsquo; records in a tab of a main record are also counted, but contribute relatively less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an example of use, in a display of sales opportunities, you want to know which opps. are being actively worked and which haven’t had any activity for some time. The activity histogram shows the ‘shape’ of activity over a period of time, at a glance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With sparklines next to every record on screen, you can quickly get an idea of the relative activity of each.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/activity-histogram.png&#34; alt=&#34;activity histogram&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;comments-feed-auto&#34;&gt;Comments Feed [Auto]&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This field contains an amalagamation of all &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-types/special-field-types/comment-feeds/&#34;&gt;comments&lt;/a&gt; added to a record, newest at the top. Adding this field to a view allows recent comments to be seen for many records at once and is an easy way of making record comments searchable. As opposed to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tiles/&#34;&gt;comments tile&lt;/a&gt;, the user sees all record comments, not just those they are a recipient for, but only those for the table in question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note - the Comments Feed [Auto] field combines comments from all comment fields in the table, if there&amp;rsquo;s more than one, as well as any comments added to other fields.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;document-storage-mb-auto&#34;&gt;Document Storage (MB) [Auto]&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shows the amount of storage used for all documents attached to a record (uploaded or generated), including previous versions. Adding this field to a view allows you to total up storage across all (or a subset of) records.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: File fields</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-types/special-field-types/file/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-types/special-field-types/file/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;By default, a file field added to a table will let users upload files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a file field is added to a view, a link to download the file is included.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Files previews can be displayed in an &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tiles/&#34;&gt;image/document library&lt;/a&gt; tile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;version-history&#34;&gt;Version history&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a new file is uploaded (or generated), any previous file is kept as a previous version, displayed with a timestamp, for download by users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;generating-pdf-documents&#34;&gt;Generating PDF documents&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a template is uploaded using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-options/file-field-options/&#34;&gt;file field options&lt;/a&gt;, the file upload button in the user interface will be replaced by a generate button.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-types/special-field-types/file/document-templates/&#34;&gt;document templates&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: File fields</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-types/special-field-types/file/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-types/special-field-types/file/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;By default, a file field added to a table will let users upload files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a file field is added to a view, a link to download the file is included.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Files previews can be displayed in an &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tiles/&#34;&gt;image/document library&lt;/a&gt; tile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;version-history&#34;&gt;Version history&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a new file is uploaded (or generated), any previous file is kept as a previous version, displayed with a timestamp, for download by users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;generating-pdf-documents&#34;&gt;Generating PDF documents&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a template is uploaded using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-options/file-field-options/#template&#34;&gt;file field options&lt;/a&gt;, the file upload button in the user interface will be replaced by a generate button.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-types/special-field-types/file/document-templates/&#34;&gt;document templates&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
