<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Agilebase docs – Calculations</title>
    <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/tags/calculations/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Calculations on Agilebase docs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 13:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/tags/calculations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Guides: 4. Calculated Datafields</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/guides/guide1-crm/calculated-datafields/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/guides/guide1-crm/calculated-datafields/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning Aim:&lt;/strong&gt;   Introduce calculations and basic SQL&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prerequisites:&lt;/strong&gt; User to have understanding of relational data&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ability to use your existing data to calculate new information will dramatically enhance the user interface, and lead your users to create new data!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this step fo the guide we&amp;rsquo;ll start with something simple, expanding the data we know about Organisations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;calculating-the-number-of-contacts-belonging-to-an-organisation&#34;&gt;Calculating the number of contacts belonging to an Organisation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the All Organisations view as a starting point, clone it and rename it &amp;ldquo;Organisation - Calculations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We will need to join down to the Contacts table, before we create our calculation field.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to “fields”, highlight the add a calculation section&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add a calculation called “Number of Contacts”, of type ‘Whole number’.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Press Add&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The important area is the ‘Calculation Definition’. In this example we want to count the number of contacts each organisation has. We can do this by using a SQL statement called Count.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;count()
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Between the brackets we choose which field we want to count. In this case the contact record&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;count({contacts.id:contacts})
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;We now need to press update to tell agileBase we have finished editing our calculation. Press Update.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see the system has correctly identified that count is something known as an aggregate field and ticked the box for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you click back on Fields you should see the list and how calculations are highlighted in purple to distinguish from regular fields taken from a table definition. Lets drag our calculation near the front”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Move the calc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Closing the edit allows us to see our results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a very simple example of an SQL calculation. For more examples as well as a link to the underlying Postgres documentation visit - &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/views/calculations/examples/&#34;&gt;docs- calculation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[guide 1.4 - video 1]
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/kxsIr6yHlNg&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;calculating-the-date-of-our-latest-sale-to-create-a-our-customers-list&#34;&gt;Calculating the Date of our Latest Sale to create a &amp;ldquo;Our Customers&amp;rdquo; list&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A further useful example is to show how we can use the results of a calculation to create a Live view, for example &amp;ldquo;Our Customers&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start by adding a join down to Sales opportunities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instead of adding an existing Sales opportunity field let’s add a calculation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to list of fields and add a calculation called “Latest Sale”, which of course will be a ‘Date’ field.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Press Add&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time our SQL looks like&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt; max({sales opportunities.date won})
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;The same aggregate field option should be ticked for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can add a filter based on the values in the calculation e.g. where ‘Latest Sale’ is not blank!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should now see your list of Organisations has dramatically shrunk&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are following along, it makes sense for a Quick name change to make it “All customers”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[guide 1.4 - video 2]
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/tGIsw4uhYZQ&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
