<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Agilebase docs – Citizen Developer level 1</title>
    <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/tags/citizen-developer-level-1/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Citizen Developer level 1 on Agilebase docs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 13:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/tags/citizen-developer-level-1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Introduction</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/introduction/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;People from many different backgrounds use Agilebase to create software that solves problems for them and their organisations. Some are seasoned IT professionals, who are able to code but are new to the no-code world. Some have used tools like Microsoft Access or newer no-code tools and many if not most are from outside of the IT world completely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a place for everyone - to encourage this diversity and ensure people can pick up Agilebase at whatever level is most appropriate, we&amp;rsquo;ve designed our unique five step Learner Progression route.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learner Progression starts at a level appropriate to someone who has no experience of software development at all. You can learn &amp;lsquo;on the job&amp;rsquo;, by following video guides and documentation and with support from partners, to become a fully fledged software architect, whatever your background.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The learner progression page below gives an outline of this route and the development mode page gives practical information on how to start using development features.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Learner Progression</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/introduction/learner-progression/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/introduction/learner-progression/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Agilebase&amp;rsquo;s learner progression pathway enables you to transform your career. You can go from  a citizen developer to a no-code software architect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Citizen developers can create their own applications using no code. Software architects can build complex applications, including powerful workflow features and integrations with other applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To go on this journey requires no technical knowledge. Beginners - &amp;ldquo;citizen developers&amp;rdquo; - come from a diverse range of non-IT backgrounds. The only skills you need are the ability to think, be willing to learn, and be able to plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agilebase will help you every step of the way. And you can stop at the level that is useful to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agilebase enables citizen developers to pass through five stages on their way to becoming software architects:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;citizen-developer-level-1&#34;&gt;Citizen Developer Level 1&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the start of the Agilebase journey. At this level you can create your own applications, using no coding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An Agilebase citizen developer can create &amp;lsquo;personal copies&amp;rsquo; of any &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/views/&#34;&gt;view&lt;/a&gt; and edit those copies&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;remove or add fields, excepting any that are marked &amp;lsquo;confidential&amp;rsquo; (only higher level developers can access those fields)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;rearrange fields&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;change field sorting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;add filters or remove filters (except on &amp;lsquo;confidential&amp;rsquo; fields)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;add and remove &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/charting/&#34;&gt;charts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A confidential field is one that has a &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-options/common-options/#show-if-record-in-view&#34;&gt;visibility&lt;/a&gt; rule, or is used for &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/roles/#multi-tenanting&#34;&gt;multi-tenanting&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The personal copy of the view is seen only by them. For example, a citizen developer may create a list of records filtered to show ones assigned to them. Everyone else in the organisation sees only the original view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You earn the Citizen Developer title once you have carried out standard functions. These include adding and editing records. The title is assigned to internal staff not to &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/users/community-users/&#34;&gt;community users&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;citizen-developer-level-2&#34;&gt;Citizen Developer Level 2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This level is suggested or &amp;lsquo;unlocked&amp;rsquo; once a citizen developer has carried out a certain number of citizen development functions and has therefore started to learn how no code development works in a safe environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However to activate the level, it must be manually assigned by a Software Architect level user, as it allows changes to the system which can affect other users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A citizen developer level 2 can&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;create new views that everyone can see, from any table
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;edit them as per the citizen developer functionality above&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;additionally they can add and remove simple joins, to include data from other tables in a view&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;remove views that they themselves have created (not those that others have)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;create their own &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/&#34;&gt;tables&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;add, edit and remove fields and tabs from those tables&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;edit basic properties of the fields&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;assign privileges (up to edit) on those tables, using existing roles or direct user privileges&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;create &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tiles/&#34;&gt;tiles&lt;/a&gt; and delete tiles they&amp;rsquo;ve added themselves&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;citizen-developer-level-3&#34;&gt;Citizen Developer Level 3&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Software Architect (see below) can, at their discretion, assign a citizen developer 3 &amp;lsquo;develop&amp;rsquo; privileges on a table (or tables).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That allows them to&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;add &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/&#34;&gt;fields&lt;/a&gt; to those table, excluding referenced fields&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;remove fields that they themselves have added (not others)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;edit the basic properties of any field in those tables, e.g. the list of options in a dropdown box&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, actions not related to having develop privileges on a particular table are&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;edit the basic properties of any regular view. However, workflow, API and some other types of system view will be read-only&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;junior-software-architect&#34;&gt;Junior Software Architect&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A junior software architect can use practically all of the application building functionality of Agilebase. For example&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/workflows/&#34;&gt;workflows&lt;/a&gt; (including chasers, document generation)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set up &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/integrations/&#34;&gt;APIs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add complex &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/views/joins/&#34;&gt;joins&lt;/a&gt; to views&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create, edit and delete &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/roles/&#34;&gt;roles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assign &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/privileges/&#34;&gt;privileges&lt;/a&gt; to roles or users up to the &amp;rsquo;edit&amp;rsquo; level&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove fields, views etc. created by anyone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edit the advanced properties of fields and views, including field visibility rules (confidentiality rules) for example&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their only limitations are to do with managing the organisation as a whole, including other users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;software-architect&#34;&gt;Software Architect&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as building and disassembling applications, software architects can set company-wide settings and manage the account as a whole. They have full discretionary spend and can&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add and remove &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/users/&#34;&gt;users&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edit company level settings (e.g. whether to enforce 2FA)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Change table &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/sensitive-data/&#34;&gt;sensitive and personal data&lt;/a&gt; settings (GDPR)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;View and controls users&amp;rsquo; learner progression levels and &amp;lsquo;budget&amp;rsquo; limits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assign any privileges up to the highest &amp;lsquo;develop&amp;rsquo; level&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Citizen Developer Level 1</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/introduction/learner-progression-levels/citizen-developer-level-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/introduction/learner-progression-levels/citizen-developer-level-1/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the start of the Agilebase journey. At this level you can create your own customisations, using no coding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An Agilebase citizen developer can create &amp;lsquo;personal copies&amp;rsquo; of any &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/views/&#34;&gt;view&lt;/a&gt; and edit those copies&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;remove or add fields, excepting any that are marked &amp;lsquo;confidential&amp;rsquo; (only higher level developers can access those fields)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;rearrange fields&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;change field sorting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;add filters or remove filters (except on &amp;lsquo;confidential&amp;rsquo; fields)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;add and remove &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/charting/&#34;&gt;charts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A confidential field is one that has a &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-options/common-options/#show-if-record-in-view&#34;&gt;visibility&lt;/a&gt; rule, or is used for &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/roles/#multi-tenanting&#34;&gt;multi-tenanting&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The personal copy of the view is seen only by them. For example, a citizen developer may create a list of records filtered to show ones assigned to them. Everyone else in the organisation sees only the original view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You earn the Citizen Developer title once you have carried out standard functions. These include adding and editing records. The title is assigned to internal staff not to &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/users/community-users/&#34;&gt;community users&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;useful-links&#34;&gt;Useful Links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visit our helpful introductory guide to personalising your agileBase experience by visiting &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/guides/guide2-personalisation/&#34;&gt;Guide 2 - Personalisation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information about:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Accessing &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/introduction/development-mode/&#34;&gt;Developer mode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/charting/built-in-charting/&#34;&gt;Built in Charting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guides: 1. Personalising our CRM</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/guides/guide2-personalisation/creating_personal_views/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/guides/guide2-personalisation/creating_personal_views/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning Aim:&lt;/strong&gt;  Understand the easy ways to alter an existing view&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prerequisites:&lt;/strong&gt; To be a competent user of agilebase, with Citizen Developer level 1 (or higher) enabled&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The guide is going to introduce to you some of the features that become available to you once you’ve been given the role of Citizen Developer. In essence, you now have the power to make small tweaks to the system that just affect yourself, helping you customise how it works and hopefully making it a more efficient and enjoyable process.
A good example would be making your own view of a list of organisations that is focused on the ones where you are the owner&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[guide 2 - video 1]
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/D_400LI_O_g&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;introducing-developer-mode&#34;&gt;Introducing Developer Mode&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Navigate to the view you wish to personalise
Then simply toggle the development mode icon that you’ll find top left of the page.
You can see some new icons on the user interface.
&lt;img src=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/view-edit-mode.png&#34; alt=&#34;Edit mode enabled - new icons now visible&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;adding-a-field&#34;&gt;Adding a field&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look at the far right of the table headers, there should now be a plus button.
If this is the first time you’ve tried to change the view then the system will tell you that it needs to make a copy just for you. Simply press the button to do this. The view will reload on screen and we can see the change in name indicating that it’s your version. You can now press the Plus button again…
From this window you can add other fields that may be of interest.
For example me, the date the record was created. This has the rather cumbersome name &amp;ldquo;Creation Time [Auto]&amp;rdquo;. Select it and press ‘Add’.
You are prompted to change the name or simply press Add to keep the original.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;moving-fields&#34;&gt;Moving Fields&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You change the order of the fields from the list of fields found under the Edit button.
Pressing  ‘Edit view’ at the top left to enter development mode. You should now see the list of all the fields and its as simple as dragging and dropping the fields in to the desired order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;removing-a-field&#34;&gt;Removing a Field&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To remove a field, you can either:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;click the small &amp;ldquo;X&amp;rdquo; icon on the right hand side of the list of fields.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;edit the individual field and press the &amp;ldquo;Remore from view button
Please be aware that some fields can NOT be removed. Don’t worry, you can’t cause any damage. The system simply alerts you that it can’t delete the field. In these cases you may want to simply move the field to the bottom of the list out of the way!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;adding-a-filter&#34;&gt;Adding a filter&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A useful filter to add in this example would be to only show Organisations that belong to myself.
Make sure you are in developer mode, oand start by clicking  ‘Edit view’ at the top left
Now click on the filters section.
To add the filter choose the field you wish to filter by, in this case ‘Owner’.
The type of filter depends on the situation, but in this case we’ll choose ‘contains’
And the value we need to enter is your name
Then we simply press ‘Add’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;renaming-a-view&#34;&gt;Renaming a view&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, make sure you are in developer mode, and start by clicking  ‘Edit view’ at the top left
Now click on &amp;ldquo;Properties and Options&amp;rdquo;
Simply enter your new title in the &amp;ldquo;view name&amp;rdquo; input box.
&lt;strong&gt;TIP&lt;/strong&gt; You can use a &amp;quot; - &amp;quot; to help organise how the views are diaplyed in the menu.
So it may make sense to rename this view to &amp;ldquo;Organisations - MY&amp;rdquo;, to have our view appear in the existing Organisations menu item.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;changing-the-default-view-of-a-tile&#34;&gt;Changing the Default View of a tile&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rather than having to swap to “my” view everytime I click in to the tile, it wuld be more efficient if changed the default to be My personal view.
On the front screen, click your avatar and choose tile settings.
Each of the tiles will now have a cog on it.
On the CRM tile we can click it and change our default view to be my personalised one.
From now on, when you click on the CRM tile it goes straight to the most useful view!&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guides: Guide 2 - Personalising our CRM</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/guides/guide2-personalisation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/guides/guide2-personalisation/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guides: 2. Personalising our CRM by adding charts</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/guides/guide2-personalisation/creating_personal_charts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/guides/guide2-personalisation/creating_personal_charts/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning Aim:&lt;/strong&gt;  Introducing building new charts&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prerequisites:&lt;/strong&gt; To be a competent user of agilebase, with Citizen Developer level 1 (or higher) enabled&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This short guide is going to introduce to you graphing features that becomes available to you once you’ve been given the role of Citizen Developer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[guide 2 - video 2]
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/wxbsluxCkCU&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;adding-a-chart&#34;&gt;Adding a Chart&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Navigate to the view containing the data for your chart&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a Citizen Developer level 1 you are able to add charts to your own views.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don’t need to be in developer mode, simply click the graph icon top right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/graph-button.png&#34; alt=&#34;Location of the graph button&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;setting-up-the-chart&#34;&gt;Setting up the chart&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Press ‘add chart or map’ and work your way through the steps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add data for the x-axis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For this example we can show the distribution in age of the Organisation records.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We can therefore choose Incorporation Date for the X axis, specifically &amp;lsquo;by Year&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For the Y-axis we want to know how many, which is a ‘Count’ of each Organisation record.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We can skip advanced settings and choose an appropriate Chart type. In this example ‘Packed Columns”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally we can change the name of the chart, and press save.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully a picture says a thousand words as we look at the graph!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information about graphs in agilebase please have a look at &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/charting/&#34;&gt;docs charting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Charting</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/charting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 11:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/charting/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;In Agilebase there are two mechanisms for charting and visualising data, each suited to a different purpose&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;our &lt;a href=&#34;built-in-charting&#34;&gt;built-in charting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;exporting data to third party business intelligence tools&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re starting out, we recommend beginning by looking at built-in charting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more advanced users, here&amp;rsquo;s a description of when each of the two options may be appropriate, with reasons why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;built-in-charting&#34;&gt;Built in charting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This should be the default starting point. It&amp;rsquo;s great for ad-hoc charting, i.e. to get quick answers to questions you may have about the data in the view you&amp;rsquo;re looking at.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creating charts can be used in conjunction with building views, in an agile fashion. For example, if you&amp;rsquo;re looking at a view of invoice and want to see a breakdown of totals for the year by customer type, but the customer type field isn&amp;rsquo;t in the view, no problem. Just&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;add the customer type field to the invoices view&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;create a chart to total up values by customer type&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developers can also choose to have certain charts emailed to different groups of people on a regular basis. For example, [TODO]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;exporting-to-business-intelligence&#34;&gt;Exporting to Business Intelligence&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any tool you wish such as Power BI or Tableau for example can be connected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This may be useful when&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You want to report summary KPIs or trends upwards, to higher levels of management, so you need a dashboard
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to include charts from different views in Agilebase in one place&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to present them in particular formats suitable for reporting, e.g. in particular sizes/layouts or using company colours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;potentially to include data from additional sources in the one dashboard e.g. from accounting systems as well&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The source data views in Agilebase are mature and aren&amp;rsquo;t likely to change. Changes can break any integration set up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You are happy with the privacy and data security implications - see below&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;privacy-and-data-security&#34;&gt;Privacy and data security&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When connecting a Business Intelligence tool, it&amp;rsquo;s important to realise that data &lt;em&gt;leaves Agilebase&lt;/em&gt; and therefore is no longer protected by Agilebase&amp;rsquo;s roles and privileges system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may have data in Agilebase which is only accessible to certain members of staff, however when accessed outside of Agilebase, those rules no longer apply. That doesn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily mean the data is accessible publicly, but it does mean it&amp;rsquo;s controlled by whatever privilege system the third party tool uses, which will be different to Agilebase&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, from Agilebase&amp;rsquo;s point of view, similar rules will apply when connecting a BI system as to when exporting data to spreadsheets. For example&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any user connecting a BI tool will be shown a warning of these consequences, which they&amp;rsquo;ll need to accept prior to going ahead&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Agilebase system administrators will get email notifications every time data in a view is made available to BI tools, containing information on whether that data is marked as sensitive or private&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only people with DEVELOP privileges on a table can connect BI tools. They also have to have two factor authentication enabled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Built In Charting</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/charting/built-in-charting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/charting/built-in-charting/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Charting is not strictly an administrator function, as any user can create charts and other data visualisations, such as maps and word clouds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, it&amp;rsquo;s useful for administrators to know how the system works in outline, so they can support users and also because creating charts may be a key part of building an application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Agilebase, charts &amp;lsquo;belong to&amp;rsquo; a view. Each view can have a collection of charts. Users can toggle between viewing data rows and looking at charts based on those rows. When a user filters data using the quick filter boxes at the top of the screen, the data or charts (whichever is shown) will update to match the filtered results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;creating-a-chart&#34;&gt;Creating a chart&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the tiles interface, open the tile and view to use as a source of chart data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click the charts button at the top right of the screen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click the &lt;em&gt;add/edit chart or map&lt;/em&gt; button&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Follow each of the steps (1 - 3) on screen to build the chart&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the last step, give a name to the chart and press &lt;em&gt;save&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When choosing a type of chart in step 3, small previews will be displayed based on some of the chart data. However some chart types may display a message rather than a preview. In this case, the chart data selected in step 1 is not applicable for this chart type.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, if in step 1 we have a count of items per year:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/chart-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Chart - step 1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;then the scatter diagram will work but the bubble chart won&amp;rsquo;t. For the bubble chart, &lt;strong&gt;two&lt;/strong&gt; y-axis measurements are required, one to specify the position of the bubble on the y-axis, plus another to determine the relative size of the bubble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/chart-bubble.png&#34; alt=&#34;Chart - step 3&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;embedding-charts-in-forms&#34;&gt;Embedding charts in forms&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Charts can be embedded into tables. When the user opens a record, the chart will automatically filter to show data pertaining to that record only.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So for example if you have a chart of sales per month per customer, which you embed into a customer table, it will show as sales per month, only for the customer on screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is accomplished by using a view with chart(s) as a &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-types/special-field-types/referenced-data/&#34;&gt;referenced data field&lt;/a&gt; - see that page for setup information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;embedding-charts-in-tabs&#34;&gt;Embedding charts in tabs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a tab contains many &amp;lsquo;child&amp;rsquo; records, e.g. an organisation may have a tab which contains financial data for the past 10 years, then charts can display above the rows of data when the tab&amp;rsquo;s opened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To accomplish this, simply add a chart to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/hierarchy-navigation/tabs/#tab-view&#34;&gt;view used by the tab&lt;/a&gt;. When the tab is opened, the chart will automatically be filtered to only show data pertaining to the parent table, in a similar fashion to how charts embedded using cross-referenced panels are filtered, as above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/endole-example.png&#34; alt=&#34;Endole example&#34; title=&#34;Example of a chart in a tab&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;subscribing-users-or-roles-to-charts&#34;&gt;Subscribing users or roles to charts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users can be subscribed to charts (or subscribe themselves) to receive them by email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In a view with some charts, open the charts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next to &amp;lsquo;Send these charts to me&amp;rsquo;, select a frequency, e.g. monthly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Under &amp;lsquo;Include data too&amp;rsquo;, select tabular data to include in the email too - various options will be displayed e.g. all new rows since the last email&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next to &amp;lsquo;roles&amp;rsquo;, select a role to send the charts and data to. All users in the role will be subscribed. Multiple roles can be added&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the view has no charts, this function can be used to send tabular data only&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Filters</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/views/filters/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/views/filters/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Filters can be applied permanently to a view, allowing an administrator to specify the subset of records that should be displayed. This is often for convenience and to create more useful systems. For example, if you have a database of suppliers, you may want to create views showing those which are approved, those which aren&amp;rsquo;t, those which are local etc. Each view would have a different set of filters applied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember people can apply additional &amp;lsquo;ad-hoc&amp;rsquo; or temporary filters to a view at any time using the filter boxes at the top of the screen, so it may not be necessary to create filtered views for every eventuality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A filter can act on any field or calculation in the view, as well as on any in joined tables or views.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Multiple filters act like they have AND between them, i.e. they are applied additively. If you wish to apply a filters with OR between them, or if you wish to apply a filter on the reult of the comparison of fields, then simply create the relevant &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/views/calculations/&#34;&gt;calculation&lt;/a&gt;. For example, if you added two filters to a suppliers view&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;status equals approved&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;status equals pending&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;then you would get no records showing - a status can&amp;rsquo;t be both one thing and another. However if you created a boolean calculation &amp;lsquo;pending or approved&amp;rsquo;, with definition&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;{status} like &#39;approved&#39; or {status} like &#39;pending&#39;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;you could then add a filter on that calculation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pending or approved equals true&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;adding-a-filter&#34;&gt;Adding a filter&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open the view you want to edit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Toggle development mode on and click the big pencil at the top left of the screen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Under &lt;em&gt;filters&lt;/em&gt;, choose a type, give it a name and press &lt;em&gt;Add&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are 26 types of filter to choose from, from the simple &amp;rsquo;equals&amp;rsquo; and &amp;rsquo;not equal to&amp;rsquo;, to more complex pattern matching using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.postgresql.org/docs/current/functions-matching.html#FUNCTIONS-POSIX-REGEXP&#34;&gt;regular expressions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some filters apply to multiple data types, others only to specific types. For example, &amp;rsquo;newer than X days ago&amp;rsquo; only applies to date fields.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you&amp;rsquo;ve added a filter, you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to type in a description for it. If no description is entered, the system will automatically generate one, which you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This description is shown to users as help in particular circumstances, e.g. when the view is used as a &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/workflows/send-chaser/&#34;&gt;chaser&lt;/a&gt;, so it&amp;rsquo;s a good idea to check it makes sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;including-blank-values&#34;&gt;Including blank values&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once a filter has been created, when you hover over it you&amp;rsquo;ll see an option to tick &amp;lsquo;or is blank&amp;rsquo;. This is useful to ensure blank values aren&amp;rsquo;t excluded by your filter, which they typically would be otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, imaging you&amp;rsquo;re setting up an &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/workflows/send-email/&#34;&gt;email notification workflow&lt;/a&gt; to send a notification to people once a week of any outstanding tasks. You&amp;rsquo;d likely need two filters, the first to find any tasks with an &amp;lsquo;outstanding&amp;rsquo; status and the second to only include tasks for which no notifications have been sent within the last 7 days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For that second filter, you would set it up as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&#39;last notified&#39; is more than 7 days ago
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, as it stands, that would exclude any tasks which have &lt;strong&gt;never&lt;/strong&gt; had a notification sent for them, i.e. where the last notified field is blank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To include those, just tick &amp;lsquo;or is blank&amp;rsquo; after creating the filter.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
