<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Agilebase docs – Software Architect</title>
    <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/tags/software-architect/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Software Architect on Agilebase docs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 13:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/tags/software-architect/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Security Features</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;In these pages you can find details of how to set up users, roles, and privileges in Agilebase. Agilebase has an extensive role-based permissions system that enables fine-grained permissions and roles to be used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tables of data can also be marked as containing &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/sensitive-data/&#34;&gt;commercially sensitive or personal data&lt;/a&gt;, relevant to GDPR and affecting application behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guides: Guide 1 - Build a CRM</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/guides/guide1-crm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/guides/guide1-crm/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Security and Compliance</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Agilebase often works best when end users become part of the development process, so they&amp;rsquo;re able to give feedback as your software builds up, also gaining confidence in the end result. So it&amp;rsquo;s quite likely that you&amp;rsquo;ll be adding user accounts relatively early in the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a good idea to adopt security best practices from the start rather than trying to retro-fit. This guide will take you through the mechanics of creating &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/users/&#34;&gt;User Accounts&lt;/a&gt; but also explain the steps you can take to ensure data is suitably protected.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Users</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/users/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/users/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2 id=&#34;adding-a-user&#34;&gt;Adding a user&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can add a new user from scratch, or clone an existing one. To add:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to the homepage and &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/introduction/development-mode/&#34;&gt;toggle development mode on&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click the &amp;lsquo;+ USER&amp;rsquo; button under Lists at the top of the screen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To clone:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to the homepage and &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/introduction/development-mode/&#34;&gt;toggle development mode on&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click the Users box at the top right to load a list of existing users&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click a user to clone to open up their editing panel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At the bottom, press the Clone button&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a cost is to be applied, this will be shown to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should now see an editing screen with the details of the user you just created.
![Add user][/add-user.png]
&lt;img src=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/new-user-details.png&#34; alt=&#34;User editing&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can enter the user&amp;rsquo;s name and username. If the username isn&amp;rsquo;t their email address, enter their email address in the field provided too. This is useful&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to allow them to reset their own password by receiving a link by email&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to allow them to receive notifications when another user adds a comment against a record&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;as various features allow a user to be assigned to a record. Workflows can be set up to email those users. E.g. if an account manager is assigned to a customer, you may want to email them when a complaint is received from that customer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;passwords&#34;&gt;Passwords&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The recommended way to set passwords is for the user to choose their own, which they can do once they have a username and email address filled in. They will need to visit the login page, click the &amp;lsquo;reset password&amp;rsquo; link and type in their username. They will be emailed a link which will let them set a password.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an administrator, you can also manually reset someone&amp;rsquo;s password by clicking &amp;lsquo;change password&amp;rsquo; in their user details screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We recommend the adoption of a password wallet service like &lt;a href=&#34;https://1password.com/&#34;&gt;1Password&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://lastpass.com&#34;&gt;LastPass&lt;/a&gt; or built-in browser features to generate and store passwords. That lets passwords become much more secure and harder to guess whilst not requiring users to remember them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;notes-about-password-security&#34;&gt;Notes about password security&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Passwords must be a minimum of 8 characters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When someone sets or changes their password, it&amp;rsquo;s checked against &lt;a href=&#34;https://haveibeenpwned.com/Passwords&#34;&gt;https://haveibeenpwned.com/Passwords&lt;/a&gt; to ensure it&amp;rsquo;s not a common one and is suitable for ongoing use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Passwords are stored in our system &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.okta.com/blog/2019/03/what-are-salted-passwords-and-password-hashing/&#34;&gt;salted and hashed&lt;/a&gt; using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bcrypt&#34;&gt;bcrypt&lt;/a&gt; scheme, with 13 rounds. This means that we do not know what your passwords are and in the unfortunate event of our passwords database being hacked, the original passwords would still not be able to be retrieved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;two-factor-authentication&#34;&gt;Two factor authentication&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users are strongly encouraged to set up two factor authentication (2FA) using an app. Unfortunately this is one step an administrator can&amp;rsquo;t do for them, but luckily it is quick and easy to do: &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/users/2fa-setup/&#34;&gt;here&amp;rsquo;s how&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users without 2FA will be prompted to do so in the user interface and by email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2FA is mandatory for &lt;a href=&#34;#roles&#34;&gt;administrators&lt;/a&gt; and necessary for a user to have before &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/privileges/&#34;&gt;develop&lt;/a&gt; privileges can be assigned to them. Users also need to have 2FA enabled in order to perform certain functions such as exporting to spreadsheet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When enabled, a user will be prompted for the 2FA code as well as their password when they log in from a device or location they haven&amp;rsquo;t used in the past 30 days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a user encounters any problems with 2FA, e.g. they lose the device for generating their codes, you can temporarily disable 2FA on their account by going to their user details screen and un-ticking &amp;lsquo;use 2FA&amp;rsquo;. Of course, you need to be aware of the risks, for example double checking that a user who contacts you is really who they say they are. Once they can log in, they&amp;rsquo;ll be able to enable 2FA themselves again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;mandating-2fa-for-everyone&#34;&gt;Mandating 2FA for everyone&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This can be done in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/advanced-usage/company-settings/#mandate-2fa&#34;&gt;company settings&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;other-options&#34;&gt;Other options&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;learner-progression-level&#34;&gt;Learner Progression Level&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When created, the level defaults to being a &amp;lsquo;core user&amp;rsquo;, i.e. a standard user who has no special development privileges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A software architect can change this to move any user up (or down) in learner development progress. Please see &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/introduction/learner-progression/&#34;&gt;learner progression&lt;/a&gt; for more information on what abilities each level confers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;use-the-custom-agilechilli-ui-rather-than-agilebases&#34;&gt;Use the custom AgileChilli UI rather than Agilebase&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s possible for companies to apply their logo and custom login screen to the system. Please contact us if you&amp;rsquo;d like to set this up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;logout-after&#34;&gt;Logout after&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Automatically end the user&amp;rsquo;s session after this many minutes of inactivity. The user themselves can also change this setting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;restrict-data-access&#34;&gt;Restrict data access&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, you can specify a field name, either an equals or a contains filter and a value. The button &lt;em&gt;set to user ID&lt;/em&gt; will set the value to the user&amp;rsquo;s ID.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this is to limit the data rows a particular user sees in a view. If a field with the name you specify appears in a view, a filter will be automatically applied so the user only sees rows which match the filter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, if you set &lt;code&gt;created by [auto] = Oliver Kohll (oliver@agilechilli.com)&lt;/code&gt;, then (assuming &lt;code&gt;Oliver Kohll (oliver@agilechilli.com)&lt;/code&gt; is their username), the user will only see records they created, as long as the &amp;lsquo;created by [auto]&amp;rsquo; field appears in the view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A similar feature exists to add filters to roles - useful when you may want to apply the same filter to multiple users. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/roles/#multi-tenanting&#34;&gt;roles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;roles&#34;&gt;Roles&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tick a role to assign the user to it. The primary purpose of roles is to apply privileges to groups of users, see &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/roles/&#34;&gt;roles&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s one special role which can be assigned. It will be marked &lt;strong&gt;grants administrative privileges&lt;/strong&gt;. Assigning that role will make a user an administrator, with full permissions over the complete system. They can create/remove users, roles, tables etc., as well as assign themselves privileges on any table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next to each role listed is a list of tiles that will be added to their screen if that role is assigned to them. This is a convenience feature to speed up setting up their home screen. The tiles shown for a role are those which more than half of the members of that role have. Tiles can be manually added and removed by an [administrator] or the user themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If any role is a &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/roles/#multi-tenanting&#34;&gt;filtering role&lt;/a&gt;, the filter applied is also displayed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;privileges&#34;&gt;Privileges&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assign individual table &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/privileges/&#34;&gt;privileges&lt;/a&gt; to a user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When dealing with larger numbers of users it&amp;rsquo;s usually more manageable if you use roles to assign privileges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a user has a privilege due to being a member of a role, that privilege is shown with a shaded blue background. Any additional privileges individually assigned to them are shown in green.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;tiles&#34;&gt;Tiles&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Allows an admin to add/remove &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tiles/&#34;&gt;tiles&lt;/a&gt; for a user. By default users can add/remove tiles themselves too, although this can be disabled through the use of a &lt;a href=&#34;#other-options&#34;&gt;custom UI&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;viewing-users&#34;&gt;Viewing users&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the homepage, &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/introduction/development-mode/&#34;&gt;toggle development mode on&lt;/a&gt; and click the &amp;lsquo;users&amp;rsquo; box at the top right. You&amp;rsquo;ll see a list of existing user accounts. Their details are listed including 2FA status (whether they&amp;rsquo;re using app-based 2FA or not) and when they last logged in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each user&amp;rsquo;s roles are shown. Any &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/roles/#multi-tenanting&#34;&gt;multi-tenanting&lt;/a&gt; roles are also included.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The list of users can be exported to spreadsheet by clicking again on the &amp;lsquo;users&amp;rsquo; box at the top right of the screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that if you want to see a full audit trail of what each user has done (editing, searching, exporting etc.), then you can use the optional &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/usage-monitoring/usage-reporting/#enhanced-audit-trail&#34;&gt;enhanced audit trail&lt;/a&gt; feature (only available on certain plans).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;removing-users&#34;&gt;Removing users&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To remove a user, click one in the list (see above) to open the user editing panel. At the bottom, click the Remove button.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A user removal will have no effect on any data stored in the system. The user&amp;rsquo;s previous comments will still be visible for example and their username will still be logged against any records they&amp;rsquo;re marked as owner of. Their changes will still be in the audit trail and they will be marked as the creator/last editor of records where relevant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may want to take some other actions after deletion e.g. to re-assign records they are assigned to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A deleted user&amp;rsquo;s profile image will be replaced with a standard icon representing a deleted user, when displayed in comment streams etc.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Community Users</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/users/community-users/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 12:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/users/community-users/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Agilebase is primarily a platform for building back office systems for employees (or members of the organisation) to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, it&amp;rsquo;s common to allow access to people outside the organisation to perform limited data entry tasks. For example, you may wish your suppliers to be able to upload certificates of conformances to items they sell you, or you may have a large workforce of contractors who you require to fill in timesheets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It may be that you don&amp;rsquo;t wish to supply each person a full Agilebase license because&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;there will be a large number of them, so there&amp;rsquo;ll be management and cost issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;you wish to restrict what they can do in the system further than can be accomplished with roles and privileges&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Community Users mechanism allows this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Community Users have limited access (described below), with subscriptions which are significantly less costly and must be purchased in bulk. Once a block of community users is purchased, you can set up and remove as many as you need within the upper limit of that block.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;validity&#34;&gt;Validity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a Community User subscription to apply, a person must be one of&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a &lt;em&gt;supplier&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a &lt;em&gt;contractor&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;an &lt;em&gt;app&lt;/em&gt; user i.e. someone who utilises Agilebase functions via the API, using a third party app or website&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;or a &lt;em&gt;member of the public&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;setup&#34;&gt;Setup&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;configuring-a-community-of-users&#34;&gt;Configuring a community of users&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To set up a new community of a certain type, a role must be created for them. The role privileges will determine which tables they have access to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each community user must be a member of that single role only - no additional roles or privileges can be applied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Different communities of users can be created by creating different roles. A separate block of subscriptions must be purchased for each role created. Therefore you can have multiple communities, for example one for members of the public and another for contractors, or two different types of contractor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When setting up the role, tick the &amp;lsquo;members are community users&amp;rsquo; tickbox. Then create a user and assign them to that role.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;functional-restrictions&#34;&gt;Functional Restrictions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following restrictions appropriate to users of an outside community are applied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a community users role can be set to allow VIEW access to up to 10 tables, plus EDIT privileges on up to 3 additional tables&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;for the 3 tables which allow editing, community users can only see and edit records they themselves have created. All records from read-only tables can be seen.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;for example, a user may have read-only access to a list of companies. Against each company, they can add and edit timesheet records&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;community users only see comments added by themselves or specifically sent to them (comments are commonly used for internal company discussions)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a community user can have up to 6 tiles on their homepage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the homepage is fixed for community users, they can&amp;rsquo;t add or remove tiles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further, community users are unable to&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;export data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;create charts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;unlock locked fields or records&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bulk edit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together, all of these measures will help protect data in the organisation whilst simplifying the user interface, allowing people from outside to be able to usefully carry out work, without having to go through the expense of creating or purchasing dedicated applications for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Policies</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/policies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/policies/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2 id=&#34;backups&#34;&gt;Backups&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data backups are performed across the stack of technology, from server down to databases and file storage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Database backups are taken daily and hosted in the European Union by Amazon. Older backups transition to &lt;a href=&#34;https://aws.amazon.com/glacier/&#34;&gt;Amazon Glacier&lt;/a&gt; and are kept for 200 days - this allows a balance between the practical necessity of allowing rollbacks to a certain point in time, whilst not storing data for an unnecessarily long period, to comply with the GDPR.
By policy, backups under 100 days old are read-only and un-deletable, so will always be available in the case of attacks like ransomware.
These backups are also encrypted so that Amazon has no access to the data within then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.postgresql.org/docs/current/warm-standby.html&#34;&gt;Continuous archiving &lt;/a&gt; of the database is also enabled, to transfer data to a &amp;lsquo;hot standby&amp;rsquo; server using streaming replication, allowing immediate failover should the primary database fail for any reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agilebase content (uploaded files, custom templates etc.) also have snapshots taken daily, kept for 200 days in a separate EU location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to these content-only backups, snapshots of the totality of each key server in the infrastructure (including configuration), are run daily using the Linode backup service &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linode.com/products/backups/&#34;&gt;https://www.linode.com/products/backups/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The backup and recovery process is monitored and tested regularly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;retrieval&#34;&gt;Retrieval&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There may be a charge for retrieval of customer data from backup, to cover our costs. The data will be restored to a separate instance of Agilebase available at a different URL, which a customer can look at to compare data. If necessary, data can then be extracted from one and loaded into the other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please be aware that depending on needs, this may be a complex process due to the fact that other data in the live system may have changed since the backup. A simple overwrite of existing data may not be the best option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;privacy-policy&#34;&gt;Privacy policy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agilebase Ltd is funded directly by the customers we provide services to, we do not have any other business model, particularly we do not resell any data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our privacy policy is available here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://agilechilli.com/help-centre/agilebase/privacy-policy/&#34;&gt;https://agilechilli.com/help-centre/agilebase/privacy-policy/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;gdpr-policy&#34;&gt;GDPR Policy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An overview of our GDPR policy is available &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/gdpr-overview.pdf&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/gdpr-overview.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/gdpr-compliance-cycle.png&#34; alt=&#34;GDPR Compliance Cycle&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;data-protection-and-disaster-recovery&#34;&gt;Data Protection and Disaster Recovery&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Full details of our processes and plans are available to customers and relevant parties on request.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Roles</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/roles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/roles/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The primary purpose of roles is to apply privileges to groups of users, rather than applying them individually. That makes managing large numbers of users easier and also more secure as it&amp;rsquo;s easy to see which privileges each type of user has and which they don&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roles have some other important uses, such as multi-tenanting, described below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;creating-a-role&#34;&gt;Creating a role&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to the homepage and toggle development mode on
42 Click the &amp;lsquo;+ ROLE&amp;rsquo; button at the top right of the screen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/add-role.png&#34; alt=&#34;Add Role&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should now see an editing screen with the details of the role you just created. You can give it a name and there are a few options:
&lt;img src=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/new-role-details.png&#34; alt=&#34;Role details&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Allow Export&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Referrs to exporting to spreadsheet - see &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/integrations/exporting-to-spreadsheet/&#34;&gt;spreadsheet exports&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Allow global editing&lt;/strong&gt;
Users with &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/privileges/&#34;&gt;edit privileges&lt;/a&gt; on a particular table, when added to this role, will be able to perform global edits on the data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To perform a global edit, the user should&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;filter the view (by typing into the filter boxes at the top of each column) to narrow down the rows to those which should be edited&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;double click on a column header in a view, to edit the data in that field. The field must be from the view&amp;rsquo;s parent table.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;click the &amp;rsquo;edit filtered&amp;rsquo; button which appears&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;type in the value you want to apply and follow through the prompts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;User Visibility&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Allow only multi-tenanting views to be seen&lt;/strong&gt;
Used to configure &lt;a href=&#34;#multi-tenanting&#34;&gt;multi-tenanting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;members&#34;&gt;Members&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tick each user to add them to the role. Users will gain all the privileges defined by the role.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;privileges&#34;&gt;Privileges&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Select the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/privileges/&#34;&gt;table privileges&lt;/a&gt; which will apply to members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Privileges are additive - if a user is a member of multiple roles, they gain all the privileges from each of those roles added together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;multi-tenanting&#34;&gt;Multi-tenanting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Multi-tenanting is the ability to separate users into groups who can’t see each other’s data. This can be used for example to allow different sets of companies, clubs, or membership groups (or whatever the organisational group is) to use the same system features whilst remaining separate from each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Multi-tenanting is a powerful feature that can be used not just for customers to segragate data amongst their users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Partners can also use this facility if building software to widely market. In that case, each customer they sign up can very quickly be set up with their own private dataset, whilst the partner retains the ability to add features which will automatically apply to everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To set up multi-tenanting:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;first &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/&#34;&gt;add a text field&lt;/a&gt; to all tables in the system for which you want data to be segragated. The field must be named the same in every table, for example&amp;rsquo;s sake here let&amp;rsquo;s assume it&amp;rsquo;s called &amp;lsquo;account name&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Then create one role for each set of users who you want to segregate. We&amp;rsquo;ll assume there&amp;rsquo;s one called &amp;lsquo;Customer A&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the role details screen for the Customer A role, tick &lt;em&gt;user visibility&lt;/em&gt;. That means that users in this role won&amp;rsquo;t see users in other roles with the same option ticked. In other words, users from Customer A won&amp;rsquo;t be able to select Customer B or Customer C users when doing things like adding comments or assigning users to records.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Under &lt;em&gt;restrict data access&lt;/em&gt; in the role details, enter &lt;code&gt;account name = Customer A&lt;/code&gt;, i.e. &lt;em&gt;Filter Field Name&lt;/em&gt; = &amp;lsquo;account name&amp;rsquo;, &lt;em&gt;Filter Value&lt;/em&gt; = &amp;lsquo;Customer A&amp;rsquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, ensure the account name field is present in all views based on the table. When creating a view, any fields used for multi-tenanting will automatically be added but you may need to retro-fit any existing views.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has two effects -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When a user assigned to the Customer A role creates a new record in one of the multi-tenanting tables, the account name field will automatically be populated with the value Customer A (as entered under &lt;em&gt;restrict data access&lt;/em&gt;). The field will be invisible to them - they won&amp;rsquo;t be able to see or edit the value.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When looking at records in a view, a filter will be automatically applied so the user only sees records where account name = Customer A.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users who &lt;strong&gt;aren&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/strong&gt; a member of the role will see the account name field in the data editing form and in views. This can be useful for allowing e.g. group managers to see all data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If any multi-tenanting roles are set up, then views which &lt;strong&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/strong&gt; contain a multi-tenanting field will be marked in red in the administration interface, as a warning. If a multi-tenanting user loads one of these views, they will see all records. Typically, practically all views will need the multi-tenanting field to be present.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;allow-only-multi-tenanting-views-to-be-seen&#34;&gt;Allow only multi-tenanting views to be seen&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Optionally, this can be ticked. If ticked, user&amp;rsquo;s will only be shown views which contain the multi-tenanting field, &amp;lsquo;Account Name&amp;rsquo; in the example above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an added protection - if the multi-tenanting field is removed from a view, the user won&amp;rsquo;t see it any more. Otherwise they&amp;rsquo;d be able to see all data in the view, even that which they shouldn&amp;rsquo;t. This can also be useful to set when there is partial multi-tenanting set up, i.e. some views are multi-tenanted but others aren&amp;rsquo;t and you only want certain groups (e.g. people outside the organisation) to see the multi-tenanted parts, not everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;complex-multi-tenanting&#34;&gt;Complex multi-tenanting&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;multi-level&#34;&gt;Multi-level&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users may be a member of more than one multi-tenanting role. For example you may use two multi-tenanting fields/roles, one for a company and another for a division. Members of a company role will be able to see data from all divisions in their company and members of both a company and a division role will only be able to see data for a single division.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;multi-account-via-multiple-roles&#34;&gt;Multi-account (via multiple roles)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s also possible for a user to be a member of multiple roles, all of which are set to multi-tenant on the same field, with different values. E.g. if a user is a member of Company A and Company B roles as in our example above, they will see data from those two companies when viewing records, but not Company C.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This works best when the user has read-only privileges on the data, e.g. for a manager reporting on those two companies. They can view records but not add new records, as the system is unable to determine the value of the account name field to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;multi-account-via-_contains_-filtering&#34;&gt;Multi-account (via &lt;em&gt;contains&lt;/em&gt; filtering)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s also possible to define a role filter under &lt;em&gt;restrict data access&lt;/em&gt; with a &amp;lsquo;contains&amp;rsquo; rather than an &amp;lsquo;=&amp;rsquo; filter. You can then use a naming convension for your account name values to allow members of this role to see multiple accounts. As above, users of this role will need to be read-only on the data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;api-setup&#34;&gt;API setup&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a multi-tenanting account, it&amp;rsquo;s possible to create new tenants, with users, by API, as opposed to the manual actions of an administrator. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/integrations/creating-user-accounts/&#34;&gt;Creating user accounts with the API&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;role-properties&#34;&gt;Role properties&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;brand-name-and-domain&#34;&gt;Brand name and domain&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These two options allow system emails (password reset notification etc.) to come from a domain name of your choice and be branded with a particular &amp;lsquo;app&amp;rsquo; name. This can be useful if you&amp;rsquo;re creating a public-facing app using Agilebase, rather than applications for your own staff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To allow the domain name to work, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to contact us to set it up - our server will need to be authorised to send email from your domain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;custom-menus&#34;&gt;Custom menus&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s possible to add custom menu items into the user menu (the one at the top right that appears if you click your user icon). That means if your company has specific help pages or process documentation relevant to your organisation or application, you can make them available from within Agilebase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each custom menu has a title, description and URL, which will be opened in a new tab when the menu item’s chosen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply add these into the &lt;strong&gt;menu title&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;menu description&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;menu URL&lt;/strong&gt; properties of a role. Assigning that role to a user will add the menu item to their profile menu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To add multiple menu items to a user or users, assign multiple roles, each with one menu item defined.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Privileges</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/privileges/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/privileges/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;In Agilebase, there are three privilege levels, as well as a special &amp;lsquo;develop&amp;rsquo; privilege.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The three privileges take effect per table, i.e. a user/role can have certain privileges on one table and different ones on another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Privileges are additive - if a user is a member of multiple roles, they gain all the privileges from each of those roles added together, plus any they may have individually assigned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;privilege-levels&#34;&gt;Privilege levels&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;View&lt;/strong&gt;: ability to see data in a table&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edit&lt;/strong&gt;: ability to create, edit and delete data in a table (create and delete subject to various table options)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Develop&lt;/strong&gt;: the privilege that allows you to use the &amp;lsquo;application building&amp;rsquo; features of Agilebase, relating to a table. Namely the ability to
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;modify the structure, i.e. create/delete fields, tabs, change options etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;create, edit and delete views from the table, including creating charts, maps and word clouds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;upload or create printout templates for views&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;view usage statistics about a table&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Develop also allows some extended user features
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;delete any user&amp;rsquo;s comments from a table&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;unlock locked records to allow editing (one at a time)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;override table options which would normally disallow adding/removing records from a table&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;override options which would normally disallow exporting data to a spreadsheet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;import data from spreadsheet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;override options which would normally disallow global editing of data in the table&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Privilege levels work in conjunction with &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/introduction/learner-progression/&#34;&gt;Learner Progression levels&lt;/a&gt;, for example, only someone at level Citizen Developer level 3 can have Develop privileges assigned to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two Factor Authentication is required for any user with any Citizen Developer or Software Architect role.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;assigning-table-privileges&#34;&gt;Assigning table privileges&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Table privileges can be assigned to one or more users or roles from that table&amp;rsquo;s editing screen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From a user or role editing screen, privileges on one or more tables can be assigned&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two methods are equivalent, whichever is the most convenient for a given purpose can be used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Managing privileges by role rather than by individual user is recommended. That makes managing large numbers of users easier and also more secure as it&amp;rsquo;s easy to see which privileges each type of user has and which they don&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To assign one or more role or user privileges to a table:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/adding-and-removing/#editing-a-table&#34;&gt;Edit a table&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open the &lt;em&gt;roles and privileges&lt;/em&gt; panel, then select or un-select any privileges required&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To assign one or more table privileges to a particular role or user:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On the homepage, toggle on development mode&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click &lt;em&gt;roles&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;users&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select the role or user to assign privileges to, then select or un-select any privileges required&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;related-to-privileges&#34;&gt;Related to privileges&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Database systems often have the concept of row level privileges. The equivalent in Agilebase is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/roles/#multi-tenanting&#34;&gt;multi-tenanting&lt;/a&gt; system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Individual fields in a table can be locked or hidden, see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-options/common-options/#show-if-record-in-view&#34;&gt;field options&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Exporting</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/exporting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/exporting/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Exporting to spreadsheet is only one way of getting data out of Agilebase, but it is the most commonly used amongst everyday users. For less ad-hoc data transfers, such as integrations with third party systems involving incoming and/or outgoing data, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/integrations/&#34;&gt;API&lt;/a&gt; can be used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;allowing-exports&#34;&gt;Allowing exports&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order for a user to be allowed to export to spreadsheet, a number of critieria have to be matched, to suitably protect your organisation&amp;rsquo;s data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The user must have &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/users/#two-factor-authentication&#34;&gt;Two Factor Authentication&lt;/a&gt; enabled&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The view to export from must have exporting enabled (it&amp;rsquo;s enabled by default). To do this
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/introduction/development-mode/&#34;&gt;edit the view&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;under &lt;em&gt;properties and options&lt;/em&gt;, tick &lt;em&gt;allow exports&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The user must also be a member of a &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/roles/&#34;&gt;role&lt;/a&gt; that allows exporting (disabled by default). To allow exporting for a role,
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;on the homepage, toggle &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/introduction/development-mode/&#34;&gt;development mode&lt;/a&gt; on&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;click &lt;em&gt;roles&lt;/em&gt; and select the role you want&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tick &lt;em&gt;allow exports&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A user with &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/privileges/&#34;&gt;develop privileges&lt;/a&gt; on the view&amp;rsquo;s parent table can bypass criteria 2 and 3. This privilege is not commonly applied to normal users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;exporting&#34;&gt;Exporting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A user with the ability to export can do so by opening the view, clicking the export icon near the top right and selecting &lt;em&gt;export&lt;/em&gt; from the options in the menu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/export.png&#34; alt=&#34;exporting&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the user &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/views/filters/&#34;&gt;filters&lt;/a&gt; the data on screen before doing this, only the filtered data will be exported.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The resulting spreadsheet will be in Microsoft Excel format. The first sheet will be some metadata about the export, such as a timestamp, the name of the exporter and any filters applied. The second sheet will be the actual data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Column A in the data sheet holds the internal row ID of each record. This is useful for matching purposes if you&amp;rsquo;re going to be modifying then re-importing the data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;charts&#34;&gt;Charts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the view has &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/charting/&#34;&gt;charts&lt;/a&gt; attached, one sheet per chart will also be included in the spreadsheet. The contents will be the chart data, not the chart visualisation itself, but the visualisation can easily be re-created in the spreadsheet from the data if necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;limits-and-notifications&#34;&gt;Limits and notifications&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An administrator can log whether each table contains commercially sensitive data (ticked by default) and/or personal data (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://gdpr-info.eu/art-4-gdpr/)&#34;&gt;https://gdpr-info.eu/art-4-gdpr/)&lt;/a&gt;. If either of these options is ticked for a view&amp;rsquo;s parent table, you’ll have additional options for&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;notifying all administrators if an export of more than a certain number of rows is done&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;setting a hard limit to completely disallow exports of more than a certain number of rows&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To configure these options, see &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/options/&#34;&gt;tables&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may also want to set an export prompt message to show people when they request an export, to remind people of their data protection obligations under the GDPR for example. This can be done in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/advanced-usage/company-settings/#export-message&#34;&gt;company settings&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Reporting</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/usage-monitoring/usage-reporting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/usage-monitoring/usage-reporting/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Log data reporting provides a rich view of system usage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;enhanced-audit-trail&#34;&gt;Enhanced audit trail&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For organisations who have activated the enhanced audit trail, all logs are stored in user-accessible tables which are just like any other tables in the system, the only difference being the data is read only. This means an administrator can use the full power of the built in Agilebase reporting features, to create views, add calculations, charts etc., even export via the API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So for example, you could analyse how many changes were made per month by each user, count the volume of logins from various locations or see what the most common fields are to search on. All actions listed on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/usage-monitoring/&#34;&gt;usage monitoring&lt;/a&gt; page are available to query.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data is also retained for an extended period, see &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/usage-monitoring/#retention-periods&#34;&gt;retention periods&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If interested in activating this feature, please &lt;a href=&#34;https://agilechilli.com/contact-us/&#34;&gt;get in touch&lt;/a&gt;. There will be a small recurring charge added to your bill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;data-stored&#34;&gt;Data stored&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;logins&#34;&gt;Logins&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Username&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Date and time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IP Address&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Country&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Internet Service Provider organisation name and location&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Client web browser (both summary and exact version details)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Client operating system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;data-changes-record-creation--update--delete&#34;&gt;Data changes (record creation / update / delete)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Username (in the case of an API call, will be &amp;lsquo;Public API [IP address]&amp;rsquo;. In the case of a system workflow, &amp;lsquo;System&amp;rsquo;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Date and time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Action (e.g. update or delete)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Table&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Field (if a single field is updated)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Row ID - internal identifier of the record updated&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Saved data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;view-access&#34;&gt;View access&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This covers any time a view is opened or filtered, either by a user, or an API call&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Username (in the case of an API call, will be &amp;lsquo;Public API [IP address]&amp;rsquo;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Date and time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tile and view name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Details - any filters and row limit applied&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rows - the number of records returned to the user or API&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Processing time - the total server-side processing time in milliseconds needed to retrieve the data, and if for an API, transform it into JSON format&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Of which Q time &lt;strong&gt;(API calls only)&lt;/strong&gt; - to achieve a fair level of load balancing, Agilebase operates a separate API request queue for each customer. If a request arrives and the system is still busy processing a previous request, the new one gets held in a queue. This field shows how much of the total processing time, in ms was spent waiting for previous requests to complete&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bytes &lt;strong&gt;(API calls only)&lt;/strong&gt; - the number of bytes of JSON data returned via the API&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Count - if many similar requests or API calls (to a particular view) reach the server in quick succession, they will be amalgamated together into one log line. The count then shows the number of requests the log line refers to, otherwise it will be 1. If more than one, then the &lt;em&gt;rows&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;processing time&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;of which q time&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;bytes&lt;/em&gt; will represent the totals for all requests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;table-schema-changes&#34;&gt;Table schema changes&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are changes made to a table structure by someone with &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/privileges/&#34;&gt;develop&lt;/a&gt; privileges, such as adding or removing a field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Date and time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Username&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Table name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Action e.g. &amp;lsquo;add field&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;remove field&amp;rsquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Details - e.g. the name of the field&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;view-schema-changes&#34;&gt;View schema changes&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Changes made to a view structure, such as adding fields, filters, calculations or charts&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Date and time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Username&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tile and view name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Action&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Details - additional data related to the action, e.g. if adding a field, the field name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;authentication-changes&#34;&gt;Authentication changes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A log of administrative actions such as assigning a user to a role, assigning privileges, or user actions such as requesting a password reset&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Date and time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Username (of the user making the change)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Action - e.g. add privilege&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Table name - only if the action relates to a particular table, e.g. assigning a role to a table&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Details - additional data related to the action, e.g. if adding a role to the table, the role name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;standard-reporting&#34;&gt;Standard reporting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Built in reports are available in a number of areas, whether using the enhanced audit trail or standard logging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-dashboard&#34;&gt;The dashboard&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the tiles interface, click the bird icon at the top left, then select &lt;em&gt;usage dashboard&lt;/em&gt;. The dashboard contains system reports including usage data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;trends&#34;&gt;Trends&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An overall usage treemap is displayed at the top. Each view is a section of the screen. Large areas represent views that get a lot of use, smaller areas those that don’t. Colours give immediate feedback on whether usage has been increasing (blue) or decreasing (grey) this month. Hovering over an area shows more stats including the top users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Underneath that a series of sparkline charts show long term trends, across selected operational, tactical and strategic metrics, all geared to showing utilisation over a 12 month period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Raw data can be downloaded to spreadsheet using the links beneath each sparkline. Note only the most recent 200,000 records can be downloaded in this way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;capacity&#34;&gt;Capacity&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as actual usage, the dashboard shows total capacity i.e. how many users, records, tables etc. are present in the system, along with purchased capacity (if relevant). These elements affect billing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;workflows&#34;&gt;Workflows&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A convenience view of all workflows which carry out automated data modifications, see &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/workflows/&#34;&gt;workflows&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;database-graph&#34;&gt;Database graph&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, for background on what the data structure looks like and how tables are connected, the database graph shows relations between tables is visual form. This can provide a fuller understaning of the system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;table-and-view-usage&#34;&gt;Table and view usage&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A quick overview of who is viewing data is shown in the administration interface for both tables and views.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a table&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edit the table&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open the &lt;em&gt;Recent Changes&lt;/em&gt; panel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The report shows the number of times each user has viewed data from the table, per view. All views which contain any data from the table are included.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a view&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edit the view&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open to the &lt;em&gt;Recent Changes&lt;/em&gt; panel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similar data is show as for tables, but limited to the selected view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;individual-record-histories&#34;&gt;Individual record histories&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any user can see the complete history of changes to an individual record, up to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/usage-monitoring/#retention-periods&#34;&gt;retention period&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When editing a record, scroll to the bottom of the screen and click &lt;em&gt;history&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To view the precise time of a change, hover over a date.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Usage Monitoring</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/usage-monitoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/usage-monitoring/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Agilebase comprehensively logs changes to data in the system as well as changes to the structure of the system. Powerful &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/usage-monitoring/usage-reporting/&#34;&gt;reporting facilities&lt;/a&gt; allow the generation of audit trails, trend monitoring, customer success monitoring etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-logged&#34;&gt;What is logged&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;user-actions&#34;&gt;User actions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following actions are recorded&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;logins, including connection details&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;record edits (create, update and delete)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;global edits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;comment additions and removals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;data imports and exports&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;viewing and searching/filtering data in views&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;password resets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When logging a record deletion, the data values deleted are logged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further, for every record in a table, the following metadata is stored and can be included in views:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The creation time and time of last update&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The user who created the record and who last updated it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The view count: how many times the record has been opened&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A visual activity histogram showing the number of edits per week over the past six months&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-types/special-field-types/automatically-present-fields/&#34;&gt;automatically present fields&lt;/a&gt; for full details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;api-and-workflow-actions&#34;&gt;API and workflow actions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data changes or outflows arising from &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/integrations/&#34;&gt;API calls&lt;/a&gt;are logged to the same log store as user actions. Instead of logging the user taking the action, it&amp;rsquo;s logged as an API call with the IP address of the source of the request.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Automated &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/workflows/&#34;&gt;workflow&lt;/a&gt; actions are also logged. Each is marked as a workflow actions with the name of the action (i.e. the view name) to identify it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;administration-and-management-actions&#34;&gt;Administration and management actions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All significant actions are recorded, in summary&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;adding, updating or removing users, roles and privileges&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;table additions and removals, field additions and removals, data constraint additions and removals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;view additions, updates and removals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;chart edits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;viewing-logs&#34;&gt;Viewing logs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Changes to schemas (e.g. tables and views) can be seen in the editing panels for those objects. On the development homepage, a history of recent changes can be seen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Changes to an individual record can be seen from the &amp;lsquo;history&amp;rsquo; link at the bottom left of any editing screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the account has the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/usage-monitoring/usage-reporting/#enhanced-audit-trail&#34;&gt;enhanced audit trail&lt;/a&gt; then all data can be queried using Agilebase views.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;retention-periods&#34;&gt;Retention periods&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data is retained for 12 months as standard. The enhanced audit trail allows customers to define their own retention period, the maximum being unlimited.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Software Architect</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/introduction/learner-progression-levels/software-architect/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/introduction/learner-progression-levels/software-architect/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as building and disassembling applications, software architects can set company-wide settings and manage the account as a whole. They can&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add and remove &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/users/&#34;&gt;users&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edit company level settings (e.g. whether to enforce 2FA)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Change table &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/sensitive-data/&#34;&gt;sensitive and personal data&lt;/a&gt; settings (GDPR)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;View and controls users&amp;rsquo; learner progression levels&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assign privileges&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;dont-know-where-to-start&#34;&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t know where to start?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your company has just started building using Agilebase and you are reading this, then you&amp;rsquo;re probably feeling that you&amp;rsquo;ve been thrown in to the deep end!
Don&amp;rsquo;t worry - using Agilebase will feel like you&amp;rsquo;ve been given a life buoy on &amp;hellip; with an outboard motor&amp;hellip; in lovely warm water&amp;hellip; next to the 5 star all inclusive carribean resort!
To kick off, watch the following guide which will walk you through building a fully functional sales CRM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/guides/guide1-crm/&#34;&gt;Build a CRM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;useful-links&#34;&gt;Useful Links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking for some guides to help you&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;COMING SOON - Video about debugging tips and advice on managing Agilebase development projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information about:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/workflows/send-data-to-a-third-party-via-api/&#34;&gt;Using the API&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;Build Patterns&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Logging in from an app</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/app_login/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2021 09:20:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/app_login/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s possible for a developer to create a third party application, for example a phone or tablet app, that communicates with Agilebase via the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/integrations&#34;&gt;API&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now to use the API, you don&amp;rsquo;t need to authenticate as a user, as long as the app has the correct Authorization key(s), it can read and write data to Agilebase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, in some cases the app may need to confirm that someone has a valid Agilebase account before allowing them to use the app. This may or may not be necessary depending on the use case, for example depending on whether the app is free to use for anyone, or must be limited to paying customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To validate a user, the app must redirect them to the Agilebase login page, let them log in and confirm that was successful. Therefore, a HTTP client is necessary - this can be a &amp;lsquo;web view component&amp;rsquo; or a programmatic client such as the &lt;a href=&#34;https://hc.apache.org/&#34;&gt;Apache HTTP Client&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Java_%28programming_language%29&#34;&gt;Java&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this example, we&amp;rsquo;ll use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://reactjs.org/&#34;&gt;React&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.npmjs.com/package/react-native-webview&#34;&gt;Native Web View&lt;/a&gt; but the principle is the same for any programming language or library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;general-principle&#34;&gt;General Principle&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The application must reproduce the same login process as a human would, using a HTTP client. Importantly, the HTTP client must support cookies, as the login process depends on them, in particular setting a &lt;code&gt;JSESSIONID&lt;/code&gt; cookie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make a request to load the page &lt;a href=&#34;https://appserver.gtportalbase.com/Agilebase/AppController.servlet?return=user_details&#34;&gt;https://appserver.gtportalbase.com/Agilebase/AppController.servlet?return=user_details&lt;/a&gt;. This will return the login page and set the cookie value.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Submit the login form using the user&amp;rsquo;s username and password. If using a programattic process i.e. making the calls from code rather than using a web view, this means making a form POST to &lt;code&gt;/Agilebase/j_security_check&lt;/code&gt; with the parameters &lt;code&gt;j_username&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;j_password&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Detect whether the login&amp;rsquo;s successful. If not, the standard Agilebase login failure page will be returned&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If successful, a HTML page will be returned containing three hidden input fields, &lt;code&gt;username&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;forename&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;surname&lt;/code&gt; containing relevant details for the logged in user. If being called from a React Native Web View, the page will also post back messages to React using this JavaScript:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;if (window.ReactNativeWebView) {
    window.ReactNativeWebView.postMessage(&amp;#34;username:&amp;#34; + username);
    window.ReactNativeWebView.postMessage(&amp;#34;forename:&amp;#34; + forename);
    window.ReactNativeWebView.postMessage(&amp;#34;surname:&amp;#34; + surname);
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;example&#34;&gt;Example&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a full example of a login.js page using the React Native Web View. NB this is an example taken from a full application, so you will need to modify it / strip it back to suit your needs, before it can be run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;//Node imports
import React, {useEffect, useRef, useState} from &amp;#39;react&amp;#39;;
import {View, StatusBar, Image, ImageBackground, ScrollView} from &amp;#39;react-native&amp;#39;;

//Local imports
import {styles} from &amp;#39;../../../styles/loginStyles&amp;#39;;
import {Images, Colors, Constants, Language} from &amp;#39;../../../common&amp;#39;;
import {useNetInfo} from &amp;#34;@react-native-community/netinfo&amp;#34;;
import { WebView } from &amp;#39;react-native-webview&amp;#39;;
import {useDispatch, useSelector} from &amp;#39;react-redux&amp;#39;;
import {updateUserData} from &amp;#39;../../../redux/actions/commonAction&amp;#39;;
import commonFunctions from &amp;#39;../../../common/commonFunctions&amp;#39;;
import SplashScreen from &amp;#39;react-native-splash-screen&amp;#39;
const {fontSize, fontFamily, Window} = Constants;

const LoginScreen = (props) =&amp;gt; {
    const dispatch = useDispatch();
    const {user_data} = useSelector(state =&amp;gt; state);
    const netInfo = useNetInfo();

    useEffect(function () {
        SplashScreen.hide();
        console.log(&amp;#39;netInfo==============&amp;#39;, netInfo)
        if(netInfo?.isInternetReachable || netInfo?.details != null){
            checkUser();
        }
    }, [netInfo, user_data]);

    const checkUser = () =&amp;gt; {
        if(user_data &amp;amp;&amp;amp; user_data?.forename &amp;amp;&amp;amp; user_data?.surname &amp;amp;&amp;amp; user_data?.username){
            goToNextPage();
        }
        console.log(&amp;#39;user_data&amp;#39;, user_data)
    }

    const goToNextPage = async () =&amp;gt; {
        await commonFunctions.removeTimeStamp();
        navigateToNextPage();
    }

    const onResponseFromWebView = (event) =&amp;gt; {
        const eventData = event.nativeEvent.data;
        console.log(&amp;#39;eventData&amp;#39;, eventData);
        if (eventData.includes(&amp;#39;username&amp;#39;)) {
            dispatch(updateUserData({username: eventData.split(&amp;#39;username:&amp;#39;)[1]}));
        } else if (eventData.includes(&amp;#39;forename&amp;#39;)) {
            dispatch(updateUserData({forename: eventData.split(&amp;#39;forename:&amp;#39;)[1]}));
        } else if (eventData.includes(&amp;#39;surname&amp;#39;)) {
            dispatch(updateUserData({surname: eventData.split(&amp;#39;surname:&amp;#39;)[1]}));
        }
    }

    const navigateToNextPage = () =&amp;gt; {
        if (netInfo?.isInternetReachable) {
            return props.navigation.navigate(&amp;#39;Loading&amp;#39;);
        }
        return props.navigation.navigate(&amp;#39;MyApplicationPage&amp;#39;);
    }

    return (
        &amp;lt;View style={styles.container}&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;StatusBar backgroundColor={Colors.black} barStyle={&amp;#39;dark-content&amp;#39;}/&amp;gt;
            {(netInfo?.isInternetReachable &amp;amp;&amp;amp; !user_data?.surname) ?
                &amp;lt;WebView
                    source={{uri: &amp;#39;https://appserver.gtportalbase.com/Agilebase/AppController.servlet?return=user_details&amp;#39;}}
                    onMessage={onResponseFromWebView}
                    textZoom={100}
                    sharedCookiesEnabled={true}
                /&amp;gt; :
                &amp;lt;View style={styles.loadingImage}&amp;gt;
                    &amp;lt;Image source={Images.logo}/&amp;gt;
                &amp;lt;/View&amp;gt;
            }
        &amp;lt;/View&amp;gt;
    );
};

export default LoginScreen;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Hierarchy Navigation</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/hierarchy-navigation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/hierarchy-navigation/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Agilebase does its best with sensible defaults to create a friendly user interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s useful for a software architect to know how to configure and tweak the system to allow the to user navigate the structure of an application in the most intuitive way possible.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Sensitive data</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/sensitive-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/sensitive-data/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;In a table&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;privacy and security&lt;/em&gt; panel, there are two options which are worth considering if the data is storing commercially sensitive information (plenty of information in most customer systems falls under this category!) or personal information as defined by EU General Data Protection Regulations (GDPR).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When either option is ticked, two controls appear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/privacy-and-security.png&#34; alt=&#34;Privacy and security&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;notify-administrators-on-export&#34;&gt;Notify administrators on export&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here you can enter a number. When a user exports more than that number of records at once to spreadsheet, all administrators (users with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/privileges/#assigning-the-administrator-privilege&#34;&gt;administrator&lt;/a&gt; privilege) are notified by email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;disallow-exports&#34;&gt;Disallow exports&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is also a number, representing a hard limit on the number of records which can be exported from this table at any one time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/exporting/&#34;&gt;exporting&lt;/a&gt; for how to set up export privileges. Exports are disallowed by default.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When &lt;strong&gt;This table contains personal data, sensitive data or data about children&lt;/strong&gt; is ticked, a number of additional data entry boxes appear, to let you record the GDPR-relevant considerations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: This is for informational purposes only and doesn&amp;rsquo;t by itself ensure compliance with the GDPR!. We recommend looking at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/guide-to-the-general-data-protection-regulation-gdpr/&#34;&gt;ICO website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;potential-exfiltration-information&#34;&gt;Potential exfiltration information&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When either option is ticked, some additional information is shown that can highlight opportunities for data to be exported.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any API views which send data to third party systems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any roles which are set up to allow exporting and which have users with privileges to see the table data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Changing Field Types</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-types/changing-field-types/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-types/changing-field-types/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Once a field has been created, the type can&amp;rsquo;t be changed with the flick of a switch. However there is an easy to follow process to accomplish this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rename the field to &lt;code&gt;[fieldname] old&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add a new field &lt;code&gt;[fieldname]&lt;/code&gt;. This means that any calculations that reference the field won&amp;rsquo;t have to be changed and won&amp;rsquo;t break due to mis-matching field names&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy all values from one field to another. The easiest way is to use a &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/workflows/&#34;&gt;workflow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Try to delete the old field. If any views reference it, the delete will fail and a list of them will be shown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edit all those views
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;remove the old field and add the new, to all fields, filters etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;update all calculations that reference the field e.g. add a space to the end of all of them. That will refresh them to reference the new field rather than the old&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, delete the old field&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before starting, it will be worth ensuring that data won&amp;rsquo;t change during the process, for example by making the data read-only to all users, or requesting they don&amp;rsquo;t edit field values until finished.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Data Integrity Checks</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/data-integrity-checks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/data-integrity-checks/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;It can be important to ensure that certain rules are followed when data is entered, either manually by a user, by an incoming &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/integrations/&#34;&gt;API request&lt;/a&gt; or someone filling in a &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/workflows/send-chaser/&#34;&gt;chaser&lt;/a&gt; response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When designing applications, just be aware there is sometimes a trade-off between the ideal of data integrity and everyday concerns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, you may like to force users to always provide an email address for contacts but in a small minority of cases, they may not have that available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agilebase has options for handling soft validation (highlighting errors or notifying someone) as well as the hard validation (disallowing invalid data entry) options discussed here. For example, you could&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/views/&#34;&gt;Create a view&lt;/a&gt;to show all records with errors, for later checking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set up a workflow or chaser to &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/workflows/send-chaser/&#34;&gt;chase someone&lt;/a&gt; when errors are found&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/integrations/&#34;&gt;API&lt;/a&gt; to send a message to your internal messaging system e.g. Slack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, these are the ways in which you can strictly enforce data integrity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;at-an-individual-field-level&#34;&gt;At an individual field level&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basic rules can be applied with &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-options/common-options/&#34;&gt;field options&lt;/a&gt;. For example a field may be set as mandatory, or it must contain unique values (no duplicates).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;data-integrity-checks-advanced&#34;&gt;Data integrity checks (advanced)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/adding-and-removing/#editing-a-table&#34;&gt;Edit a table&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click _Data Integrity Checks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click &amp;lsquo;Add Single-Field Check&amp;rsquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here you can add more complex checks, such as the value must be longer or shorter than a certain length, be within a date range or match a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Regular_expression&#34;&gt;regular expression&lt;/a&gt;. The list of checks available is the same as that used in &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/views/filters/&#34;&gt;view filters&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/field-checks.png&#34; alt=&#34;Field checks&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;multi-field-unique-constraints&#34;&gt;Multi-field unique constraints&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/adding-and-removing/#editing-a-table&#34;&gt;Edit a table&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click _Data Integrity Checks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click &amp;lsquo;Add Multi-Field Unique Check&amp;rsquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, fields must be unique &lt;strong&gt;in combination&lt;/strong&gt;. For example, imagine you have a system for recording customer complaints. One of the fields might be a customer&amp;rsquo;s reference number, another a relation to the customer record.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You want to avoid duplicates being entered, so could make the customer reference number unique. However it could be that two different customers could use the same reference number independently, so that wouldn&amp;rsquo;t really work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The solution is to add a multi-field unique constraint on customer and customer reference number. That way, a reference number won&amp;rsquo;t be able to be re-used for a complaint from the same customer, but more than one customer is allowed to use the same reference.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Options</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/options/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/options/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;To access these options, &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/adding-and-removing/#editing-a-table&#34;&gt;edit a table&lt;/a&gt; and select &amp;rsquo;tags and options&#39;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;allow-add&#34;&gt;Allow add&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If this is ticked (it is by default), users can add records to the table. Anyone with develop privileges on the table can add tables regardless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;only-from-within-tab&#34;&gt;Only from within tab&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If this is ticked, users can add records but only when accessing this table&amp;rsquo;s form from within a tab of a parent record. This can help ensure that child records are always connected to a parent and aren&amp;rsquo;t created as &amp;lsquo;orphans&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;allow-clone-and-merge&#34;&gt;Allow clone and merge&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Off by default). Show a clone/merge record button when a user is viewing a record.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cloning makes a simple copy of all data in the record. The contents of tabs are not cloned. A more advanced clone facility can be created with a &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/workflows/&#34;&gt;workflow&lt;/a&gt; if desired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Merging allows the user to select another record to merge with this one. This is commonly use to resolve a situation where there are duplicate records. The contents of one are merged into the other, then the first deleted. A wizard will guide the user through selecting which data to keep from each record. Child records from the deleted record will be re-attached to the one remaining. So for example if Organisation 1 containing two contacts is merged with Organisation 2 containing 3, a single organisation with five contacts will result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;allow-remove&#34;&gt;Allow remove&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(On by default). Allow records to be deleted by people with EDIT privileges as well as people with develop privileges, who can always delete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;allow-share&#34;&gt;Allow share&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Showa button which allows links to individual records to be shared between users using email. Note - recipients still need a login and relevant privileges to see the record.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;data-entry-from-external-sources&#34;&gt;Data entry from external sources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The options in this section are for configuring the table to allow an API request from an external source to create and edit records. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/integrations/&#34;&gt;API use&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;other-options&#34;&gt;Other options&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;records-lockable&#34;&gt;Records lockable&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Records can be locked to prevent editing. You may like to do this based on criteria e.g. once a customer order has been sent, it should be locked against further changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To actually lock the record, a &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/workflows/&#34;&gt;workflow&lt;/a&gt; can be used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Locked records can be manually unlocked by someone with develop privileges on the table, but only one at a time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;email-notifications&#34;&gt;Email notifications&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When someone adds a comment to a record, when selecting recipients, they have the option to email those recipients, as well as adding the comment to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tiles/&#34;&gt;comment stream&lt;/a&gt;. Ticking this table option sets the default to send emails for any comment added to this table. Users can override this on an individual comment basis and recipients can override in their notification preferences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;flag-records-with-colour&#34;&gt;Flag records with colour&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enter a field name here and add a field with the same name to a view, to flag records. The contents of the field must be one of the colour names as given on the screen. The field added to the view can be a calculation, specifically a hidden calculation. This will flag the view without showing the colour name on screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This option can also be used to colour items in a junction chooser (see tab option: &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/hierarchy-navigation/tabs/#choose-a-record-when-a-new-item-is-added&#34;&gt;Choose a record when a new item is added&lt;/a&gt;). In the junction table, set this option, then in the view used as a relation picker (set in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-options/relation-field-options/#view-to-use&#34;&gt;relation field options&lt;/a&gt;), add the colour calculation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s also possible to colour individual table fields or calculations in a view (as opposed to this option which flags the whole row). See the options for &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-options/text-field-options/#colour-words&#34;&gt;field colouring&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/views/calculations/#colouring&#34;&gt;calculation colouring&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;accept-emails-to-this-address&#34;&gt;Accept emails to this address&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The system can accept incoming emails and attach them to relevant records e.g. attaching an email from a customer to that customer&amp;rsquo;s record.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A particular email address can be set up to receive emails. The system can be configured to either accept emails from anyone, or just from users. If just from users, then users can forward any emails they receive to the system to have them imported, or BCC the address when sending to people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The email text will be logged as a &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-types/special-field-types/comment-feeds/&#34;&gt;comment&lt;/a&gt; against the record, with the full email attached if it is HTML formatted or includes attachments. The table must have a comments field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please &lt;a href=&#34;https://agilechilli.com/contact-us/&#34;&gt;contact us&lt;/a&gt; if you&amp;rsquo;d like to set that up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emails are matched by creating a view containing the email addresses of potential recipients. An incoming email is attached to the record from this view which matches the sender&amp;rsquo;s email address. If there is no match, it is added to a &amp;lsquo;holding bay&amp;rsquo; where users can view and manually attach emails to records.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;configuring-the-email-address-used&#34;&gt;Configuring the email address used&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An email address of the form &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:viewname@accountname.domainname&#34;&gt;viewname@accountname.domainname&lt;/a&gt; will be set up, e.g. &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:contacts@mycompany.agilebase.co.uk&#34;&gt;contacts@mycompany.agilebase.co.uk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;viewname&lt;/em&gt; determines the view which Agilebase queries to find the recipient email address. The comment will be added to the matching record in the view&amp;rsquo;s parent table, or a tab of the table, if &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/hierarchy-navigation/tabs/#accept-emails-from-parent-table&#34;&gt;Accept emails from parent table&lt;/a&gt; is enabled in a tab. If multiple tabs have this option enabled, then the tab with a name also matching &lt;em&gt;viewname&lt;/em&gt; is used&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;accountname&lt;/em&gt; determines the company account to look in&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;domainname&lt;/em&gt; is the domain name of the Agilebase server&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;information&#34;&gt;Information&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the options, some structural information is shown, such as which tables depend on this one i.e. have a &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-types/basic-field-types/#relation&#34;&gt;relation&lt;/a&gt; to it, how many fields and views per tile there are. See also the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/usage-monitoring/usage-reporting/#the-dashboard&#34;&gt;usage dashboard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Workflow</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 12:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/workflow/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The workflow panel of a table shows any &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/workflows/&#34;&gt;workflows&lt;/a&gt; which act on data in that table. In other words, any workflow that updates records, creates new records in the table, or deletes records from it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/workflow-tab.png&#34; alt=&#34;Workflow tab&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, this panel allows you to choose a workflow to run whenever a new record is created, or (less frequently used) whenever a record is opened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That can be very useful for setting initial values for fields, where those values may be more complex calculations than just a static default value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;when-a-records-created-run-workflow&#34;&gt;When a record&amp;rsquo;s created, run workflow&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Run a &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/workflows/&#34;&gt;workflow&lt;/a&gt; immediately after the creation of a record. The workflow runs after any field default values have been set.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The workflow &amp;lsquo;knows&amp;rsquo; metadata such as which user is logged in, which tile is open etc., so if you want to &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/views/calculations/#special-functions&#34;&gt;use those in a calculation&lt;/a&gt; in the workflow, you can do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that only workflows which have &lt;strong&gt;Frequency = manual&lt;/strong&gt; set can be chosen to be run when a record is created. That&amp;rsquo;s because a single workflow can&amp;rsquo;t be used both to set initial values &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; to run every X minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;run-this-workflow-whenever-each-record-is-viewed&#34;&gt;Run this workflow whenever each record is viewed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as running the workflow on record creation, also run it whenever a user views a record in this table. Be aware this may have a performance impact for users, if the workflow is resource intensive and/or multi-step, particularly if records are also viewed frequently.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Calculation Examples</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/views/calculations/examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/views/calculations/examples/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The database which underpins Agilebase is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.postgresql.org&#34;&gt;PostgreSQL&lt;/a&gt; - &amp;lsquo;The World&amp;rsquo;s Most Advanced Open Source Relational Database&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This page will just be an introduction to some of the things you can do with calculations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A comprehensive definition and reference for all of the functions possible can be found here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.postgresql.org/docs/current/functions.html&#34;&gt;https://www.postgresql.org/docs/current/functions.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;example-functions-for-each-type-of-field&#34;&gt;Example functions for each type of field&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some &amp;lsquo;starters for 10&amp;rsquo; that may be useful day to day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;general-functions&#34;&gt;General functions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a couple of functions that are particularly useful to know about, to keep in your calculations toolkit. These are&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;coalesce&#34;&gt;Coalesce&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The coalesce function lets you deal sensibly with empty values, which we call &amp;rsquo;null&amp;rsquo; values. Normally, if any field you reference is null, then the result of the calculation is also null. Coalesce is a way to provide a default value. So for example, if a view of customer order lines has a quantity and a price field, but the quantity may be blank, then&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;coalesce({quantity}, 0) * {price}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;would calculate the line value, outputting zero if the quantity is not filled in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coalesce can be used with more than two arguments - the first non-null value it encounters, from left to right, will be output to be used in further calculation steps&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;case&#34;&gt;Case&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A case statement can be used to add &amp;lsquo;if/then/else&amp;rsquo; logic. An example is&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;case
  when {due date} is null then &amp;#39;unknown&amp;#39;
  when {due date} &amp;lt; now() then &amp;#39;overdue&amp;#39;
  when {due date} &amp;lt; now() + interval &amp;#39;7 days&amp;#39; then &amp;#39;due soon&amp;#39;
  else &amp;#39;not due yet&amp;#39;
end
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;(We&amp;rsquo;ll cover date calculations more below).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note the top clauses of a case statement are evaluated first, so put more specific things at the top if multiple lines may match.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;number-functions&#34;&gt;Number functions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Common mathematical functions can be found here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.postgresql.org/docs/current/functions-math.html&#34;&gt;https://www.postgresql.org/docs/current/functions-math.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;text-functions&#34;&gt;Text functions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;{field 1} || &#39; &#39; || {field 2}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Two vertical bars are used to join bits of text together (this seems an odd choice to use rather than something like an ampersand or + sign, but there you go, that&amp;rsquo;s what it is). A literal piece of text is surrounded by single quotes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;substring({text field} FROM 1 FOR 1)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extracts the first letter (or other character e.g. number) from some text.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;regexp_replace({full name}, &#39;\\s.*&#39;, &#39;&#39;)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A simplistic way of extracting a person&amp;rsquo;s first name from a full name - strip out everything from the first space onwards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;regexp_replace(
  {account owner},
  &amp;#39;.*\\((.*)\\).*&amp;#39;,
  &amp;#39;\\1&amp;#39;
)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A more complex example. Given an &amp;lsquo;account owner&amp;rsquo; value in the format &lt;strong&gt;Forename Surname (username)&lt;/strong&gt;, extract the username, i.e. everything between the brackets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last two are slightly more complex because they use a powerful text matching/search and replace facility called &lt;strong&gt;regular expressions&lt;/strong&gt;, or regexes for short. Again, this is a standard facility and there&amp;rsquo;s lots of documentation available on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.postgresql.org/docs/current/functions-matching.html#FUNCTIONS-POSIX-REGEXP&#34;&gt;PostgreSQL website&lt;/a&gt; and elsewhere if you&amp;rsquo;d like to learn more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only difference from standard to be aware of is that when entering a regex into a calculation in Agilebase, you must use two backslashes instead of one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;like&lt;/code&gt; compares two elements of text and &lt;code&gt;ilike&lt;/code&gt; does so case-insensitively. A percentage sign means &amp;lsquo;match any text&amp;rsquo;. So for example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;case
  when {postcode} ilike &amp;#39;bs%&amp;#39; then &amp;#39;Bristol&amp;#39;
  else &amp;#39;elsewhere&amp;#39;
end
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Outputs &amp;lsquo;Bristol&amp;rsquo; if the postcode field starts with &amp;lsquo;BS&amp;rsquo; (or &amp;lsquo;bs&amp;rsquo;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;date-functions&#34;&gt;Date functions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The database has very strong support for working with dates and time - you can do many calculations on them. Here are a few examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;{date field} + &#39;1 year&#39;::interval&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;adds a year on to the given date&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can do the same with months, week, days etc. and combinations like &amp;lsquo;1 week 1 day&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;date_part(&#39;year&#39;, {date field})&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;date_part(&#39;dow&#39;, {date field})&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;These two extract different parts of the date - the first just the year, the second the day of the week as a number 0 - 6. More info is available in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.postgresql.org/docs/current/static/functions-datetime.html#FUNCTIONS-DATETIME-EXTRACT%22&#34;&gt;PostgreSQL documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;date_part(&#39;days&#39;, ((date_trunc(&#39;month&#39;, now()) + &#39;1 month&#39;::interval) - now()))&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Works out how many days are left in the current month. This example introduces a couple more date functions:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;now()&lt;/code&gt; gives the current date and time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;date_trunc&lt;/code&gt; &amp;rsquo;truncates&amp;rsquo; a date to the month in this case (in other words rounding it down to the nearest month)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;to_char(&#39;19 May 2020&#39;::timestamp, &#39;Day&#39;)&lt;/code&gt; - outputs &amp;lsquo;Tuesday&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;to_char(&#39;19 May 2020&#39;::timestamp, &#39;Mon yyyy&#39;)&lt;/code&gt; - outputs &amp;lsquo;May 2020&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.postgresql.org/docs/current/functions-formatting.html&#34;&gt;to_char&lt;/a&gt; formats a date (it also works with numbers)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;date_part(&#39;weeks&#39;,{date field 1} - {date field 2})&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Counts the number of weeks between two dates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;aggregate-calculations&#34;&gt;Aggregate calculations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of the examples above work within one row, or record, of data. Aggregate calculations are different, the take many rows of data and condense them down into one result - one number, or piece of text, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They&amp;rsquo;re very useful for creating summaries of data, such as total sales per product, counts of complaints per month per category, total value of an order (summing individual order lines) etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;aggregates-of-child-rows&#34;&gt;Aggregates of child rows&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make an aggregate you have to have something to summarise by and something to aggregate. The easiest way of doing this is to create a view with a &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/views/joins/#upwards-and-downwards-joins&#34;&gt;join down&lt;/a&gt; from a parent table to a child. You can then summarise, or group by each parent row and aggregate one (or more) of the fields in the child table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, if we have an invoices table and an invoice lines table, assuming there is a relation linking each invoice line to its parent invoice:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/views/creating-a-view/&#34;&gt;create a view&lt;/a&gt; from the invoices table - we&amp;rsquo;ll call it &amp;lsquo;invoice totals&amp;rsquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/views/joins/&#34;&gt;add a join&lt;/a&gt; down to invoice lines&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add the calculation &lt;code&gt;sum({line total})&lt;/code&gt; to the view&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should then have a view with just one row per invoice line, showing the invoice total. &lt;strong&gt;sum&lt;/strong&gt; is an example of an aggregate calculation. Another common example is &lt;strong&gt;count&lt;/strong&gt;. If you replaced &lt;code&gt;sum({line total})&lt;/code&gt; with &lt;code&gt;count(*)&lt;/code&gt;, that would count the number of invoice lines in the invoice, instead of totalling the values up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note - the aggregate calculation groups by all non-aggregate fields in a view. For example, if you added the product name into ou invoice totals view, you&amp;rsquo;d get a total per product per invoice, rather than a total for each whole invoice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;aggregates-without-child-rows&#34;&gt;Aggregates without child rows&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s another way to create aggregates, which can be used without joining down to a child table or view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the tiles interface, open the view you wish to edit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click your user icon at the top right and select &lt;em&gt;admin - edit view&lt;/em&gt; from the menu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tick &lt;em&gt;Group by all non-aggregate fields&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add any fields you wish to group by to the view. Remove any you don&amp;rsquo;t wish to group by &lt;strong&gt;including any hidden fields&lt;/strong&gt; such as the IDs of joined tables&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add the aggregate calculation e.g. &lt;code&gt;sum({my field})&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;expanding-rows&#34;&gt;Expanding rows&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some functions do the opposite of an aggregate function - rather than condensing and summarising many rows into one, they split one row up into many. For example, if one of your fields is a comma separated list, you could split that up into many rows, one per item in the list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Say for example you import data from a form on a website which produces a comma separated list of products ordered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adding the calculation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;regexp_split_to_table({products ordered}, &#39;,&#39;)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;would produce one output row per product in the list. That could then be joined to other data in the system such as pricing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;window-functions&#34;&gt;Window functions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Window functions are somewhat like aggregate functions in that they can act on many rows, not just one. However, they don&amp;rsquo;t condense down into a single row. An example would be calculating a rolling average or cumulative total as each row is shown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Effectively, they look at a &amp;lsquo;window&amp;rsquo;, also called a partition, of rows around the current row and calculate a result based on those. That could be for example&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the current row, the one before and the one after it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;every row up to the current row&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;every row&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;every row which is similar in some way e.g. has the same value for a &amp;lsquo;category&amp;rsquo; field&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an example,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;{price} - avg({price}) over (partition by {category})&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;would calculate for each item, the difference from the average price of items with the same category.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This again is much too large a topic to cover in an introductory page, there&amp;rsquo;s plenty of documentation here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.postgresql.org/docs/current/tutorial-window.html&#34;&gt;https://www.postgresql.org/docs/current/tutorial-window.html&lt;/a&gt;
and a video introduction to the concept here:&lt;/p&gt;

 &lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
   &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/blHEnrYwySE&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;series-generation&#34;&gt;Series generation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you need to &lt;strong&gt;generate&lt;/strong&gt; a set of rows, as opposed to having the data stored in the database. Here are some quick examples:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;generate_series(1,10)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;generates the numbers 1 to 10, each one in a different row&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;generate_series(now() - &#39;10 years&#39;::interval, now(), &#39;1 month&#39;::interval)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;generates one row per month, from 10 years ago up until this month&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The functions above highlight just a few of the many possibilities. Please feel free to read up on PostgreSQL some more and if you come up with any neat calculations yourself in your everyday work, please do send them to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:support@agilebase.co.uk&#34;&gt;support@agilebase.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; so we can add them to this page (with credit).&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Roles and Privileges</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/users-and-roles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/users-and-roles/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;When editing a table, the &lt;em&gt;Roles and Privileges&lt;/em&gt; panel allows privileges to be assigned to a user or role on a table. Please see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/privileges/&#34;&gt;privileges&lt;/a&gt; page for more details.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Usage</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/usage/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/usage/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;This panel shows a list of views that contain data from the table. Any view with data is included, not just those directly created from the table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/usage-monitoring/usage-reporting/&#34;&gt;usage reporting&lt;/a&gt; for more info.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/new-table-usage.png&#34; alt=&#34;table usage&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Testing</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/integrations/test-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 12:15:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/integrations/test-server/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;When systems get to a certain size, in particular when you start integrating with apps representing other parts of the business, then it can be beneficial to be able to test new developments and changes before putting them live.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, when accepting orders via an e-commerce website, or sending invoices to an accounting package, or accepting incoming stock change records from Goods In staff using a bar code scanning application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In cases like that, you don&amp;rsquo;t want potentially large quantities of test data polluting your live system. And when systems are up and running, they can be mission critical - you don&amp;rsquo;t want a change to cause online orders to be missed or incorrect invoices to transfer to accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People from the traditional IT world will be familiar with the concept of testing changes during the development process, before deploying them live.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Agilebase is a no-code platform, the processes are slightly different - there are no &amp;lsquo;code&amp;rsquo; changes to deploy. But here&amp;rsquo;s how we achieve the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;commissioning-a-test-server&#34;&gt;Commissioning a test server&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In summary, when your system is&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mature&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mission critical&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;integrating with third party systems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;then you will most likely benefit from requesting a test server setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The test server will be an exact copy of your live system. The application structure (table, views etc.) will be the same as will the data itself in the database. All users and roles will also be the same, so people can log in using their existing username and passwords to test changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-test-process&#34;&gt;The test process&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Transfer a snapshot from live - this will update your test system to be an exact copy of the live system as of approx. 7am in the morning
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Log in to the web interface for your test server at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linode.com&#34;&gt;www.linode.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click your test server name, then the &amp;lsquo;Launch LISH Console&amp;rsquo; button at the top right&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter your username, then password at the prompts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Type &lt;code&gt;sudo ./reload.sh&lt;/code&gt; and enter your password again&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The system will now update from the latest snapshot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Type &amp;rsquo;logout&amp;rsquo; and press Enter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please wait around 5 minutes then you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to log in to it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make and test any changes on the test server&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;View a summary list of changes you&amp;rsquo;ve made
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/usage-monitoring/usage-reporting/#enhanced-audit-trail&#34;&gt;enhanced audit trail&lt;/a&gt; to see changes like field addition/removals or view alterations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you don&amp;rsquo;t already have the enhanced audit trail, it will be set up as part of the test server commisioning process&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Re-create those changes in the live system
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is currently a manual process, though the audit trail above helps ensure you&amp;rsquo;ve not missed anything&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Internal IDs for tables, fields and views are deterministic. That means if you create them with the same names in the same order on the live system, they will get the same internal IDs. Therefore APIs using them won&amp;rsquo;t need changing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;API Authorization keys however will be different, so will need updating in any system that calls a new API&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By default, a new snapshot will be made available every 24hrs, at around 7am. However, if you wish, you can ask us to set up a different timing or frequency of snapshots, just let us know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;testing-agilebase-platform-updates&#34;&gt;Testing Agilebase platform updates&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as testing your own changes, the test server comes with the added benefit that you can access pre-release versions of new versions of the Agilebase platform itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That means you can test out new features before they&amp;rsquo;re released and if you like run your own API tests against it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We do of course have our own automated API and end to end tests, but you&amp;rsquo;re welcome to add your own specific unit tests for any APIs specific to your setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will be optionally enrolled onto our pre-release mailing list to be notified when a new version has been prepared, along with it&amp;rsquo;s planned release date which will typically be Monday to Wednesday the following week.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: External Reporting</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/integrations/external-reporting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 08:06:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/integrations/external-reporting/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;As well as using the REST API, an ODBC database link can send data to external tools such as Power BI, Tableau, Apache Superset or preset.io or even just Excel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please see &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/charting/business-intelligence/&#34;&gt;Business Intelligence&lt;/a&gt; for full details.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Advanced Usage</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/advanced-usage/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/advanced-usage/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Also, new features, news and tips and tricks are posted on &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.agilebase.co.uk&#34;&gt;https://blog.agilebase.co.uk&lt;/a&gt;. Please subscribe on that page to receive any updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When carrying out changes to critical systems which the business relies on, you may wish to take advantage of a &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/integrations/test-server/&#34;&gt;test server&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Company Settings</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/advanced-usage/company-settings/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/advanced-usage/company-settings/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;To access them:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the administration interface, expand the &lt;em&gt;Administration&lt;/em&gt; section at the bottom left&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select &lt;em&gt;company&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click the pencil icon in the top toolbar to edit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;mandate-2fa&#34;&gt;Mandate 2FA&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When this is ticked, all users in the organisation will be required to set up &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/users/2fa-setup/&#34;&gt;Two Factor Authentication&lt;/a&gt; before they can see or use any features of the application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We recommend that all administrators enable this if possible. Even when 2FA is mandated, admins can still &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/users/#two-factor-authentication&#34;&gt;disable it temporarily&lt;/a&gt; on a per-user basis. The next time they log in they will be prompted to set it up again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When this is off, users will still be prompted to set up 2FA, it just won&amp;rsquo;t be mandatory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;smtp-server&#34;&gt;SMTP server&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agilebase &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/workflows/send-email/&#34;&gt;workflows&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/workflows/send-chaser/&#34;&gt;chasers&lt;/a&gt; that send emails use an @notifications.agilebase.co.uk email address by default.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may wish to instead use email addresses from your own domain name, especially if the system sends emails to people outside your organisation, like customers or suppliers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To allow this, you will need to use your own SMTP server, or a third party trusted system authenticated against your domain name. Using a service like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.authsmtp.com/&#34;&gt;AuthSmtp&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sendgrid.com/&#34;&gt;SendGrid&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://aws.amazon.com/ses/&#34;&gt;Amazon Simple Email Service&lt;/a&gt; is probably the most straightforward way of setting this up - their instructions will tell you how to set up facilities such as Sender Policy Framework and DomainKeys in order to increase email deliverability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you have the SMTP server address, username and password from your service, enter them into the details in this section in Agilebase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;slack-webhook-url&#34;&gt;Slack Webhook URL&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/integrations/slack-integration/&#34;&gt;Integrations - Slack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;send-chart-subscriptions-from&#34;&gt;Send chart subscriptions from&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users can opt to have daily, weekly or monthly emails sent to them containing all the charts they&amp;rsquo;ve subscribed to for that period. The emails will come from an email address @notifications.agilebase.co.uk by default, this option will allow you to specify your own address.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If used, then the SMTP details above also need to be completed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;export-message&#34;&gt;Export message&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you will know, your organisation is required to protect personal data, as per the GDPR. One thing to watch out for is what happens to data that is exported to spreadsheet?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are various &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/exporting/&#34;&gt;rules&lt;/a&gt; you can set up to control exports that are well worth familiarising yourself with, as an administrator. These control who can export, what they can export and how much can be exported. Once data is in a spreadsheet of course, the system no longer has any control over it. It can be emailed, shared etc. as the spreadsheet owner wishes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This option allows you to set the text of a prompt that users see before exporting. It can be used to remind people of their obligations and point them to any further information provided by your organisation. They will need to tick to accept before performing the export.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Send Data to a third party via API</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/workflows/send-data-to-a-third-party-via-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 12:35:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/workflows/send-data-to-a-third-party-via-api/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;When integrating Agilebase with third party systems, the API is really useful. Programmers can use it to send data to websites, to other software such as PowerBI, a  Business Intelligence tool, or to external systems such as label/barcode printers for example. The opportunities are endless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agilebase can either ‘push’ data to a third party system, or have the third party system ‘pull’ it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s the difference? Simply put, if pulling, a third party system has to regularly ask, or &amp;lsquo;poll&amp;rsquo;, Agilebase whether there’s any new data. It may do this once an hour, once every few minutes or however often it needs. That means extra work for both systems. New data may be reasonably infrequent but when it is there you want it to be transferred quickly, which means polling often even when there’s nothing to send.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conversely, with ‘push’, Agilebase sends a message to the third party system &lt;strong&gt;only when there’s relevant data to send&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;push&#34;&gt;PUSH&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When using push, calls are made only when necessary. Further, you can specify in the settings the maximum number of calls to make per day, so you can control the maximum possible cost. You can set it to anything from once every 5 minutes to once a day. Different integrations may require more or less timely data. For example invoice totals may be ok to push to an accounting system once a day but individual customer orders may be best sent as soon as they’re received.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/integrations/setting-up-the-push-api/&#34;&gt;More detail about setting up a PUSH API can be found here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;pull&#34;&gt;Pull&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Connections to Agilebase are made using standard HTTP calls. This makes it easy for developers in any language, so PHP, Java, even JavaScript in a browser can be used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/integrations/setting-up-the-pull-api/&#34;&gt;More detail about setting up a PULL API can be found here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Build Patterns</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/advanced-usage/build-patterns/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/advanced-usage/build-patterns/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Some of these are just useful ideas, some are tips and tricks and some are larger-scale build patterns for more complex tasks commonly undertaken by customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These tips will link to various other places in the documentation, but it will still be useful to have some experience of building in Agilebase before reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;settings-table-idea&#34;&gt;Settings table idea&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To use a single store of a common setting throughout the application. When a setting is changed it will then automatically take effect throught the whole application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example: VAT rate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;snapshots-idea&#34;&gt;Snapshots idea&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taking snapshots of a set of rows from a table at a point in time allows a comparison of earlier snapshots with later ones, or the current state, to show differences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example: delivery van loading reports. An initial snapshot of tomorrow’s orders shows what product quantities to load onto the vans. Later snapshots, taken at any point, will show any additions/removals needed at that time, by subtracting the current order lines from previous ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;gap-filling-in-monthly-or-other-period-reporting&#34;&gt;Gap filling in monthly (or other period) reporting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When reporting monthly figures in a view (e.g. quantities sold per product per month), if there may be some gaps, they can be filled with zeros.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In outline, the solution is to&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a table containing one and only one record. Once a record has been created, disallow adding or removing records using &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/options/&#34;&gt;table options&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From that table create a view called e.g. &amp;lsquo;month series&amp;rsquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add a &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/views/calculations/examples/#series-generation&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;generate_series&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; calculation to that view to generate the list of months required.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A report can then be created by joining from &amp;lsquo;month series&amp;rsquo; to the actual data you want to report. You may need to join on a calculation, e.g. a text representation of the month (using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/views/calculations/examples/#date-functions&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;to_char&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; function) or an amalgamation of a month and product code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;joining-on-compound-keys&#34;&gt;Joining on compound keys&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extending the above, what about when you want to summarise by two factors, e.g. ‘by customer by product’. In that case create calculations to make a unique key per combination e.g.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;{customers.id:customers} || ‘_’ || {products.id:products}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use the same calculation in views you want to join to and join on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is much better than the &amp;rsquo;naive&amp;rsquo; idea of creating separate joins to each table, which won’t work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;including-multiple-aggregates-from-different-sources&#34;&gt;Including multiple aggregates from different sources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joining from one table down to multiple child tables in order to perform aggregates will not work - you&amp;rsquo;ll experience double counting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, if a customers table joins down to both &amp;lsquo;customer invoices&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;customer complaints&amp;rsquo;, then a &lt;code&gt;count(*)&lt;/code&gt; calculation will return neither the number of invoices or complaints, but the product of the two i.e. the number of invoices times the number of complaints.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To solve this,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create one view dedicated to each aggregate calculation, created from the parent table. The view will then have one row per parent record i.e. customer in this case&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From a final view created from the parent table, join to these views in order to include the results&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;calculating-the-number-of-weekdays-or-weekends-between-two-dates&#34;&gt;Calculating the number of weekdays or weekends between two dates&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generate a series of all the dates between two dates, calculate the day of the week for each&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From a separate view, join to this series and count up all the cases where it&amp;rsquo;s not a weekend&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is necessary as calculations on the results of a generate_series often need to be done from a separate view&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;outputting-a-pivoted-view-in-a-printout&#34;&gt;Outputting a ‘pivoted’ view in a printout&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a template, &lt;code&gt;$view.htmlTable(“table name”, “view name”)&lt;/code&gt; outputs the contents of the view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use &lt;code&gt;$view.htmlTableTransverse(“table name”, “view name”)&lt;/code&gt; instead for a pivoted version with columns and rows swapped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;capturing-dates-of-status-changes-on-lookup-list&#34;&gt;Capturing dates of status changes on lookup list&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Show a date field only when the dropdown reaches the desired status, using &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-options/common-options/#show-if-record-in-view&#34;&gt;field options&lt;/a&gt;. Use a &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-options/common-options/#set-from-previous-referenced-field&#34;&gt;referenced data field&lt;/a&gt; to populate it with the current time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;record-builder&#34;&gt;Record Builder&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scenario: A customer tends to order the same products every time. Have an option for the system to auto fill the “standard” order every time an order is placed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use the tab option &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/hierarchy-navigation/tabs/#populate-from-template&#34;&gt;Populate from template&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;de-duplicating-a-comma-separated-list&#34;&gt;De-duplicating a comma separated list&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Calculation template:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;array_to_string(
  array(select distinct unnest(
    regexp_split_to_array(‘my,comma,separated,list’, &amp;#39;,&amp;#39;)
  ))
,&amp;#39;,&amp;#39;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;array_to_string(
  array(select distinct unnest(
    regexp_split_to_array(
      string_agg({b2.2) ingredient suppliers.ingredient supplier&amp;#39;s countries of origin}, &amp;#39;,&amp;#39;)
    ,&amp;#39;,&amp;#39;)
  ))
,&amp;#39;,&amp;#39;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;custom-filtering-when-choosing-a-relation&#34;&gt;Custom filtering when choosing a relation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When choosing a relation, either in a &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/relational-database-concepts/&#34;&gt;junction table&lt;/a&gt; or otherwise, the system will automatically filter on the ID of any related parent record. For example, when adding order lines to a customer order, if each product is related to a customer, then the system will automatically only let the user choose products for that customer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However it won’t filter on anything that’s more than one direct relationship away. If you want to do that, or indeed filter on anything else at all, you can create a filter calculation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the relation chooser view, create a calculation e.g. ‘my relation filter’ and set it to contain the contents of what you want to filter on e.g. some other field. The calculation can be hidden.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From the main table, create a new view. In that view, create a calculation with the same name and contents.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add that a cross-reference field into the main table, utilising that view. In the field options, tick &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-options/referenced-field-options/#use-as-a-filter-for-relations&#34;&gt;use as filter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;switching-a-field-from-one-type-to-another&#34;&gt;Switching a field from one type to another&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, converting a whole number field into a decimal number&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rename the field to &amp;lsquo;{fieldname} old&amp;rsquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add a new field &amp;lsquo;{fieldname}&amp;rsquo;. This means that any calcs updated won&amp;rsquo;t have to be changed and won&amp;rsquo;t break due to mis-matching field names&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy all values from one field to another. The easiest way to do that is to use a &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/workflows/&#34;&gt;workflow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Try to delete the old field. It will show a list of views that contain it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edit all those views to remove references to the field and add the new field. That includes updating all calculations that reference the field to trigger the system to realise that the calc. no longer references eht old field&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove the old field&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;finding-the-latest-child-record&#34;&gt;Finding the &amp;rsquo;latest&amp;rsquo; child record&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A common scenario occurs when you have a one to many relationship. You want a view which shows precise info from the &amp;rsquo;latest&amp;rsquo; child record.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start with parent table and join to child, add the controlling field and set the correct order. For example, sorting by &amp;lsquo;created on [auto]&amp;rsquo; descending will give you the newest child record. Then go to &lt;em&gt;properties and options&lt;/em&gt; panel when editing the view and set the &lt;em&gt;Distinct Field&lt;/em&gt; option to the Parent table’s ID field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can now freely add what ever fields from the child record happy in the knowledge you’ll only have the one line per parent.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Performance Optimisation</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/advanced-usage/performance-optimisation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/advanced-usage/performance-optimisation/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Agilebase automatically takes some measures behind the scenes to maintain high performance as data volumes grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are other mechanisms that can be manually enabled such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/views/options/behaviour-options/#cache-view-rows&#34;&gt;caching&lt;/a&gt; and increasing the memory assigned to particular views.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we will be happy to to do all we can to speed up any parts of your application that require it if you &lt;a href=&#34;https://agilechilli.com/contact-us/&#34;&gt;contact us&lt;/a&gt;. Often, a solution as simple as manually adding an index to a particular field can speed up requests by multiple orders of magnitude.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For really big data projects, there&amp;rsquo;s also the option of utilising PostgreSQL-compatible database services designed for such tasks, like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.citusdata.com/&#34;&gt;Citus Data&lt;/a&gt;, which we will be happy to provision.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: PUSH API worked example - Zapier</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/integrations/push-example-zapier/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/integrations/push-example-zapier/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;One of the most common methods of pushing data into other systems is to use &lt;a href=&#34;https://zapier.com&#34;&gt;Zapier&lt;/a&gt;, which is a ‘drag and drop’ integration tool that requires no programming (just like Agilebase itself).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will use a worked example: building a system to send a ‘hello’ SMS message whenever a new contact is added to our database. In real life, you may send appointment reminders or other notifications by text. Of course Zapier integrations aren&amp;rsquo;t limited to sending text messages, there are tons of third party systems you can use, under many different categories, but text messages are a nice simple example to work through.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this example we’ll use&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://agilebase.co.uk&#34;&gt;Agilebase&lt;/a&gt; as a source of data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://zapier.com&#34;&gt;Zapier&lt;/a&gt; to collect the data and send it to…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twilio.com&#34;&gt;Twilio&lt;/a&gt; to send the text messages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;agilebase-setup&#34;&gt;Agilebase setup&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, some preparatory work in Agilebase. Assuming we already have a contacts database, each person with a name and mobile phone number, there’s just one extra thing we need to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The system will need to know when a contact has been sent a text, so it can filter them out and prevent them being repeatedly texted. To allow this, we need to add a field, call it &lt;code&gt;intro text sent&lt;/code&gt;. Make it a date and time field, accurate to the second.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/zapier-sent-field.png&#34; alt=&#34;Zapier sent field&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can set it to ‘show never’, as this information’s unlikely to be useful to the average user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, we &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/views/&#34;&gt;create a view&lt;/a&gt; to provide the data to send to the text messaging service. Here’s such a view. It’s very simple, containing just the info necessary, i.e. a message calculation and the mobile phone number to send it to. We’ve put it in a tile called ‘System – Integration’. It’s a good idea to put views used for system purposes somewhere like this so they’ll be hidden from everyday users, but administrators can still easily find them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/zapier-view.png&#34; alt=&#34;Zapier view&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve added a couple of [filters]((/docs/views/filters/), firstly to make sure we only pick up people who have a phone number entered and secondly to filter out any who’ve already been sent the message (using the Intro Text Sent field we created above). You’ll notice for initial testing only, I’ve added a third filter here so only one contact is listed - myself. When we’ve confirmed the system works as expected, this filter can be removed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/zapier-view-filters.png&#34; alt=&#34;Zapier view filters&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One small note to do with this specific example only – Twilio likes to receive phone numbers in international format but without the leading +, i.e. rather than “07891 123456”, use “447891123456”. In real life we’d probably create a calculation field to format them this way, for now we’ll just make sure to enter test numbers like that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;zapier-setup---receiving-data-from-agilebase&#34;&gt;Zapier Setup - receiving data from Agilebase&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s the Agilebase side of things prepared, now to Zapier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Log into your Zapier account and press the &lt;em&gt;Make a Zap!&lt;/em&gt; button.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under &lt;em&gt;choose app&lt;/em&gt;, select &lt;em&gt;Webhooks by Zapier&lt;/em&gt;. Webhooks are the way to communicate with Agilebase. At the time of writing you’ll need a paid Zapier account to use them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under &lt;em&gt;choose trigger event&lt;/em&gt; two options will be shown - &lt;em&gt;Retrieve Poll&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Catch Hook&lt;/em&gt;. In brief, if you select &lt;em&gt;Retrieve Poll&lt;/em&gt;, Zapier will regularly poll Agilebase (say every 5 minutes) to check if there’s any new data to retrieve. If you select &lt;em&gt;Catch Hook&lt;/em&gt;, communication will instead be started by Agilebase, which will ‘push’ data to Zapier only when there is something new to send.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, we’ll use Catch Hook, which is generally recommended. It’s more efficient and a bit easier to set up, as Agilebase will automatically record the time each record is sent to Zapier. Otherwise, you’ll have to set up additional steps in Zapier to send this information back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/zapier-catch-hook.png&#34; alt=&#34;Zapier catch hook&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you press Continue, Zapier will provide you with a custom URL and some additional options which can be left unchanged. Copy this URL and record it in Agilebase: edit the view and open the &lt;em&gt;Use API&lt;/em&gt; panel. Paste the Zapier URL into the &lt;em&gt;Push URL&lt;/em&gt; space provided:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/zapier-ab-push.png&#34; alt=&#34;Zapier aB push&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, select the date &amp;amp; time field ‘Intro Text Sent’ (created above) in the dropdown. That means whenever a record is sent to Zapier, the timestamp will be recorded in that field. All other settings can be left on their defaults.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, press the &lt;em&gt;Run Workflow Now&lt;/em&gt; button to send a test record to Zapier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in Zapier, just press &lt;em&gt;Test and Continue&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;finishing-zapier-setup&#34;&gt;Finishing Zapier setup&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zapier now has our data, at least a test record. The next step is to set up actually sending the text message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are dozens of Zapier-compatible services that can send text messages. We use Twilio but the process is similar whatever you choose. In fact the process is similar whatever you’re doing with the data, be that sending a text, sending the data to a Google Spreadsheet or Mailchimp, to name just three examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/zapier-select-twilio.png&#34; alt=&#34;Zapier select Twilio&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you press Continue, you’ll be asked to sign into Twilio (in this example). Do that as prompted, then you’ll be able to set the options below. The important ones are&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;From Number&lt;/strong&gt;: just select, this will automatically show any phone numbers you’ve set up in Twilio&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To Number&lt;/strong&gt;: here, click the selector on the right and select the phone number field from Agilebase. By this stage, Zapier, knows which fields are in Agilebase&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Message&lt;/strong&gt;: similarly, click the selctor and choose the message field from Agilebase&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/zapier-send-sms.png&#34; alt=&#34;Zapier send SMS&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Press &lt;em&gt;Test and Continue&lt;/em&gt;. If all goes well, a text message will be sent and you’ll get the option to turn the integration on permanently!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/zapier-success.png&#34; alt=&#34;Zapier success&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, you can remove the test filters from the view in Agilebase and everything will be live.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although today we used the example of sending a text message, the process is very similar whichever service you decide to connect to with Zapier - you should be able to follow along the example replacing the SMS-specific steps with your own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good luck and please let us know what cool things you do with your data. Also if anything can be improved in this walkthrough, we’d be very keen to hear about that too.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Complete API worked example</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/integrations/complex-example/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/integrations/complex-example/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a great example of using an API to provide business benefits, that we use ourselves here at agileChilli. As well as outlining the steps necessary to set up the API, with links to other documentation pages where relevant, we also include other elements of the solution, like workflows and charting, which often form a part of integrations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scenario is that we want to be able to look up and store multiple years worth of financial data for any UK company we hold in our CRM system. It can be useful to be able to have this data to hand to aid sales, when considering partnering or when doing competitor/market analysis for example - see our &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.agilebase.co.uk/2021/11/01/the-value-of-integrating-with-endole/&#34;&gt;CEO&amp;rsquo;s blog post&lt;/a&gt; on the subject.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, we need to find a provider of this data who have an API - we use &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.endole.co.uk/&#34;&gt;Endole&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need to &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/&#34;&gt;create a table&lt;/a&gt; to store the figures. We created a &amp;lsquo;financial data&amp;rsquo; table containing the following fields:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/financial-fields.png&#34; alt=&#34;financial fields&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first field is a link to the organisation we&amp;rsquo;re looking up financial data about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second is a text field which stores the date that figures are reported for. The reason that it&amp;rsquo;s a text field is that our service, Endole, uses the format YYYYMM to represent the date, e.g. 202110 for October 2021. Agilebase doesn&amp;rsquo;t recognise this date format for incoming data via the API but not to worry, we can save it as text, then create a workflow in Agilebase to transform it into an actual date as the data comes in. That&amp;rsquo;s the next field and we&amp;rsquo;ll cover the process below. This being a real example, we get to show this type of thing, which would be left out of a more theoretical case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bulk of the remaining fields are to store the particular figures we&amp;rsquo;re most interested in and wish to receive from Endole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once that&amp;rsquo;s there, we can add the financial data &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/hierarchy-navigation/tabs/&#34;&gt;as a tab&lt;/a&gt; under the organisation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So now we have the data structure fully set up in Agilebase, but no figures to see. Let&amp;rsquo;s get on and set up the integration with some API work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This integration will comprise a three step process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Send the company number for the organisation we&amp;rsquo;re interested in to Endole&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use that number to look up the financial data for the organisation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, send the information back into our financial data table, one record per year&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;setting-up-the-api-calls&#34;&gt;Setting up the API calls&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The integration is relatively easy to set up using &lt;a href=&#34;https://zapier.com&#34;&gt;Zapier&lt;/a&gt;. There&amp;rsquo;s one Zapier action for each step in the process:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/endole-zapier-overview.png&#34; alt=&#34;Endole Zapier Overview&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each step is created using Zapier&amp;rsquo;s Webhooks integration - this is a flexible, general purpose integration suitable for communicating with many different companies&amp;rsquo; APIs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 1&lt;/strong&gt; is what Zapier calls a &amp;lsquo;catch hook&amp;rsquo;. It&amp;rsquo;s a single purpose URL they will generate to allow you to push data to them. Once that step is created, we can create a matching workflow view in Agilebase which contains the company number we wish to query Endole for. We created a simple view with just one field, the company number. We then turned on a &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/integrations/setting-up-the-push-api/&#34;&gt;PUSH API&lt;/a&gt; using the URL Zapier provided. That&amp;rsquo;s as simple as pasting in the URL into the provided space in the Agilebase view:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/endole-push-url.png&#34; alt=&#34;Endole Zapier push link&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 2&lt;/strong&gt; in Zapier queries Endole with that company number. Here&amp;rsquo;s the meat of the process:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/endole-zapier-query.png&#34; alt=&#34;Endole Zapier query&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Endole will come back with the figures for that company and in &lt;strong&gt;step 3&lt;/strong&gt; we can send them to Agilebase as a new &amp;lsquo;financial data&amp;rsquo; record attached to the organisation, using a &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/integrations/setting-up-the-post-api/&#34;&gt;POST API&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/endole-zapier-details.png&#34; alt=&#34;Endole Zapier details&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that the value for the Organisation relation field we mentioned in the start is given as an ID. This is the internal ID of the organisation which the company number belongs to. Zapier can find this as Agilebase includes it in every push or pull API request as the &amp;lsquo;id&amp;rsquo; parameter, whether we ask for it or not. It can be really useful for linking data in different tables together, as we&amp;rsquo;re doing here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may be thinking that this data looks like it represents one year&amp;rsquo;s worth of financial data, but we want a full history covering multiple years. How do we get that?
In short, we don&amp;rsquo;t need to worry about it. Endole provides the data to Zapier as an array, one entry for each year. Zapier transparenty handles that, sending one PUSH request to Agilebase per entry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we have everything we need regarding the integration! We could set the workflow to run in the background, so whenever a new organisation with a company number is entered into the CRM, the integration goes off and finds the financial data. However, because we have many thousands of organistions in our database, we want to be a bit more judicious about our use. Each API request to Endole costs only a small amount, but costs could add up if we were to automatically run it for every organisation, particularly if we include historical records.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So in this case, we&amp;rsquo;ll add a &amp;lsquo;retrieve financials&amp;rsquo; &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/workflows/advanced/workflow-buttons/&#34;&gt;workflow button&lt;/a&gt; to the organisation screen to kick off the workflow on demand. It looks like this on the screen:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/retrieve-financials.png&#34; alt=&#34;Retrieve Financials&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;final-tweaks&#34;&gt;Final tweaks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Above, we mentioned creating a workflow to transform the YYYYMM date format (stored as text) into a proper date field. To do this we create a [workflow](/docs/workflows/altering-data/ which will update our Date field. It contains a calculation called Date with the definition&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;to_date(
    {1.4) financial data.date representation},
    &amp;#39;YYYYMM&amp;#39;
  )
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;The workflow can be set to run whenever a financial details record is created, i.e. as data comes in, using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/workflows/advanced/workflow-on-create/&#34;&gt;run workflow on record creation&lt;/a&gt; option of a table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;charting-the-data&#34;&gt;Charting the data&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s one more thing we can do to add some polish. When opening the financial details tab of the record, we can show a chart of the data for that organisation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To do that, just add a chart to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/hierarchy-navigation/tabs/#tab-view&#34;&gt;tab view&lt;/a&gt;, with each metric you&amp;rsquo;re interested in. When the tab&amp;rsquo;s opened, the chart will automatically be filtered to show just the details for the organisation on screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once complete, the screen will look something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/endole-example.png&#34; alt=&#34;Endole example&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Slack integration</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/integrations/slack-integration/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/integrations/slack-integration/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;When a comment is added to a record in Agilebase, a copy can be sent to your Slack or Teams workspace, to a specific channel appropriate to the tile. Instructions are in progress, in the meantime please &lt;a href=&#34;https://agilechilli.com/contact-us/&#34;&gt;contact us&lt;/a&gt; for help setting this up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Integration with other similar services is also possible should a customer wish - please get in touch if so.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Authenticating users via the API</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/integrations/testing-a-login/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 12:41:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/integrations/testing-a-login/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Sometimes when developing an app that integrates with Agilebase, you may want to allow it to query the system to check the login details a user provides. In other words, let a user &amp;rsquo;log in&amp;rsquo; via your app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The API mechanisms described in this section (push, pull etc.) don&amp;rsquo;t require a login to use, they work only via the API keys as described, however your app may still wish to test a users login to ensure they are a valid user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To do that, the third party app must act exactly as if it were a web browser allowing the user to log in. In other words it must follow this process:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://appserver.gtportalbase.com/Agilebase/AppController.servlet?return=user_details&#34;&gt;https://appserver.gtportalbase.com/Agilebase/AppController.servlet?return=user_details&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The page will return a login form and a cookie JSESSIONID&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Post the form i.e. submit values j_username and j_password, along with the cookie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the username and password are correct, a JSON object will be returned in the response, containing the user&amp;rsquo;s details. If not, an error page will be returned&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;resources--examples&#34;&gt;Resources / Examples&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;java&#34;&gt;Java&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See section &lt;strong&gt;Form Login with Cookies&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tutorialspoint.com/apache_httpclient/apache_httpclient_form_based_login.htm&#34;&gt;https://www.tutorialspoint.com/apache_httpclient/apache_httpclient_form_based_login.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;react&#34;&gt;React&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use the &amp;lsquo;react-cookie&amp;rsquo; package: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.npmjs.com/package/react-cookies&#34;&gt;https://www.npmjs.com/package/react-cookies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;python&#34;&gt;Python&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use the &amp;lsquo;urllib2&amp;rsquo; library: &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/301924/python-urllib-urllib2-httplib-confusion&#39;&#34;&gt;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/301924/python-urllib-urllib2-httplib-confusion&#39;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Creating user accounts with the API</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/integrations/creating-user-accounts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 10:41:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/integrations/creating-user-accounts/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Normally, a user account can only be created by a system administrator - see &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/users/#adding-a-user&#34;&gt;adding a user&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However there&amp;rsquo;s one special case in which the organisation runs a &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/roles/#multi-tenanting&#34;&gt;multi-tenanted&lt;/a&gt; Agilebase account. In that case, you can use an API call to create a new tenant in the account and new user(s) for that tenant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, imagine your organisation is a body for football clubs around the country, where each club was a tenant, i.e. each club had users who could log in, but only see data from their own club. In that case, the user creation API could be called to&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;create a new club&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;create an initial user (or users) for that club&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;preparation&#34;&gt;Preparation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: these instructions need updating for the newest release, please contact support if you wish to use this functionality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before calling the API, you have to configure the system to allow it to be used. In the administrator user interface:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expand the &lt;em&gt;Administration&lt;/em&gt; menu in the lefthand sidebar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click &lt;em&gt;company&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click your company name then the pencil icon in the toolbar to edit the details&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;Multi-tenanting field name (optional)&lt;/em&gt;, type in the field name that your system uses to differentiate tenants, e.g. &amp;ldquo;account name&amp;rdquo;. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/roles/#multi-tenanting&#34;&gt;multi-tenanting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Refresh the page and an API key will appear. We will need this to call the API as below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To disable the API at any point, just delete the value you entered into &lt;em&gt;Multi-tenanting field name (optional)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;calling-the-api&#34;&gt;Calling the API&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use URL &lt;a href=&#34;https://ab.agilechilli.com/Agilebase/Public.ab&#34;&gt;https://ab.agilechilli.com/Agilebase/Public.ab&lt;/a&gt;. You should make a &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTTP/Methods/POST&#34;&gt;POST&lt;/a&gt; request with encoding &lt;code&gt;application/x-www-form-urlencoded&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;Authorization&lt;/code&gt; header needs to be set to the API key as above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following paramaters are required&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;c: this identifies your company account and will always be the same. It will be shown in the company editing screen used in preparation, above&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;create_tenant: true&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;json&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The value of the json parameter is a JSON object, defined below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the below format, &lt;code&gt;multi-tenanting fieldname&lt;/code&gt; is the name of the field used to differentiate tenants with spaces replaced with underscores, e.g. &amp;lsquo;account_name&amp;rsquo;. The &lt;code&gt;multi-tenanting value&lt;/code&gt; is the name of the tenant you wish to create with this particular API call. A multi-tenanting role will be created named &amp;lsquo;cust &lt;code&gt;multi-tenanting value&lt;/code&gt;&amp;rsquo;. E.g. if the value is &amp;lsquo;spurs&amp;rsquo;, the role will be named &amp;lsquo;cust spurs&amp;rsquo;. The value should be a lowercase string consisting only of letters from a through to z and numbers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;users&lt;/code&gt; property is an array of users. Each user will be created and assigned to the above multi-tenanting role, so they can only see data belonging to them and other users of that role. The user will need a valid &lt;code&gt;email address&lt;/code&gt; in order to perform a password reset so they can log in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;customui&lt;/code&gt; property refers to the option to &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/users/#use-the-custom-agilechilli-ui-rather-than-agilebases&#34;&gt;apply a custom logo and login screen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For each user, the &lt;code&gt;roles&lt;/code&gt; parameter is a comma separated list of internal role IDs, or role names. In addition to the multi-tenanting role, they will also be assigned these roles. They could be e.g. &amp;lsquo;manager&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;sales rep&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;accounts dept&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For each user, &lt;code&gt;tiles&lt;/code&gt; is an array of the tiles the user should see on screen when they log in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;{
  &amp;#34;[multi-tenanting fieldname]&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;[multi-tenanting value]&amp;#34;,
  &amp;#34;users&amp;#34;: [
    {
      &amp;#34;username&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;[username&amp;#34;,
      &amp;#34;forename&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;[forename]&amp;#34;,
      &amp;#34;surname&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;[surname]&amp;#34;,
      &amp;#34;email&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;[email address]&amp;#34;,
      &amp;#34;customui&amp;#34;: [true/false],
      &amp;#34;roles&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;[comma separated list of role names]&amp;#34;,
      &amp;#34;tiles&amp;#34;: [
        {
          &amp;#34;tiletype&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;comment_stream / calendar / data_link / files&amp;#34;,
          &amp;#34;colour&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;blue / yellow / green / purple / pink / turquoise / blue2 / yellow2 / green2 / purple2 / pink2 / turquoise2&amp;#34;,
          &amp;#34;internaltilename&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;[for data_link or files tiles, identifies the tile to add]&amp;#34;
        },
        { ... }
      ]
    }
  ]
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;On a successful call, the JSON&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;{
&amp;#34;result&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;ok&amp;#34;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;will be returned, with a 200 HTTP status code. If there is an error,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;{
&amp;#34;error&amp;#34;: true,
&amp;#34;type&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;[class of error]&amp;#34;,
&amp;#34;message&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;[error message]&amp;#34;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;will be returned and the HTTP status code will reflect the error.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
