<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>agileBase docs – Core User</title>
    <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/tags/core-user/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Core User on agileBase docs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/tags/core-user/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: 2FA setup</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/users/2fa-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/users/2fa-setup/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-two-factor-authentication&#34;&gt;What is two factor authentication?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply put, it helps to keep your company’s data more secure, to stop outsiders stealing it, editing or even deleting it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When someone logs in from a new device or location, the system will prompt them for a code sent to or generated by their phone, to prove their identity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to dive into more detail, check out this video from authy.com: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ds_TANz4n3U&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ds_TANz4n3U&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-long-does-this-take-to-set-up&#34;&gt;How long does this take to set up?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No more than a minute or two. It’s a really simple set up process. Here&amp;rsquo;s a 60 second video showing how to do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/lGqp6oDVUF4&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This example shows an iPhone but it’s the same process with an Android phone - just install the Authenticator app from the Google Play store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Setup only needs to be done once. From then on you don’t need to do anything apart from open the app when asked. The app will automatically generate and display a code without any need for you to do anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To kick off the process&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click your user icon at the top right of the screen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select &amp;lsquo;edit profile&amp;rsquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tick &amp;lsquo;enable two factor authentication&amp;rsquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-if-i-cant-use-a-smartphone&#34;&gt;What if I can’t use a smartphone?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don’t use a smartphone at work, that’s no problem. You can use an app on your computer - in fact many people find that more convenient than using a phone. Please ask your system administrator how to set things up and they’ll give you a hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;when-should-i-set-this-up&#34;&gt;When should I set this up?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s never a bad time to upgrade your data security and privacy protection measures. If you’ve not already set up 2FA, agileBase will prompt you to do so once a week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, you can do so at any time: click your user icon at the top right of the screen, select &amp;lsquo;edit profile&amp;rsquo; and tick &amp;lsquo;enable two factor authentication&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
