<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>agileBase docs – System Owner</title>
    <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/tags/system-owner/</link>
    <description>Recent content in System Owner on agileBase docs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/tags/system-owner/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Security Features</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Security and Compliance</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;agileBase often works best when end users become part of the development process, so they&amp;rsquo;re able to give feedback as your software builds up, also gaining confidence in the end result. So it&amp;rsquo;s quite likely that you&amp;rsquo;ll be adding user accounts relatively early in the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a good idea to adopt security best practices from the start rather than trying to retro-fit. This guide will take you through the mechanics of creating &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/users/&#34;&gt;User Accounts&lt;/a&gt; but also explain the steps you can take to ensure data is suitably protected.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Users</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/users/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/users/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2 id=&#34;adding-a-user&#34;&gt;Adding a user&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expand the &lt;em&gt;Administration&lt;/em&gt; menu in the lefthand sidebar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click &lt;em&gt;users&lt;/em&gt;. You&amp;rsquo;ll see a list of existing users&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click the plus button in the toolbar at the top&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should now see an editing screen with the details of the user you just created.
&lt;img src=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/user-details.png&#34; alt=&#34;User editing&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can enter the user&amp;rsquo;s name and username. If the username isn&amp;rsquo;t their email address, enter their email address in the field provided too. This is useful&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to allow them to reset their own password by receiving a link by email&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to allow them to receive notifications when another user adds a comment against a record&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;as various features allow a user to be assigned to a record. Workflows can be set up to email those users. E.g. if an account manager is assigned to a customer, you may want to email them when a complaint is received from that customer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;passwords&#34;&gt;Passwords&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The recommended way to set passwords is for the user to choose their own, which they can do once they have a username and email address filled in. They will need to visit the login page, click the &amp;lsquo;reset password&amp;rsquo; link and type in their username. They will be emailed a link which will let them set a password.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an administrator, you can also manually reset someone&amp;rsquo;s password by clicking &amp;lsquo;change password&amp;rsquo; in their user details screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We recommend the adoption of a password wallet service like &lt;a href=&#34;https://1password.com/&#34;&gt;1Password&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://lastpass.com&#34;&gt;LastPass&lt;/a&gt; or built-in browser features to generate and store passwords. That lets passwords become much more secure and harder to guess whilst not requiring users to remember them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;notes-about-password-security&#34;&gt;Notes about password security&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Passwords must be a minimum of 8 characters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When someone sets or changes their password, it&amp;rsquo;s checked against &lt;a href=&#34;https://haveibeenpwned.com/Passwords&#34;&gt;https://haveibeenpwned.com/Passwords&lt;/a&gt; to ensure it&amp;rsquo;s not a common one and is suitable for ongoing use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Passwords are stored in our system &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.okta.com/blog/2019/03/what-are-salted-passwords-and-password-hashing/&#34;&gt;salted and hashed&lt;/a&gt; using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bcrypt&#34;&gt;bcrypt&lt;/a&gt; scheme, with 13 rounds. This means that we do not know what your passwords are and in the unfortunate event of our passwords database being hacked, the original passwords would still not be able to be retrieved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;two-factor-authentication&#34;&gt;Two factor authentication&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users are strongly encouraged to set up two factor authentication (2FA) using an app. Unfortunately this is one step an administrator can&amp;rsquo;t do for them, but luckily it is quick and easy to do: &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/users/2fa-setup/&#34;&gt;here&amp;rsquo;s how&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users without 2FA will be prompted to do so in the user interface and by email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2FA is mandatory for &lt;a href=&#34;#roles&#34;&gt;administrators&lt;/a&gt; and necessary for a user to have before &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/privileges/&#34;&gt;manage&lt;/a&gt; privileges can be assigned to them. Users also need to have 2FA enabled in order to perform certain functions such as exporting to spreadsheet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When enabled, a user will be prompted for the 2FA code as well as their password when they log in from a device or location they haven&amp;rsquo;t used in the past 30 days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a user encounters any problems with 2FA, e.g. they lose the device for generating their codes, you can temporarily disable 2FA on their account by going to their user details screen and un-ticking &amp;lsquo;use 2FA&amp;rsquo;. Of course, you need to be aware of the risks, for example double checking that a user who contacts you is really who they say they are. Once they can log in, they&amp;rsquo;ll be able to enable 2FA themselves again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;mandating-2fa-for-everyone&#34;&gt;Mandating 2FA for everyone&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This can be done in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/advanced-usage/company-settings/#mandate-2fa&#34;&gt;company settings&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;other-options&#34;&gt;Other options&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;use-the-custom-agilechilli-ui-rather-than-agilebases&#34;&gt;Use the custom AgileChilli UI rather than agileBase&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s possible for companies to apply their logo and custom login screen to the system. Please contact us if you&amp;rsquo;d like to set this up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;logout-after&#34;&gt;Logout after&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Automatically end the user&amp;rsquo;s session after after this many minutes of inactivity. The user themselves can also change this setting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;restrict-data-access&#34;&gt;Restrict data access&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, you can specify a field name, either an equals or a contains filter and a value. The button &lt;em&gt;set to user ID&lt;/em&gt; will set the value to the user&amp;rsquo;s ID.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this is to limit the data rows a particular user sees in a view. If a field with the name you specify appears in a view, a filter will be automatically applied so the user only sees rows which match the filter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, if you set &lt;code&gt;created by [auto] = Oliver Kohll (oliver@agilechilli.com)&lt;/code&gt;, then (assuming &lt;code&gt;Oliver Kohll (oliver@agilechilli.com)&lt;/code&gt; is their username), the user will only see records they created, as long as the &amp;lsquo;created by [auto]&amp;rsquo; field appears in the view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A similar feature exists to add filters to roles - useful when you may want to apply the same filter to multiple users. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/roles/#multi-tenanting&#34;&gt;roles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;roles&#34;&gt;Roles&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tick a role to assign the user to it. The primary purpose of roles is to apply privileges to groups of users, see &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/roles/&#34;&gt;roles&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s one special role which can be assigned. It will be marked &lt;strong&gt;grants administrative privileges&lt;/strong&gt;. Assigning that role will make a user an administrator, with full permissions over the complete system. They can create/remove users, roles, tables etc., as well as assign themselves privileges on any table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next to each role listed is a list of tiles that will be added to their screen if that role is assigned to them. This is a convenience feature to speed up setting up their home screen. The tiles shown for a role are those which more than half of the members of that role have. Tiles can be manually added and removed by an [administrator] or the user themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If any role is a &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/roles/#multi-tenanting&#34;&gt;filtering role&lt;/a&gt;, the filter applied is also displayed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;privileges&#34;&gt;Privileges&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assign individual table &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/privileges/&#34;&gt;privileges&lt;/a&gt; to a user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When dealing with larger numbers of users it&amp;rsquo;s usually more manageable if you use roles to assign privileges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a user has a privilege due to being a member of a role, that privilege is shown with a shaded blue background. Any additional privileges individually assigned to them are shown in green.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;tiles&#34;&gt;Tiles&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Allows an admin to add/remove &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tiles/&#34;&gt;tiles&lt;/a&gt; for a user. By default users can add/remove tiles themselves too, although this can be disabled through the use of a &lt;a href=&#34;#other-options&#34;&gt;custom UI&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;viewing-users&#34;&gt;Viewing users&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Expand the &lt;em&gt;Administration&lt;/em&gt; menu in the lefthand sidebar and click users. You&amp;rsquo;ll see a list of existing user accounts. Their details are listed including 2FA status (whether they&amp;rsquo;re using app-based 2FA or not) and when they last logged in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each user&amp;rsquo;s roles are shown. Any &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/roles/#multi-tenanting&#34;&gt;multi-tenanting&lt;/a&gt; roles are marked in bold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;removing-users&#34;&gt;Removing users&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To remove users, when viewing the list of users, tick those to remove and press the delete (cross) button in the top toolbar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A user removal will have no effect on any data stored in the system. The user&amp;rsquo;s previous comments will still be visible for example and their username will still be logged against any records they&amp;rsquo;re marked as owner of. Their changes will still be in the audit trail and they will be marked as the creator/last editor of records where relevant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may want to take some other actions after deletion e.g. to re-assign records they are assigned to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A deleted user&amp;rsquo;s profile image will be replaced with a standard icon representing a deleted user, when displayed in comment streams etc.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Policies</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/policies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/policies/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2 id=&#34;backups&#34;&gt;Backups&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data backups are performed across the stack of technology, from server down to databases and file storage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Database backups are taken daily and hosted in the European Union by Amazon. Older backups transition to &lt;a href=&#34;https://aws.amazon.com/glacier/&#34;&gt;Amazon Glacier&lt;/a&gt; and are kept for 200 days - this allows a balance between the practical necessity of allowing rollbacks to a certain point in time, whilst not storing data for an unnecessarily long period, to comply with the GDPR.
By policy, backups under 100 days old are read-only and un-deletable, so will always be available in the case of attacks like ransomware.
These backups are also encrypted so that Amazon has no access to the data within then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.postgresql.org/docs/current/warm-standby.html&#34;&gt;Continuous archiving &lt;/a&gt; of the database is also enabled, to transfer data to a &amp;lsquo;hot standby&amp;rsquo; server using streaming replication, allowing immediate failover should the primary database fail for any reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;agileBase content (uploaded files, custom templates etc.) also have snapshots taken daily, kept for 200 days in a separate EU location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to these content-only backups, snapshots of the totality of each key server in the infrastructure (including configuration), are run daily using the Linode backup service &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linode.com/products/backups/&#34;&gt;https://www.linode.com/products/backups/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The backup and recovery process is monitored and tested regularly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;retrieval&#34;&gt;Retrieval&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There may be a charge for retrieval of customer data from backup, to cover our costs. The data will be restored to a separate instance of agileBase available at a different URL, which a customer can look at to compare data. If necessary, data can then be extracted from one and loaded into the other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please be aware that depending on needs, this may be a complex process due to the fact that other data in the live system may have changed since the backup. A simple overwrite of existing data may not be the best option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;privacy-policy&#34;&gt;Privacy policy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;agileBase Ltd is funded directly by the customers we provide services to, we do not have any other business model, particularly we do not resell any data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our privacy policy is available here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://agilechilli.com/help-centre/agilebase/privacy-policy/&#34;&gt;https://agilechilli.com/help-centre/agilebase/privacy-policy/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;gdpr-policy&#34;&gt;GDPR Policy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An overview of our GDPR policy is available &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/gdpr-overview.pdf&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/gdpr-overview.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/gdpr-compliance-cycle.png&#34; alt=&#34;GDPR Compliance Cycle&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;data-protection-and-disaster-recovery&#34;&gt;Data Protection and Disaster Recovery&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Full details of our processes and plans are available to customers and relevant parties on request.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Roles</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/roles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/roles/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The primary purpose of roles is to apply privileges to groups of users, rather than applying them individually. That makes managing large numbers of users easier and also more secure as it&amp;rsquo;s easy to see which privileges each type of user has and which they don&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roles have some other important uses, such as multi-tenanting, described below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;creating-a-role&#34;&gt;Creating a role&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expand the &lt;em&gt;Administration&lt;/em&gt; menu in the lefthand sidebar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click &lt;em&gt;roles&lt;/em&gt;. You&amp;rsquo;ll see a list of existing roles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click the plus button in the toolbar at the top&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should now see an editing screen with the details of the role you just created. You can give it a name and there are a few options:
&lt;img src=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/role-details.png&#34; alt=&#34;Role details&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Allow Export&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Referrs to exporting to spreadsheet - see &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/integrations/exporting-to-spreadsheet/&#34;&gt;spreadsheet exports&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Allow global editing&lt;/strong&gt;
Users with &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/privileges/&#34;&gt;edit privileges&lt;/a&gt; on a particular table, when added to this role, will be able to perform global edits on the data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To perform a global edit, the user should&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;filter the view (by typing into the filter boxes at the top of each column) to narrow down the rows to those which should be edited&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;double click on a column header in a view, to edit the data in that field. The field must be from the view&amp;rsquo;s parent table.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;click the &amp;lsquo;edit filtered&amp;rsquo; button which appears&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;type in the value you want to apply and follow through the prompts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;User Visibility&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Restrict Data Access&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
These are used to set up &lt;a href=&#34;#multi-tenanting&#34;&gt;multi-tenanting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;members&#34;&gt;Members&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tick each user to add them to the role. Users will gain all the privileges defined by the role.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;privileges&#34;&gt;Privileges&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Select the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/privileges/&#34;&gt;table privileges&lt;/a&gt; which will apply to members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Privileges are additive - if a user is a member of multiple roles, they gain all the privileges from each of those roles added together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;multi-tenanting&#34;&gt;Multi-tenanting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Multi-tenanting is the ability to separate users into groups who can’t see each other’s data. This can be used for example to allow different sets of companies, clubs, or membership groups (or whatever the organisational group is) to use the same system features whilst remaining separate from each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Multi-tenanting is a powerful feature that can be used not just for customers to segragate data amongst their users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Partners can also use this facility if building software to widely market. In that case, each customer they sign up can very quickly be set up with their own private dataset, whilst the partner retains the ability to add features which will automatically apply to everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To set up multi-tenanting:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;first &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/&#34;&gt;add a text field&lt;/a&gt; to all tables in the system for which you want data to be segragated. The field must be named the same in every table, for example&amp;rsquo;s sake here let&amp;rsquo;s assume it&amp;rsquo;s called &amp;lsquo;account name&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Then create one role for each set of users who you want to segregate. We&amp;rsquo;ll assume there&amp;rsquo;s one called &amp;lsquo;Customer A&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the role details screen for the Customer A role, tick &lt;em&gt;user visibility&lt;/em&gt;. That means that users in this role won&amp;rsquo;t see users in other roles with the same option ticked. In other words, users from Customer A won&amp;rsquo;t be able to select Customer B or Customer C users when doing things like adding comments or assigning users to records.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Under &lt;em&gt;restrict data access&lt;/em&gt; in the role details, enter &lt;code&gt;account name = Customer A&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, ensure the account name field is present in all views based on the table. When creating a view, any fields used for multi-tenanting will automatically be added but you may need to retro-fit any existing views.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has two effects -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When a user assigned to the Customer A role creates a new record in one of the multi-tenanting tables, the account name field will automatically be populated with the value Customer A (as entered under &lt;em&gt;restrict data access&lt;/em&gt;). The field will be invisible to them - they won&amp;rsquo;t be able to see or edit the value.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When looking at records in a view, a filter will be automatically applied so the user only sees records where account name = Customer A.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users who &lt;strong&gt;aren&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/strong&gt; a member of the role will see the account name field in the data editing form and in views. This can be useful for allowing e.g. group managers to see all data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If any multi-tenanting roles are set up, then views which &lt;strong&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/strong&gt; contain a multi-tenanting field will be marked in red in the administration interface, as a warning. If a multi-tenanting user loads one of these views, they will see all records. Typically, practically all views will need the multi-tenanting field to be present.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;complex-multi-tenanting&#34;&gt;Complex multi-tenanting&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;multi-level&#34;&gt;Multi-level&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users may be a member of more than one multi-tenanting role. For example you may use two multi-tenanting fields/roles, one for a company and another for a division. Members of a company role will be able to see data from all divisions in their company and members of both a company and a division role will only be able to see data for a single division.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;multi-account-via-multiple-roles&#34;&gt;Multi-account (via multiple roles)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s also possible for a user to be a member of multiple roles, all of which are set to multi-tenant on the same field, with different values. E.g. if a user is a member of Company A and Company B roles as in our example above, they will see data from those two companies when viewing records, but not Company C.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This works best when the user has read-only privileges on the data, e.g. for a manager reporting on those two companies. They can view records but not add new records, as the system is unable to determine the value of the account name field to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;multi-account-via-_contains_-filtering&#34;&gt;Multi-account (via &lt;em&gt;contains&lt;/em&gt; filtering)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s also possible to define a role filter under &lt;em&gt;restrict data access&lt;/em&gt; with a &amp;lsquo;contains&amp;rsquo; rather than an &amp;lsquo;=&amp;rsquo; filter. You can then use a naming convension for your account name values to allow members of this role to see multiple accounts. As above, users of this role will need to be read-only on the data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;api-setup&#34;&gt;API setup&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a multi-tenanting account, it&amp;rsquo;s possible to create new tenants, with users, by API, as opposed to the manual actions of an administrator. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/integrations/creating-user-accounts/&#34;&gt;Creating user accounts with the API&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;role-properties&#34;&gt;Role properties&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;brand-name-and-domain&#34;&gt;Brand name and domain&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These two options allow system emails (password reset notification etc.) to come from a domain name of your choice and be branded with a particular &amp;lsquo;app&amp;rsquo; name. This can be useful if you&amp;rsquo;re creating a public-facing app using agileBase, rather than applications for your own staff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To allow the domain name to work, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to contact us to set it up - our server will need to be authorised to send email from your domain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;custom-menus&#34;&gt;Custom menus&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s possible to add custom menu items into the user menu (the one at the top right that appears if you click your user icon). That means if your company has specific help pages or process documentation relevant to your organisation or application, you can make them available from within agileBase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each custom menu has a title, description and URL, which will be opened in a new tab when the menu item’s chosen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply add these into the &lt;strong&gt;menu title&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;menu description&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;menu URL&lt;/strong&gt; properties of a role. Assigning that role to a user will add the menu item to their profile menu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To add multiple menu items to a user or users, assign multiple roles, each with one menu item defined.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Privileges</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/privileges/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/privileges/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;In agileBase, there are three privilege levels, as well as a special ‘administrator’ privilege.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The three privileges take effect per table, i.e. a user/role can have certain privileges on one table and different ones on another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Privileges are additive - if a user is a member of multiple roles, they gain all the privileges from each of those roles added together, plus any they may have individually assigned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;privilege-levels&#34;&gt;Privilege levels&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;View&lt;/strong&gt;: ability to see data in a table&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edit&lt;/strong&gt;: ability to create, edit and delete data in a table (create and delete subject to various table options)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Manage&lt;/strong&gt;: the privilege that allows you to use the &amp;lsquo;application building&amp;rsquo; features of agileBase, relating to a table. Namely the ability to
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;modify the structure, i.e. create/delete fields, tabs, change options etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;create, edit and delete views from the table, including creating charts, maps and word clouds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;upload or create printout templates for views&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;view usage statistics about a table&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manage also allows some extended user features
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;delete any user&amp;rsquo;s comments from a table&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;unlock locked records to allow editing (one at a time)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;override table options which would normally disallow adding/removing records from a table&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;override options which would normally disallow exporting data to a spreadsheet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;import data from spreadsheet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;override options which would normally disallow global editing of data in the table&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally the &lt;strong&gt;administrator&lt;/strong&gt; privilege allows full permissions over the complete system. An administrator can create/remove users, roles, tables etc., as well as assign table privileges to any user, including themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The administrator privilege is the only one that allows the user to add new tables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two Factor Authentication is required for any user with manage or administrator privileges&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;assigning-table-privileges&#34;&gt;Assigning table privileges&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Table privileges can be assigned to one or more users or roles from that table&amp;rsquo;s editing screen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From a user or role editing screen, privileges on one or more tables can be assigned&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two methods are equivalent, whichever is the most convenient for a given purpose can be used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Managing privileges by role rather than by individual user is recommended. That makes managing large numbers of users easier and also more secure as it&amp;rsquo;s easy to see which privileges each type of user has and which they don&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To assign one or more role or user privileges to a table:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expand the &lt;em&gt;Build Tables&lt;/em&gt; section in the lefthand navigation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click a table&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click the pencil (edit) icon in the top toolbar (or click a record to load the editing screen)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click the &lt;em&gt;manage&lt;/em&gt; tab at the bottom of the screen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open the &lt;em&gt;roles&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;users&lt;/em&gt; section, then select or un-select any privileges required&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To assign one or more table privileges to a particular role or user:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expand the &lt;em&gt;Administration&lt;/em&gt; section of the lefthand navigation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click &lt;em&gt;roles&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;users&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select the role or user to assign privileges to, then select or un-select any privileges required&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;assigning-the-administrator-privilege&#34;&gt;Assigning the administrator privilege&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expand the &lt;em&gt;Administration&lt;/em&gt; section&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click &lt;em&gt;users&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select the user to make an administrator&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open the &lt;em&gt;roles&lt;/em&gt; section&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tick the role marked &lt;strong&gt;Grants administrative privileges&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;related-to-privileges&#34;&gt;Related to privileges&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Database systems often have the concept of row level privileges. The equivalent in agileBase is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/roles/#multi-tenanting&#34;&gt;multi-tenanting&lt;/a&gt; system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Individual fields in a table can be locked or hidden, see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-options/common-options/#show-if-record-in-view&#34;&gt;field options&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Reporting</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/usage-monitoring/usage-reporting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/usage-monitoring/usage-reporting/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Log data reporting provides a rich view of system usage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;enhanced-audit-trail&#34;&gt;Enhanced audit trail&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For organisations who have activated the enhanced audit trail, all logs are stored in user-accessible tables which are just like any other tables in the system, the only difference being the data is read only. This means an administrator can use the full power of the built in agileBase reporting features, to create views, add calculations, charts etc., even export via the API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So for example, you could analyse how many changes were made per month by each user, count the volume of logins from various locations or see what the most common fields are to search on. All actions listed on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/usage-monitoring/&#34;&gt;usage monitoring&lt;/a&gt; page are available to query.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data is also retained for an extended period, see &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/usage-monitoring/#retention-periods&#34;&gt;retention periods&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If interested in activating this feature, please &lt;a href=&#34;https://agilechilli.com/contact-us/&#34;&gt;get in touch&lt;/a&gt;. There will be a small recurring charge added to your bill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;data-stored&#34;&gt;Data stored&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;logins&#34;&gt;Logins&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Username&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Date and time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IP Address&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Country&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Internet Service Provider organisation name and location&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Client web browser (both summary and exact version details)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Client operating system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;data-changes-record-creation--update--delete&#34;&gt;Data changes (record creation / update / delete)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Username (in the case of an API call, will be &amp;lsquo;Public API [IP address]&amp;rsquo;. In the case of a system workflow, &amp;lsquo;System&amp;rsquo;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Date and time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Action (e.g. update or delete)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Table&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Field (if a single field is updated)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Row ID - internal identifier of the record updated&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Saved data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;view-access&#34;&gt;View access&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This covers any time a view is opened or filtered, either by a user, or an API call&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Username (in the case of an API call, will be &amp;lsquo;Public API [IP address]&#39;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Date and time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tile and view name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Details - any filters and row limit applied&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rows - the number of records returned to the user or API&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Processing time - the total server-side processing time in milliseconds needed to retrieve the data, and if for an API, transform it into JSON format&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Of which Q time &lt;strong&gt;(API calls only)&lt;/strong&gt; - to achieve a fair level of load balancing, agileBase operates a separate API request queue for each customer. If a request arrives and the system is still busy processing a previous request, the new one gets held in a queue. This field shows how much of the total processing time, in ms was spent waiting for previous requests to complete&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bytes &lt;strong&gt;(API calls only)&lt;/strong&gt; - the number of bytes of JSON data returned via the API&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Count - if many similar requests or API calls (to a particular view) reach the server in quick succession, they will be amalgamated together into one log line. The count then shows the number of requests the log line refers to, otherwise it will be 1. If more than one, then the &lt;em&gt;rows&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;processing time&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;of which q time&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;bytes&lt;/em&gt; will represent the totals for all requests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;table-schema-changes&#34;&gt;Table schema changes&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are changes made to a table structure by someone with &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/privileges/&#34;&gt;manage&lt;/a&gt; privileges, such as adding or removing a field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Date and time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Username&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Table name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Action e.g. &amp;lsquo;add field&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;remove field&amp;rsquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Details - e.g. the name of the field&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;view-schema-changes&#34;&gt;View schema changes&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Changes made to a view structure, such as adding fields, filters, calculations or charts&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Date and time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Username&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tile and view name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Action&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Details - additional data related to the action, e.g. if adding a field, the field name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;authentication-changes&#34;&gt;Authentication changes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A log of administrative actions such as assigning a user to a role, assigning privileges, or user actions such as requesting a password reset&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Date and time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Username (of the user making the change)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Action - e.g. add privilege&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Table name - only if the action relates to a particular table, e.g. assigning a role to a table&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Details - additional data related to the action, e.g. if adding a role to the table, the role name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;standard-reporting&#34;&gt;Standard reporting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Built in reports are available in a number of areas, whether using the enhanced audit trail or standard logging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-dashboard&#34;&gt;The dashboard&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the tiles interface, click the bird icon at the top left, then select &lt;em&gt;usage dashboard&lt;/em&gt;. The dashboard contains system reports including usage data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;trends&#34;&gt;Trends&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An overall usage treemap is displayed at the top. Each view is a section of the screen. Large areas represent views that get a lot of use, smaller areas those that don’t. Colours give immediate feedback on whether usage has been increasing (blue) or decreasing (grey) this month. Hovering over an area shows more stats including the top users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Underneath that a series of sparkline charts show long term trends, across selected operational, tactical and strategic metrics, all geared to showing utilisation over a 12 month period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Raw data can be downloaded to spreadsheet using the links beneath each sparkline. Note only the most recent 200,000 records can be downloaded in this way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;capacity&#34;&gt;Capacity&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as actual usage, the dashboard shows total capacity i.e. how many users, records, tables etc. are present in the system, along with purchased capacity (if relevant). These elements affect billing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;workflows&#34;&gt;Workflows&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A convenience view of all workflows which carry out automated data modifications, see &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/workflows/&#34;&gt;workflows&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;database-graph&#34;&gt;Database graph&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, for background on what the data structure looks like and how tables are connected, the database graph shows relations between tables is visual form. This can provide a fuller understaning of the system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;table-and-view-usage&#34;&gt;Table and view usage&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A quick overview of who is viewing data is shown in the administration interface for both tables and views.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a table&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open a table, under the &lt;em&gt;Build Tables&lt;/em&gt; section of the lefthand navigation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go the the manage tab and click the &lt;em&gt;Usage&lt;/em&gt; icon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The report shows the number of times each user has viewed data from the table, per view. All views which contain any data from the table are included.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a view&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open a view from the lefthand navigation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to the manage tab and click the &lt;em&gt;Usage&lt;/em&gt; icon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similar data is show as for tables, but limited to the selected view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;individual-record-histories&#34;&gt;Individual record histories&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any user can see the complete history of changes to an individual record, up to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/usage-monitoring/#retention-periods&#34;&gt;retention period&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When editing a record, scroll to the bottom of the screen and click &lt;em&gt;history&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To view the precise time of a change, hover over a date.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Usage Monitoring</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/usage-monitoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/usage-monitoring/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;agileBase comprehensively logs changes to data in the system as well as changes to the structure of the system. Powerful &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/usage-monitoring/usage-reporting/&#34;&gt;reporting facilities&lt;/a&gt; allow the generation of audit trails, trend monitoring, customer success monitoring etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-logged&#34;&gt;What is logged&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;user-actions&#34;&gt;User actions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following actions are recorded&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;logins, including connection details&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;record edits (create, update and delete)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;global edits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;comment additions and removals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;data imports and exports&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;viewing and searching/filtering data in views&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;password resets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When logging a record deletion, the data values deleted are logged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further, for every record in a table, the following metadata is stored and can be included in views:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The creation time and time of last update&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The user who created the record and who last updated it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The view count: how many times the record has been opened&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A visual activity histogram showing the number of edits per week over the past six months&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/fields/field-types/special-field-types/automatically-present-fields/&#34;&gt;automatically present fields&lt;/a&gt; for full details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;api-and-workflow-actions&#34;&gt;API and workflow actions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data changes or outflows arising from &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/integrations/&#34;&gt;API calls&lt;/a&gt;are logged to the same log store as user actions. Instead of logging the user taking the action, it&amp;rsquo;s logged as an API call with the IP address of the source of the request.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Automated &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/workflows/&#34;&gt;workflow&lt;/a&gt; actions are also logged. Each is marked as a workflow actions with the name of the action (i.e. the view name) to identify it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;administration-and-management-actions&#34;&gt;Administration and management actions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All significant actions are recorded, in summary&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;adding, updating or removing users, roles and privileges&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;table additions and removals, field additions and removals, data constraint additions and removals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;view additions, updates and removals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;chart edits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;retention-periods&#34;&gt;Retention periods&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data is retained for 12 months as standard. The enhanced audit trail allows customers to define their own retention period, the maximum being unlimited.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Sensitive data</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/sensitive-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/sensitive-data/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;In a table&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;manage&lt;/em&gt; tab, there are two options which are worth considering if the data is storing commercially sensitive information (plenty of information in most customer systems falls under this category!) or personal information as defined by EU General Data Protection Regulations (GDPR).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When either option is ticked, two controls appear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;notify-administrators-on-export&#34;&gt;Notify administrators on export&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here you can enter a number. When a user exports more than that number of records at once to spreadsheet, all administrators (users with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/privileges/#assigning-the-administrator-privilege&#34;&gt;administrator&lt;/a&gt; privilege) are notified by email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;disallow-exports&#34;&gt;Disallow exports&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is also a number, representing a hard limit on the number of records which can be exported from this table at any one time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/exporting/&#34;&gt;exporting&lt;/a&gt; for how to set up export privileges. Exports are disallowed by default.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When &lt;strong&gt;This table contains personal data, sensitive data or data about children&lt;/strong&gt; is ticked, a number of additional data entry boxes appear, to let you record the GDPR-relevant considerations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: This is for informational purposes only and doesn&amp;rsquo;t by itself ensure compliance with the GDPR!. We recommend looking at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/guide-to-the-general-data-protection-regulation-gdpr/&#34;&gt;ICO website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;potential-exfiltration-information&#34;&gt;Potential exfiltration information&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When either option is ticked, some additional information is shown that can highlight opportunities for data to be exported.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any API views which send data to third party systems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any roles which are set up to allow exporting and which have users with privileges to see the table data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Usage</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/usage/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/usage/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;This panel shows a list of views that contain data from the table. Any view with data is included, not just those directly created from the table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/usage-monitoring/usage-reporting/&#34;&gt;usage reporting&lt;/a&gt; for more info.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/table-usage.png&#34; alt=&#34;table usage&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Users and Roles</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/users-and-roles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/users-and-roles/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Users&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Roles&lt;/em&gt; panels of a table&amp;rsquo;s manage tab allow privileges to be assigned to a user or role on a table. Please see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/privileges/&#34;&gt;privileges&lt;/a&gt; page for more details.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
