<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Agilebase docs – Security and Compliance</title>
    <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Security and Compliance on Agilebase docs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Security Features</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/security-features/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;In these pages you can find details of how to set up users, roles, and privileges in Agilebase. Agilebase has an extensive role-based permissions system that enables fine-grained permissions and roles to be used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tables of data can also be marked as containing &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/tables/sensitive-data/&#34;&gt;commercially sensitive or personal data&lt;/a&gt;, relevant to GDPR and affecting application behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Policies</title>
      <link>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/policies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/docs/security-and-compliance/policies/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2 id=&#34;backups&#34;&gt;Backups&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data backups are performed across the stack of technology, from server down to databases and file storage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Database backups are taken daily and hosted in the European Union by Amazon. Older backups transition to &lt;a href=&#34;https://aws.amazon.com/glacier/&#34;&gt;Amazon Glacier&lt;/a&gt; and are kept for 200 days - this allows a balance between the practical necessity of allowing rollbacks to a certain point in time, whilst not storing data for an unnecessarily long period, to comply with the GDPR.
By policy, backups under 100 days old are read-only and un-deletable, so will always be available in the case of attacks like ransomware.
These backups are also encrypted so that Amazon has no access to the data within then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.postgresql.org/docs/current/warm-standby.html&#34;&gt;Continuous archiving &lt;/a&gt; of the database is also enabled, to transfer data to a &amp;lsquo;hot standby&amp;rsquo; server using streaming replication, allowing immediate failover should the primary database fail for any reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agilebase content (uploaded files, custom templates etc.) also have snapshots taken daily, kept for 200 days in a separate EU location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to these content-only backups, snapshots of the totality of each key server in the infrastructure (including configuration), are run daily using the Linode backup service &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linode.com/products/backups/&#34;&gt;https://www.linode.com/products/backups/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The backup and recovery process is monitored and tested regularly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;retrieval&#34;&gt;Retrieval&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There may be a charge for retrieval of customer data from backup, to cover our costs. The data will be restored to a separate instance of Agilebase available at a different URL, which a customer can look at to compare data. If necessary, data can then be extracted from one and loaded into the other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please be aware that depending on needs, this may be a complex process due to the fact that other data in the live system may have changed since the backup. A simple overwrite of existing data may not be the best option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;privacy-policy&#34;&gt;Privacy policy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agilebase Ltd is funded directly by the customers we provide services to, we do not have any other business model, particularly we do not resell any data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our privacy policy is available here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://agilechilli.com/help-centre/agilebase/privacy-policy/&#34;&gt;https://agilechilli.com/help-centre/agilebase/privacy-policy/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;gdpr-policy&#34;&gt;GDPR Policy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An overview of our GDPR policy is available &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/gdpr-overview.pdf&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/gdpr-overview.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://docs.agilebase.co.uk/gdpr-compliance-cycle.png&#34; alt=&#34;GDPR Compliance Cycle&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;data-protection-and-disaster-recovery&#34;&gt;Data Protection and Disaster Recovery&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Full details of our processes and plans are available to customers and relevant parties on request.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
